<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/research/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-11-20T21:51:51+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/research/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Kavour | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Mixtures of In-Context Learners</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/InContextLearners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mixtures of In-Context Learners" />
      <published>2024-11-05T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/InContextLearners</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/InContextLearners">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; In-context learning (ICL) adapts LLMs by providing demonstrations without fine-tuning the model parameters; however, it does not differentiate between demonstrations and quadratically increases the complexity of Transformer LLMs, exhausting the memory. As a solution, we propose Mixtures of In-Context Learners (MoICL), a novel approach to treat subsets of demonstrations as experts and learn a weighting function to merge their output distributions based on a training set. In our experiments, we show performance improvements on 5 out of 7 classification datasets compared to a set of strong baselines (up to +13\% compared to ICL and LENS). Moreover, we enhance the Pareto frontier of ICL by reducing the inference time needed to achieve the same performance with fewer demonstrations. Finally, MoICL is more robust to out-of-domain (up to +11\%), imbalanced (up to +49\%), or noisy demonstrations (up to +38\%) or can filter these out from datasets. Overall, MoICL is a more expressive approach to learning from demonstrations without exhausting the context window or memory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hong,+G&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Giwon Hong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=van+Krieken,+E&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Emile van Krieken&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ponti,+E&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Edoardo Ponti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Malkin,+N&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nikolay Malkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Minervini,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pasquale Minervini&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.20771&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">MrT5:Dynamic Token Merging for Efficient Byte-level Language Models</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/DynamicToken" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MrT5:Dynamic Token Merging for Efficient Byte-level Language Models" />
      <published>2024-10-28T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/DynamicToken</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/DynamicToken">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Models that rely on subword tokenization have significant drawbacks, such as sensitivity to character-level noise like spelling errors and inconsistent compression rates across different languages and scripts. While character- or byte-level models like ByT5 attempt to address these concerns, they have not gained widespread adoption -- processing raw byte streams without tokenization results in significantly longer sequence lengths, making training and inference inefficient. This work introduces MrT5 (MergeT5), a more efficient variant of ByT5 that integrates a token deletion mechanism in its encoder to dynamically shorten the input sequence length. After processing through a fixed number of encoder layers, a learnt delete gate determines which tokens are to be removed and which are to be retained for subsequent layers. MrT5 effectively ``merges'' critical information from deleted tokens into a more compact sequence, leveraging contextual information from the remaining tokens. In continued pre-training experiments, we find that MrT5 can achieve significant gains in inference runtime with minimal effect on performance. When trained on English text, MrT5 demonstrates the capability to transfer its deletion feature zero-shot across several languages, with significant additional improvements following multilingual training. Furthermore, MrT5 shows comparable accuracy to ByT5 on downstream evaluations such as XNLI and character-level tasks while reducing sequence lengths by up to 80%. Our approach presents a solution to the practical limitations of existing byte-level models. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Kallini,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Julie Kallini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Murty,+S&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Shikhar Murty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Manning,+C+D&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Christopher D. Manning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Potts,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Christopher Potts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Csord%C3%A1s,+R&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Róbert Csordás&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.20771&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Large Language Models Reflect the Ideology of their Creators</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/CreatorsIdeology" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Large Language Models Reflect the Ideology of their Creators" />
      <published>2024-10-24T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/CreatorsIdeology</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/CreatorsIdeology">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Large language models (LLMs) are trained on vast amounts of data to generate natural language, enabling them to perform tasks like text summarization and question answering. These models have become popular in artificial intelligence (AI) assistants like ChatGPT and already play an influential role in how humans access information. However, the behavior of LLMs varies depending on their design, training, and use.
In this paper, we uncover notable diversity in the ideological stance exhibited across different LLMs and languages in which they are accessed. We do this by prompting a diverse panel of popular LLMs to describe a large number of prominent and controversial personalities from recent world history, both in English and in Chinese. By identifying and analyzing moral assessments reflected in the generated descriptions, we find consistent normative differences between how the same LLM responds in Chinese compared to English. Similarly, we identify normative disagreements between Western and non-Western LLMs about prominent actors in geopolitical conflicts. Furthermore, popularly hypothesized disparities in political goals among Western models are reflected in significant normative differences related to inclusion, social inequality, and political scandals.
Our results show that the ideological stance of an LLM often reflects the worldview of its creators. This raises important concerns around technological and regulatory efforts with the stated aim of making LLMs ideologically `unbiased', and it poses risks for political instrumentalization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Buyl,+M&quot;&gt;Maarten Buyl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Rogiers,+A&quot;&gt;Alexander Rogiers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Noels,+S&quot;&gt;Sander Noels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Dominguez-Catena,+I&quot;&gt;Iris Dominguez-Catena&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Heiter,+E&quot;&gt;Edith Heiter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Romero,+R&quot;&gt;Raphael Romero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Johary,+I&quot;&gt;Iman Johary&lt;/a&gt;
, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Mara,+A&quot;&gt;Alexandru-Cristian Mara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lijffijt,+J&quot;&gt;Jefrey Lijffijt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=De+Bie,+T&quot;&gt;Tijl De Bie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.18417&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Theoretical Understanding of Chain-of-Thought:Coherent Reasoning and Error-Aware Demonstration</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/CoT" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Theoretical Understanding of Chain-of-Thought:Coherent Reasoning and Error-Aware Demonstration" />
      <published>2024-10-21T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/CoT</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/CoT">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Few-shot Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has demonstrated strong performance in improving the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs). While theoretical investigations have been conducted to understand CoT, the underlying transformer used in these studies isolates the CoT reasoning process into separated in-context learning steps (Stepwise ICL). In this work, we theoretically show that, compared to Stepwise ICL, the transformer gains better error correction ability and more accurate predictions if the reasoning from earlier steps (Coherent CoT) is integrated. Given that this coherent reasoning changes the behavior of the transformer, we further investigate the sensitivity of the transformer with Coherent CoT when the demonstration examples are corrupted at the inference stage. Our theoretical results indicate that the transformer is more sensitive to errors in intermediate reasoning steps than the final outcome. Building upon this observation, we propose an improvement on CoT by incorporating both correct and incorrect reasoning paths in the demonstration. Our experiments validate the effectiveness of the proposed approach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Cui,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yingqian Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pengfei He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tang,+X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Xianfeng Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+Q&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Qi He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Luo,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chen Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tang,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jiliang Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xing,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yue Xing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.16540&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Looking Inward:Language Models Can Learn About Themselves by Introspection</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Introspection" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking Inward:Language Models Can Learn About Themselves by Introspection" />
      <published>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Introspection</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Introspection">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Humans acquire knowledge by observing the external world, but also by introspection. Introspection gives a person privileged access to their current state of mind (e.g., thoughts and feelings) that is not accessible to external observers. Can LLMs introspect? We define introspection as acquiring knowledge that is not contained in or derived from training data but instead originates from internal states. Such a capability could enhance model interpretability. Instead of painstakingly analyzing a model's internal workings, we could simply ask the model about its beliefs, world models, and goals. More speculatively, an introspective model might self-report on whether it possesses certain internal states such as subjective feelings or desires and this could inform us about the moral status of these states. Such self-reports would not be entirely dictated by the model's training data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We study introspection by finetuning LLMs to predict properties of their own behavior in hypothetical scenarios. For example, &quot;Given the input P, would your output favor the short- or long-term option?&quot; If a model M1 can introspect, it should outperform a different model M2 in predicting M1's behavior even if M2 is trained on M1's ground-truth behavior. The idea is that M1 has privileged access to its own behavioral tendencies, and this enables it to predict itself better than M2 (even if M2 is generally stronger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In experiments with GPT-4, GPT-4o, and Llama-3 models (each finetuned to predict itself), we find that the model M1 outperforms M2 in predicting itself, providing evidence for introspection. Notably, M1 continues to predict its behavior accurately even after we intentionally modify its ground-truth behavior. However, while we successfully elicit introspection on simple tasks, we are unsuccessful on more complex tasks or those requiring out-of-distribution generalization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Binder,+F+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Felix J Binder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chua,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;James Chua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Korbak,+T&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tomek Korbak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sleight,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Henry Sleight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hughes,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;John Hughes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Long,+R&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Robert Long&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Perez,+E&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ethan Perez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Turpin,+M&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Miles Turpin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Evans,+O&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Owain Evans&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.13787&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Agent-as-a-Judge:Evaluate Agents with Agents</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agent-as-a-Judge:Evaluate Agents with Agents" />
      <published>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Contemporary evaluation techniques are inadequate for agentic systems. These approaches either focus exclusively on final outcomes -- ignoring the step-by-step nature of agentic systems, or require excessive manual labour. To address this, we introduce the Agent-as-a-Judge framework, wherein agentic systems are used to evaluate agentic systems. This is an organic extension of the LLM-as-a-Judge framework, incorporating agentic features that enable intermediate feedback for the entire task-solving process. We apply the Agent-as-a-Judge to the task of code generation. To overcome issues with existing benchmarks and provide a proof-of-concept testbed for Agent-as-a-Judge, we present DevAI, a new benchmark of 55 realistic automated AI development tasks. It includes rich manual annotations, like a total of 365 hierarchical user requirements. We benchmark three of the popular agentic systems using Agent-as-a-Judge and find it dramatically outperforms LLM-as-a-Judge and is as reliable as our human evaluation baseline. Altogether, we believe that Agent-as-a-Judge marks a concrete step forward for modern agentic systems -- by providing rich and reliable reward signals necessary for dynamic and scalable self-improvement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhuge,+M&quot;&gt;Mingchen Zhuge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhao,+C&quot;&gt;Changsheng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ashley,+D&quot;&gt;Dylan Ashley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+W&quot;&gt;Wenyi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Khizbullin,+D&quot;&gt;Dmitrii Khizbullin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xiong,+Y&quot;&gt;Yunyang Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+Z&quot;&gt;Zechun Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chang,+E&quot;&gt;Ernie Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Krishnamoorthi,+R&quot;&gt;Raghuraman Krishnamoorthi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tian,+Y&quot;&gt;Yuandong Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shi,+Y&quot;&gt;Yangyang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chandra,+V&quot;&gt;Vikas Chandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Schmidhuber,+J&quot;&gt;Jürgen Schmidhuber&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10934&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Simplifying, Stabilizing and Scaling Continuous-Time Consistency Models</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/TimeConsistencyModels" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simplifying, Stabilizing and Scaling Continuous-Time Consistency Models" />
      <published>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/TimeConsistencyModels</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TimeConsistencyModels">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Consistency models (CMs) are a powerful class of diffusion-based generative models optimized for fast sampling. Most existing CMs are trained using discretized timesteps, which introduce additional hyperparameters and are prone to discretization errors. While continuous-time formulations can mitigate these issues, their success has been limited by training instability. To address this, we propose a simplified theoretical framework that unifies previous parameterizations of diffusion models and CMs, identifying the root causes of instability. Based on this analysis, we introduce key improvements in diffusion process parameterization, network architecture, and training objectives. These changes enable us to train continuous-time CMs at an unprecedented scale, reaching 1.5B parameters on ImageNet 512x512. Our proposed training algorithm, using only two sampling steps, achieves FID scores of 2.06 on CIFAR-10, 1.48 on ImageNet 64x64, and 1.88 on ImageNet 512x512, narrowing the gap in FID scores with the best existing diffusion models to within 10%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lu,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cheng Lu&lt;/a&gt;
, 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Song,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yang Song&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11081&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Thinking LLMs:General Instruction Following with Thought Generation</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thinking LLMs:General Instruction Following with Thought Generation" />
      <published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; LLMs are typically trained to answer user questions or follow instructions similarly to how human experts respond. However, in the standard alignment framework they lack the basic ability of explicit thinking before answering. Thinking is important for complex questions that require reasoning and planning -- but can be applied to any task. We propose a training method for equipping existing LLMs with such thinking abilities for general instruction following without use of additional human data. We achieve this by an iterative search and optimization procedure that explores the space of possible thought generations, allowing the model to learn how to think without direct supervision. For each instruction, the thought candidates are scored using a judge model to evaluate their responses only, and then optimized via preference optimization. We show that this procedure leads to superior performance on AlpacaEval and Arena-Hard, and shows gains from thinking on non-reasoning categories such as marketing, health and general knowledge, in addition to more traditional reasoning &amp;amp; problem-solving tasks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wu,+T&quot;&gt;Tianhao Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lan,+J&quot;&gt;Janice Lan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yuan,+W&quot;&gt;Weizhe Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jiao,+J&quot;&gt;Jiantao Jiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Weston,+J&quot;&gt;Jason Weston&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sukhbaatar,+S&quot;&gt;Sainbayar Sukhbaatar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10630&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Scaling Laws For Diffusion Transformers</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scaling Laws For Diffusion Transformers" />
      <published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Diffusion transformers (DiT) have already achieved appealing synthesis and scaling properties in content recreation, e.g., image and video generation. However, scaling laws of DiT are less explored, which usually offer precise predictions regarding optimal model size and data requirements given a specific compute budget. Therefore, experiments across a broad range of compute budgets, from 1e17 to 6e18 FLOPs are conducted to confirm the existence of scaling laws in DiT for the first time. Concretely, the loss of pretraining DiT also follows a power-law relationship with the involved compute. Based on the scaling law, we can not only determine the optimal model size and required data but also accurately predict the text-to-image generation loss given a model with 1B parameters and a compute budget of 1e21 FLOPs. Additionally, we also demonstrate that the trend of pre-training loss matches the generation performances (e.g., FID), even across various datasets, which complements the mapping from compute to synthesis quality and thus provides a predictable benchmark that assesses model performance and data quality at a reduced cost. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liang,+Z&quot;&gt;Zhengyang Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+H&quot;&gt;Hao He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+C&quot;&gt;Ceyuan Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Dai,+B&quot;&gt;Bo Dai&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.08184&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">OpenCoder The Open Cookbook for Top-Tier Code Large Language Models</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/OpenCoder" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpenCoder The Open Cookbook for Top-Tier Code Large Language Models" />
      <published>2024-10-09T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/OpenCoder</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/OpenCoder">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Large language models (LLMs) for code have become indispensable in various domains, including code generation, reasoning tasks and agent systems. While open-access code LLMs are increasingly approaching the performance levels of proprietary models, high-quality code LLMs suitable for rigorous scientific investigation, particularly those with reproducible data processing pipelines and transparent training protocols, remain limited. The scarcity is due to various challenges, including resource constraints, ethical considerations, and the competitive advantages of keeping models advanced. To address the gap, we introduce OpenCoder, a top-tier code LLM that not only achieves performance comparable to leading models but also serves as an &quot;open cookbook&quot; for the research community. Unlike most prior efforts, we release not only model weights and inference code, but also the reproducible training data, complete data processing pipeline, rigorous experimental ablation results, and detailed training protocols for open scientific research. Through this comprehensive release, we identify the key ingredients for building a top-tier code LLM: (1) code optimized heuristic rules for data cleaning and methods for data deduplication, (2) recall of text corpus related to code and (3) high-quality synthetic data in both annealing and supervised fine-tuning stages. By offering this level of openness, we aim to broaden access to all aspects of a top-tier code LLM, with OpenCoder serving as both a powerful model and an open foundation to accelerate research, and enable reproducible advancements in code AI. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Huang,+S&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Siming Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Cheng,+T&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tianhao Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;J.K. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hao,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jiaran Hao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Song,+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Liuyihan Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yang Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;J. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;J.H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chenchen Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chai,+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Linzheng Chai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yuan,+R&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ruifeng Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+Z&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zhaoxiang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Fu,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jie Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+Q&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Qian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+G&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ge Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+Z&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zili Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Qi,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yuan Qi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yinghui Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chu,+W&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wei Chu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.04905&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Abstract</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
