<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/deep-learning/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2024-12-08T16:34:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/deep-learning/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Kavour | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Jingle or No Jingle. A Hilariously Serious Dive into PyTorch Image Classification for Santa Claus Detection. 🎄</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jingle_or_no_jingle" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jingle or No Jingle. A Hilariously Serious Dive into PyTorch Image Classification for Santa Claus Detection. 🎄" />
      <published>2023-12-26T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2023-12-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jingle_or_no_jingle</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jingle_or_no_jingle">&lt;p&gt; Season's Greetings, data scientists and tech enthusiasts! In the spirit of ho-ho-hilarity and cutting-edge Christmas cheer, I present to you a Christmas-themed trip into the world of PyTorch image classification. Armed with the power of pixels and powered by the magic of MacOS, this jolly project endeavors to answer the age-old question: Is Santa Claus photo bombing your holiday snapshots? Join me on this merry adventure and get ready for a sleigh ride through code, Christmas spirit, and a dash of high-tech merriment! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Before we dive into the jingle of PyTorch and the festive magic of image classification, let's address the elephant in the room – a.k.a. the neural network. If you're already familiar with the ins and outs of neural networks, fantastic! If not, take a brief pause and explore the basics in this &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;introductory post&lt;/a&gt;. Fear not! I won't be unwrapping the intricacies of neural network structures here. Instead, we're keeping it as simple as Santa's route to your chimney, because after all, his visit is just around the corner! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Introduction and Data Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; To kick things off, let's import the necessary packages to set the stage for our upcoming tasks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  from pathlib import Path
  from timeit import default_timer as timer
  import random
  from PIL import Image
  import numpy as np
  import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
  from tqdm.auto import tqdm
  
  import torch
  from torch import nn
  from torch.utils.data import DataLoader
  from torchvision import datasets, transforms


  from santa_functions import (walk_through_dir,
                             accuracy_fn,
                             print_train_time,
                             plot_transformed_images)
  from CNN_Model import SantaCNN
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt; All the libraries, except for the final two, consist of built-in modules housing valuable functions and classes essential for our Santa-spotting mission. You can locate the last two in &lt;a href=&quot;//&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt;, which also hosts the utilized data. Additionally, I've included two Python scripts allowing you to effortlessly rename all files within a folder. I found this handy for organizing the myriad photos collected, ensuring seamless tracking when needed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; After securing the aforementioned files, it's prudent to verify that everything is in order. Consequently, I've provided some lines of code for a quick cross-check. To initiate this, we establish the path to the directory containing our data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
# Directory containing data
data_path = Path(&quot;/your/path/to/Is that Santa? 🎅/project&quot;)
image_path = data_path / &quot;train&quot;
  
walk_through_dir(image_path)
  
# Setup train and testing directory

train_dir = &quot;/path/to/data/train&quot;
test_dir = &quot;/path/to/data/test&quot;
  
walk_through_dir(train_dir)
walk_through_dir(test_dir)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure that within the designated path (e.g., test_dir), a specific number of images is present—308 depicting Santa and an equivalent number portraying non-Santa scenarios. Following this, our next task is to select a &quot;random&quot; image (seed predetermined) and scrutinize its dimensional particulars.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  random.seed(42)
  image_path_list = list(image_path.glob(&quot;*/*.jpg&quot;))
  random_image_path = random.choice(image_path_list)
  image_class = random_image_path.parent.stem
  img = Image.open(random_image_path)
  
  
  print(f&quot;Random image path: {random_image_path}&quot;)
  print(f&quot;Image class: {image_class}&quot;)
  print(f&quot;Image height: {img.height}&quot;)
  print(f&quot;Image width: {img.width}&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where we receive the details as an outcome:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Random image path: /path/to/selected/image/265_NotSanta.jpg
Image class: non_santa
Image height: 574
Image width: 1148
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let's spot the not so Santa to be witness of this madness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
img_as_array = np.asarray(img)
plt.figure(figsize=(10, 7))
plt.imshow(img_as_array)
plt.title(f&quot;Image class: {image_class} | Image shape: {img_as_array.shape} -&amp;gt; [height, width, color_channels]&quot;)
plt.axis(False)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/jingle_no_jingle/sample_pic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample_Santa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon closer inspection, you'll observe that the included images exhibit varying dimensions. This variability demands attention to enhance our model's efficacy. Consequently, we'll implement specific transformations. Initially, we'll standardize all images to a uniform size of 64 by 64. Following this, we'll introduce random flips with a 50% probability for certain images. This strategic move aims to prevent the model from fixating on the horizontal direction as a defining feature of Santa, ensuring a more robust learning process. Lastly, to seamlessly integrate these images into our model, we'll convert them into tensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
data_transform = transforms.Compose([
    transforms.Resize(size=(64, 64)),
    transforms.RandomHorizontalFlip(p=0.5),
    transforms.ToTensor()
])

plot_transformed_images(image_path_list,
                        transform=data_transform,
                        n=3)
train_data = datasets.ImageFolder(root=train_dir,
                                  transform=data_transform,
                                  target_transform=None)

test_data = datasets.ImageFolder(root=test_dir,
                                 transform=data_transform)

print(f&quot;Train data:\n{train_data}\nTest data:\n{test_data}&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the upcoming lines, we'll establish the image classes present in the training and testing folders. As you might anticipate, these classes are none other than Santa and Not Santa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
class_names = train_data.classes
class_names

class_dict = train_data.class_to_idx
class_dict
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Finally, in order to use our data iteratively in batches and not all at once, we are going to use the &lt;code&gt;DataLoader&lt;/code&gt; format, build-in &lt;code&gt;torch.utils.data&lt;/code&gt; as imported from above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
BATCH_SIZE = 32
train_dataloader = DataLoader(train_data,
    batch_size=BATCH_SIZE,
    shuffle=True
)

test_dataloader = DataLoader(test_data,
    batch_size=BATCH_SIZE,
    shuffle=False
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to take a look at the objects we just created and investigate their dimensions, we can run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
train_features_batch, train_labels_batch = next(iter(train_dataloader))
train_features_batch.shape, train_labels_batch.shape
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we are going to see the exact shape of train and features and labels that we will import to our model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
(torch.Size([32, 3, 64, 64]), torch.Size([32])) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Model Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand; you might be contemplating something right now. While I initially mentioned avoiding an in-depth exploration of the model's intricacies, I'd like to clarify that I won't delve into technical specifics. Instead, let's take a moment to introduce the architecture that underlies the results we'll unveil shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's meet the SantaCNN, a neural network ready to crack this festive code! This jolly model, is inspired by the TinyVGG architecture (because even Santa needs a tech upgrade), is on a mission to distinguish between Santa  and mere holiday enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SantaCNN is a two-block ensemble, each packed with convolutional charm. The first block, a confection of convolutions (Conv2d), ReLUs, and a splash of MaxPooling magic, sets the stage for unraveling the festive mysteries. Block two follows suit, further refining the holiday essence with additional layers of convolutional wizardry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, here's where the magic happens: the classifier swoops in like Santa on Christmas Eve, flaunting a Flattening feat and a Linear layer to make sense of the pixelated clues. With an impressive 8192 in_features dance, our neural maestro is ready to deliver the verdict: Naughty or Nice (Santa edition).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details take a look at the &lt;code&gt;CNN_model.py&lt;/code&gt;, in the aforementioned repo, or ask me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Let's find Santa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first – let's don our Santa goggles! In the upcoming Python script, we're not only sketching out our initial model but also summoning the powers of a loss function and an optimizer. These dynamic duos will be our guiding elves, assisting us in fine-tuning those parameters batch by batch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
model_init = SantaCNN(input_shape=3,
    hidden_units=32,
    output_shape=len(class_names))

loss_fn = nn.CrossEntropyLoss()
optimizer = torch.optim.Adam(params=model_init.parameters(),
                            lr=0.001)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are going to establish our training and testing loop for preselected number of epochs and take a look at the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
torch.manual_seed(42)
train_time_start_on_cpu = timer()

epochs = 10

for epoch in tqdm(range(epochs)):
    print(f&quot;Epoch: {epoch}\n-------&quot;)
    train_loss = 0
    for batch, (X, y) in enumerate(train_dataloader):
        model_init.train()
        y_pred = model_init(X)
        loss = loss_fn(y_pred, y)
        train_loss += loss
        optimizer.zero_grad()
        loss.backward()
        optimizer.step()
        if batch % 400 == 0:
            print(f&quot;Looked at {batch * len(X)}/{len(train_dataloader.dataset)} samples&quot;)
    train_loss /= len(train_dataloader)

    test_loss, test_acc = 0, 0
    model_init.eval()
    with torch.inference_mode():
        for X, y in test_dataloader:
            test_pred = model_init(X)
            test_loss += loss_fn(test_pred, y)
            test_acc += accuracy_fn(y_true=y, y_pred=test_pred.argmax(dim=1))
        test_loss /= len(test_dataloader)
        test_acc /= len(test_dataloader)

    print(f&quot;\nTrain loss: {train_loss:.5f} | Test loss: {test_loss:.5f}, Test acc: {test_acc:.2f}%\n&quot;)

train_time_end_on_cpu = timer()
total_train_time_model_0 = print_train_time(start=train_time_start_on_cpu,
                                            end=train_time_end_on_cpu,
                                            device=str(next(model_init.parameters()).device))
total_train_time_model_0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt; And you are wondering right now, what are the results, right? Well the last iteration return the following results: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Train loss: 0.00240 | Test loss: 0.33573, Test acc: 91.88%

Train time on cpu: 280.503 seconds
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty good, huh? Well, off you go – import those selfies and delve deeper into the mystical realm of Santa Claus spirit. Wishing you better luck than I had; may you uncover his elusive presence hidden somewhere in the background! 🎅🔍 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I hope you enjoyed this, and the rest of this year's posts as much as I did and learned something!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be safe, code safer!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="project" />
      
        <category term="Deep Learning" />
      
        <category term="PyTorch Vision" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Season's Greetings, data scientists and tech enthusiasts! In the spirit of ho-ho-hilarity and cutting-edge Christmas cheer, I present to you a Christmas-themed trip into the world of PyTorch image classification. Armed with the power of pixels and powered by the magic of MacOS, this jolly project endeavors to answer the age-old question: Is Santa Claus photo bombing your holiday snapshots? Join me on this merry adventure and get ready for a sleigh ride through code, Christmas spirit, and a dash of high-tech merriment! Before we dive into the jingle of PyTorch and the festive magic of image classification, let's address the elephant in the room – a.k.a. the neural network. If you're already familiar with the ins and outs of neural networks, fantastic! If not, take a brief pause and explore the basics in this introductory post. Fear not! I won't be unwrapping the intricacies of neural network structures here. Instead, we're keeping it as simple as Santa's route to your chimney, because after all, his visit is just around the corner!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Neural Network ~ Predicting a Numerical Value</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/neural_network" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neural Network ~ Predicting a Numerical Value" />
      <published>2023-03-04T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2023-03-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/neural_network</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neural_network">&lt;p&gt;Welcome back! As part of this introductory series on Neural Networks, we will be exploring the process of building NNs and making decisions about their topology. This includes determining the number of layers, the number of neurons per layer, selecting appropriate activation functions, and implementing backpropagation. Throughout this process, we will delve into various factors to consider when building an effective neural network. Though everything is statistics (😉) I will try to keep statistical formulas to the minimum possible level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado let's jump right into fun (hopefully!).  In this post we will be building two differenct neural network models to predict numerical values :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model to predict the strength of concrete strength.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A model to predict the prices of houses in Paris (Why Paris? Don't know just cause! We don't need a reason for everything, accept it 😛)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I planned to explain the concepts and decision-making process between the code chunks. However, I understand that some readers may prefer to just jump straight into the code and results. Therefore, I will provide a summary of the topics I plan to cover at the top of the post and keep the code and results at the bottom for those who prefer that approach. No judgement here - feel free to choose what works best for you! Or is there some judgement? Just kiding, choose your way (or am I not? 😛)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we encounter a neural network, the first thing that typically stands out to us is the layer structure. Before we dive into understanding the movement, input features, activation functions, or weights, we need to have a solid grasp of the layers in a neural network. So let's start from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to decide the number of the layers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, there is no solid way or any rule of thumb to calculate the number of layers needed for any type of problem you are trying to solve. As a result, deciding on the number of layers can be a challenging task. However, there are some general guidelines that can help:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Start small&lt;/strong&gt;: Beginning with a simple network structure with just a few layers can help to avoid overfitting and to gradually increase the complexity as needed. Remember the goal is to find the simplest model possible not the most complex one. A small network with few layers is called shallow neural network. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Research pre-existing architectures&lt;/strong&gt;: If possible, consider using pre-existing network architectures that have proven effective in solving similar problems. I know you want to build your own model and you want to be independent, but your mother's cooked food is always better than yours, right? So try searching around for your mom, I mean a built model that is proven to work efficiently and the try adjusting this to your own needs. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Get to know your data&lt;/strong&gt;: Having a large amount of training data can support deeper and more complex neural networks. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Practise, practise, practise..&lt;/strong&gt;: The Mose effective way to find out the optimal number of layers your your specific needs and flavours, is through experimentation and testing difference architectures, so after completing the steps described above, play around, change the configurations and check the outcome. The time is your enemy and depending on the pc specs you run your tests on, hopefully, this won't take long per model build. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, there is no one rule that fits the all to determin the oprimal number of layers in a neural network. Only one mom to cook the perfect dish for every occation. The key is to balance the complexity of the network with the available resources and the data in your environment. Remember though, we aim for simplicity as choosing more that 2 layers, can get computationally expensive really fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine with the layers, but how many neurons should we use per layer added in a model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you search around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; for information on determining the optimal number of neurons per layer in a neural network, you will come across several &quot;rules of thumb&quot; that suggest a range of options. Some of those are the following: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you search for information on determining the optimal number of neurons per layer in a neural network, you may come across several &quot;rules of thumb&quot; that suggest a range of options. While these rules can provide a starting point, it's important to remember that the optimal solution may vary depending on the specific problem you are trying to solve. Therefore, it's important to also consider other factors such as the complexity of the problem, available resources, and experimentation with different architectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The number of hidden neurons should be between the size of the input layer and the size of the output layer. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The number of the neurons should be 2/3 the size of the input layer, plus the size of the output layer. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The number of the hidden neurons should be less than twice the size of the input layer. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these ruls can provide a starting point, it's important to remember that the optimal solution may vary depending on the problem that you are trying to answer. Once again, I feel the need to remind you that we aim for the simpliest model possible, complexity costs and slow us down. Remember after all the most beutiful mathematical formulas are the simpliest ones. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While keeping that in mind, note that using less neurons than it is required may lead us to underfitting the data imported, while using more neurons than needed may end up to overfitting, high variance and increse the time it takes to train the network. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A way that may give us a good intuition on the number of neurons needed is using cross-validation method with different configurations (starting with the simplest possible) and compare the Mean Square Errors (MSE) in order to stick with the option that minimises MSE. Fill free to try this in the models we are going to build and find out a better model architecture for the models provided below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool cool cool.. No doubt.. How do we pass through the neurons and layers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/XAdbHJywVjF5K&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;274&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/someone-gwen-stefani-XAdbHJywVjF5K&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those two or three..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/XAdbHJywVjF5K&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am glad you asked.. (Did you? Hopefully you did, or I am hearing voices 👻). If you recall from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kavourei.github.io/neural_network_intro&quot;&gt;introductory post&lt;/a&gt; of this series, we mentioned the activation functions which we shall discuss later in this post, but I have not mentioned at all the work backpropagation though you may have come across in some posts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://people.idsia.ch/~juergen/who-invented-backpropagation-2014.html&quot;&gt;Backpropagation&lt;/a&gt; is a fundamental algorithm in the training process. The main purpose that we use back propagation is to adjust the weights (the numbers above the arrows that you will come across later in a NN plot) of the neural network. The weights distinguish level of importance that every feature (through the neurons in the input layer) has. Recall the example of the house pricing. It is more important that it has proper roof than higher number of entrances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backpropagation works iteratively. This means that the algorithm is used many times to adjust the weights that the difference between the predicted outcome and the actual outcome through the training process is minimized. This is also known as the error. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps at every iteration is the following. After a full process is completed and the model has the first pair of results, the backpropagation (BP) algorithm is set to use. It starts from the end (output) to the beginning (input) of the model, that is why it is called -&lt;strong&gt;back&lt;/strong&gt;-propagation. It computes the derivative of the error with respect to each weight in the network. This tells us (don't worry it is done without your contribution) how much each choice of weight has contributed to the final error acquired at the end, hence how much this can be adjusted. Then changes are made and then the model runs from the beginning to the end once again, producing a new error, and going back again calculating new weights. This back and forth is done many many times (hopefully, not that many) until the error is minimised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this repeation, the network grafually learns to map input data to output data more accurately. This process is often reffered as learning rate. Overall BP is a powerfull tool and helps us humans solve very complex problems. The formulation of this process to programm by hand can be really complex, but there is no need for that as R (and Python for anyone interested) gives us this as an option to choose amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is learning rate mentioned earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well during the process of BP, we said that the weights are adjusted. Learning rate is the steps that we allow the algorithm to take. In other words, is the amount that we allow the algorithm to adjust the weights per iteration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you may think that we can set this high so that the model will converge fast..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am a sorry to be the party pooper (💩) here but setting learning rate high can lead our model to diverge. This can happen as the optimal choice of weight may be &quot;jumped over&quot; a big step of weight configuration. Image you search for a middle in the floor, you can not search while making huge steps. On the other hand, it is sure that making small steps will lead us to finding the middle though it make take time, so really small steps is not a good option as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what?!? There is no method that tells us the learning rate no matter the problem. Some of the best practises are the following : &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Loss/Error VS Learning Rate&lt;/strong&gt; : With this approach if you are patient, you have to plot the loss function vs the learning rate on a logarithmic scale, which will help us deside on a good range of learning rates to use. On the range that has been prompted, we have to use the largest possible, as we want the model to converge without many iterations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Grid Search&lt;/strong&gt; : Again, if you are patient enough, by trying out different learning rates over the training values and evaluating the performance of the model on the validation set, can help you identify a good range of learning rates to use. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that was all I wanted to discuss about Neural Network configurations and really did not used any mathematical/statistical formulas at all!!! I hope you got the ideas presented above (as simple as possible). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is time for the second part, the implementation. Bellow you will see two examples. The first implementation is from a really good book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Machine-Learning-techniques-predictive-modeling/dp/1788295862&quot;&gt;Machine Learning with R&lt;/a&gt;&quot; providing you with as much information needed to get introduced to the topic and the other one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;. All the data can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stedy/Machine-Learning-with-R-datasets/blob/master/concrete.csv&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usuall, we are going to start with importing the libraries. We are going to use &lt;em&gt;caret&lt;/em&gt; library in order to split the data randomly. The library &lt;em&gt;neuralnet&lt;/em&gt; to build neural network models. The last library, &lt;em&gt;sigmoid&lt;/em&gt;, is worth noting as it contains all the activation functions mentioned in the previous post. I you feel like it take a moment and search for the document of this last one, in order to check what are the functions included in there, so you dop't have to define them from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
library(caret)
library(neuralnet)
library(sigmoid)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward we are going to load the data for the first example, the concrete one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
data1_init &amp;lt;- read.csv('/Users/.../concrete.csv')

str(data1_init)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see we have the 8 input features and the last one that is the output to be predicted feature, the strength of the concrete. All the models perform much better with normalised data. There are many ways to do that, it's one with some unique pros and cons (It is out of this post's scope to dive into that). Some to mention are the normalise with log transformation, with Min-Max values (which we are going to use) or with stars scaling (also called standardisation). In order to perform the normalisation selected, there are two ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the process as a custom function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the usage of the functions &lt;em&gt;preProcess&lt;/em&gt; and predict. In the first one you choose the type through the argument &lt;em&gt;mehtod&lt;/em&gt; and then by passing through the second function you apply this method to the data you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's define our normalisation function, which will be clearer how the process works and then apply the normalisation function to the data imported:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
custom_norm &amp;lt;- function(x){
  return((x-min(x))/(max(x)-min(x)))
}
data1_norm &amp;lt;- as.data.frame(lapply(data1_init, custom_norm))

str(data1_norm)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to split the data to train and test datasets. Though a better practise is to split data in three parts, train, validation and test datasets, we will use the simpler way as the point of the posts is to get solid foundations and build upon that on later steps and further experimentation. In order to split the data we run the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
set.seed(1)
trainIndex &amp;lt;- createDataPartition(data1_norm$strength,
                                  p = 0.7,
                                  list = FALSE,
                                  times = 1) 
data1_train &amp;lt;- data1_norm[trainIndex,]
data1_test &amp;lt;- data1_norm[-trainIndex,]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use here the &lt;em&gt;set.seed(1)&lt;/em&gt; so that if you copy and paste the code chunks you end up with the same results as me. The creatDataPartition help us create index to take the train and test sample according to the vector we will use as outcome. The second argument is used to define the amount of data we will split the data upon, here we use 70%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what time it is.. To build our first model. We are going to build the simplest model possible to start with and get an idea. We will use the function &lt;em&gt;neuralnet&lt;/em&gt;. As the first argument, we define the data that we take the features from and then address the formula. Before the tilde ( '~' ) we define the output variable to be predicted and in the right of it we define the input features. By adding the dot, we indicate to the model to use all the other features available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
conc_model1 &amp;lt;- neuralnet(data = data1_train, strength ~ .)
plot(conc_model1)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our first Neural Network. Here we see the input layer (all the dots to the right), with the weights each feature is measured with the help of BP, the hidden layer (1) in the middle, where the logarithmic activation function is used (by default in neuralnet) and th outcome where layer. Bellow we can see the Error (which is the sum of squared errors (&lt;strong&gt;SSE&lt;/strong&gt;)) and the number of training steps required for the model to converge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to evaluate our first NN, we continue as listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
conc_results1 &amp;lt;- compute(conc_model1, data1_test[1:8])
conc_pred1 &amp;lt;- conc_results1$net.result
cor(conc_pred1,data1_test[9])
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correlation at 0.84, not bad for our first try, right? Let's run some more evaluation metrics though. I will use bellow the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Mean Squared Error (&lt;strong&gt;MSE&lt;/strong&gt;) : It represents the difference between the original and predicted values extracted by squared the average difference over the data set. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Mean Absolute Error (&lt;strong&gt;MAE&lt;/strong&gt;) : It represents the difference between the original and predicted values extracted by the averaged absolute difference over the data set. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Root Mean Squared Error (&lt;strong&gt;RMSE&lt;/strong&gt;) is the error rate by the square root of MSE &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Coefficient of determination (&lt;strong&gt;R-squared&lt;/strong&gt;) represents the coefficient of how well the values fit compared to the original values of a vanilla model. The value from 0 to 1 interpreted as percentages. The higher the value is, the better the model is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
d1 = data1_test$strength-conc_pred1
mse = mean((d1)^2)
mae = mean(abs(d1))
rmse = sqrt(mse)
R2 = 1-(sum((d1)^2)/sum((data1_test$strength-mean(data1_test$strength))^2))
cat(&quot; MAE:&quot;, mae, &quot;\n&quot;, &quot;MSE:&quot;, mse, &quot;\n&quot;, 
    &quot;RMSE:&quot;, rmse, &quot;\n&quot;, &quot;R-squared:&quot;, R2)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see that overall, the results we obtain are good. But there is always room for improvement. &lt;strong&gt;Perfection is the enemy of a good result&lt;/strong&gt; after all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
conc_model2 &amp;lt;- neuralnet(data = data1_train, strength ~ ., hidden =5)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we have modified the single hidden layer, by adding 4 extra neurons (5 in total) through the argument of &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
plot(conc_model2) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the Error provided through the plot of the new NN model, we have a sign that we have improved the situation, though let us proceed to our model evaluation metrics introduced above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
conc_results2 &amp;lt;- compute(conc_model2, data1_test[1:8])
conc_pred2 &amp;lt;- conc_results2$net.result
cor(conc_pred2,data1_test[9])

d2 = data1_test$strength-conc_pred2
mse = mean((d2)^2)
mae = mean(abs(d2))
rmse = sqrt(mse)
R2 = 1-(sum((d2)^2)/sum((data1_test$strength-mean(data1_test$strength))^2))
cat(&quot; MAE:&quot;, mae, &quot;\n&quot;, &quot;MSE:&quot;, mse, &quot;\n&quot;, 
    &quot;RMSE:&quot;, rmse, &quot;\n&quot;, &quot;R-squared:&quot;, R2)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can clearly see that we have obtained from that small change. You can modify the model above by adding one or more layers and change the number of the neurons. Though this is like a sandbox where you can test different things, remember you always need to take care of the number of layers and neurons used as the most common error of the excitement while going closer to perfect prediction is overfitting.. In order to change the number of letters, we should modify the &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; argument in the &lt;em&gt;neuralnet&lt;/em&gt; function. For example if we want 4 neurons in the first hidden layer and 5 in the second we should define it as &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
example_model &amp;lt;- neuralnet(..., hidden = c(4,5))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from those there are many more arguments to modify your network like &lt;em&gt;startweights&lt;/em&gt; which defines the starting value of each weight, &lt;em&gt;learningrate&lt;/em&gt; which indicates the learning rate of your model, &lt;em&gt;algorithm&lt;/em&gt; which let's you change the algorithm for weights adjustment (a.k.a. change the default backpropagation usage), &lt;em&gt;act.fct&lt;/em&gt; which let's you choose activation function through your model, &lt;em&gt;err.fct&lt;/em&gt; which gives you the power to use specific error calculating function and many many more, feel free to type &lt;strong&gt;neuralnet&lt;/strong&gt; in your console to find out all of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second example is an implementation of two neural network models. After followin the same normalization preprocessing and splitting steps as above for the data about house prices in Paris we have a 1-3-1 model  where the hidden layers will consist from 4 neurons each and a 1-1-1 model where the hidden layer will consist from 2 neurons, and compare the results. In those models, the ReLU activation function was used. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
house_model0 &amp;lt;- neuralnet(data = house_train, price ~ .,hidden = c(2),act.fct = relu)
house_model1 &amp;lt;- neuralnet(data = house_train, price ~ .,hidden = c(4,4,4), act.fct = relu)

plot(house_model0)
plot(house_model1)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let us run all the evaluation metrics in order to compare the two models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
data.frame(Model_1 = c(cor21,mae21,mse21,rmse21,R2_21),
           Model_2= c(cor22,mae22,mse22,rmse22,R2_22),
           row.names = c('Correlation',&quot;MAE:&quot;,&quot;MSE:&quot;,&quot;RMSE:&quot;,&quot;R-squared:&quot;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the evaluation metrics, we can say that both our models do great at predicting the house prices. The reason that I have used these examples though is not to build the models, is to show to you that a much deeper model will not always result in a better situation. Apart from the result, the complexity and computational time needed to build the second model is much more than the first one. So keep in mind when playing around that we always aim for the simplest model possible that will give us the best results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading this post, I hope you have learned something new and more importantly noe you are able to implement yourself neural netowrks to predict numerical values. There will be a new post about image recognition on the topic where we will use some different kind of neural networks. Anyways thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this place I would like to especially thank the readers who send me their comments (both good and bad) and general remarks, with their help I become better and keep it going. So thank you guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be safe, code safer!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="project" />
      
        <category term="Deep Learning" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome back! As part of this introductory series on Neural Networks, we will be exploring the process of building NNs and making decisions about their topology. This includes determining the number of layers, the number of neurons per layer, selecting appropriate activation functions, and implementing backpropagation. Throughout this process, we will delve into various factors to consider when building an effective neural network. Though everything is statistics (😉) I will try to keep statistical formulas to the minimum possible level.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A smooth introduction to Neural Networks</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/neural_network_intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A smooth introduction to Neural Networks" />
      <published>2023-02-09T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2023-02-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/neural_network_intro</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neural_network_intro">&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, deep learning is entering in our lives deeper and deeper (you see what I did there?!? 🤯🤯🤯) Anyways, as I was saying the evolution of deep learning and the usage of Neural Network has taken an exponential rate. As not everyone is a computer science expert/enthusiast it is obvious that a question may rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
What is Neural Network and how such a network works?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to create a series of posts, starting with this one, where I will try to answer this very question stated above. Initially, in this post, I will try to present to you a brief introduction on the topic, including the components of a neural network, the steps one need to follow in order to create such a network and of course where this can help us.  I will try not to bring on the surface difficult mathematical formulas or nonsense calculations, so hopefully, you will enjoy reading this and will be waiting for the implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Neural Networks - The first touch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our everyday life, we are meant to complete tasks that require, or not, our effort. As you can guess the effort may differ from task to task. Some of those tasks, you would not think as ones that you put effort to complete and if I was to ask you, you would not even considering to enumerate them. Some, that I have in mind are objects detection or patterns recognition. Consider for example when you try to cross the road and check to your right and left, if any car is passing by or not. This is a task as object detection that you have to complete almost every day and you don't even think about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday doings as the one I have just mentioned or any other you could think of, is completed with the help of a system that is placed within our body. Every one of us has a network that helps them take actions and complete tasks. This network is not other than our own biological neural network. This nervous system is built up of many interconnectioned neurons (you may have heard the term &quot;nerve cells&quot;). The nervous system uses the neurons to send messages back and forth from the brain, through the spinal cord, to the nerves throughout the body. As simple as that. Whether you see a car coming then (hopefully) won't pass the road, as you have detected an object (the car). Or imagine you touch a cactus to its spine. At this very moment, the nerves in your finger send a message to your brain that this is not probably good, and this is converted to pain, more or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial neural networks (ANN) are inspired by this and attempt to mimic the way that our brain and biological nervous system works. Artificial Neural Networks were firstly introduced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warren_Sturgis_McCulloch&quot;&gt;Warren McCulloch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Pitts&quot;&gt;Walter Pitts&lt;/a&gt;. They established the computational model in 1943 in their paper called &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF02478259&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;A Logical Calculus of the Ideas Immanent in Nervous Activity&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
In this paper a mathematical model is proposed inspired by our own neural network. A binary neuron model is described, in which each neuron receives input from other neurons and generates an output based on a threshold function. At the end the authors suggested that this simple model could perform logical operations.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I believe that now you have a general idea of what is a neural network, and of course many many questions should start popping in your head, I can imagine. Let's continue and I will try to answer them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
So, what does a neural network consists of?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A neural network consists of 3 layers: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Input Layer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Hidden Layers&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The Output Layer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's take them one by one. The &lt;strong&gt;input layer&lt;/strong&gt; is there to welcome all the variables that the scientist would like to use in the model. In our example before the input layer of our biological nervous system is the finger, and the variable incoming is the cactus needle when we touched it (🫳🌵🙅🏽), I believe you get the idea here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, the &lt;strong&gt;hidden layers&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the layers between the input and the output layers. The data when passed from the input layer are processed in this part of the model and generate a representation, which is passed to the next layer. The term hidden is given due to the fact that the neuron's activation (that belong in this layers) are not obvious/visible from the input layer or the output of the network and as a result this term is set. This layer allows the model, hence the scientist, to model complex relationships and abstractions of the data, which enables them to create powerful predictions and classification tasks. The numbers of the neurons and the number of the layers can be adjusted according to the needs and the complexity in order to obtain accuracy depending of the obtained data and the goal. The hidden layer for our example would be our brain, where the information imported is processed and valued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but obviously not less important than the rest, is the &lt;strong&gt;output layer&lt;/strong&gt;. Through this layer the outcome of the model is produced based on the information processed by the previous layers (input and hidden). The numbers of the neurons in the output layer depends on the task that the network is designed to perform. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary classification is probably one output neuron that produces the probability expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In multi-class classification there is one output neuron per class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cactus example of course, as you can guess the output is the pain we feel after the process that took place in our own hidden layers (a.k.a. the brain) imported from our own input layer (our stupid action to touch the cactus, just kidding, I mean our finger).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Neural Networks - The &quot;Magic&quot; behind fancy words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far so good. I believe that the next obvious question would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
And how does this work?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following situation. Imagine the case where you want to buy a house. What are the factors that matter in a house's price? Some that I could think of are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The neighbourhood &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The available rooms &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The time it was built &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; etc &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So each of those factors represent a variable, let's assume that neighbourhood is x1, available rooms x2, time it was built x3, and the rest that you can think of. So obviously some are more important than others and play a greater role in our model. As a result, every factor is assigned to a weight (let's say the weight of importance).  After a weight is assigned to each factor, we can produce the weighted sum of all those factors. Finally with the help of an activation function, this is converted and output to a number. The output that we search for (hopefully if we have done everything right 🤞🏼). Bellow, with the help of a graph, those steps are represented in a simple and clear way. I believe till now everything is well understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/intro_to_nn/1_simple_nn_architecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;NN Architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤔🤔🤔&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you may want to say the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Ok..?!?.. But what is the activation function?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the final touch in our models, to be completed. In order to explain the use of activation functions, I would like you to think of google translate. So what is the way you use google translate?!? You select the language you are going to type in and then the one you want the words to be translated to. So activation function is more or less doing the same thing. After the Weighted sum of the factors is calculated after you end up with a number. Then the activation function is called to translate this number to a solution you are searching for. Imagine this, you are trying to create a neural network to classify a picture that shows a dog. In order to do that you set the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 0 : The picture does not contain a dog &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 : The picture contains a dog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not going to get in the details of the network's architecture in this post, but basically, you want to end up to a result based on probabilities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just reminding: probabilities are in the set of [0,1]. Probability of 1 means that the event is certainly going to happen, whereas probability of 0 implies that the event is not going to happen, eveeeeeerrrrrrrrrrrrr..... 😛&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So by calculating the sum of weighted factors, you are going to end up with a number that most of the cases do not belong in the [0,1] set. After all, what activation function do is that it translates the result to the desired solution (in our example, a number that belongs to the set [0,1] and tells us with what probability the picture we provided contains a dog). I believe you get why we need it in our game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More formally, with the use of an activation function we can introduce non-linearity into the network that we build, which gives us the flexibility to create networks to model more complex relationship between inputs and outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three types of activation functions Linear, Binary and Non-Linear activation functions. Most common activation functions that are used are :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sigmoid_function&quot;&gt;Sigmoid&lt;/a&gt; : This function is useful for binary classification problems. It can map any inputs to a value between 0 and 1. 😮😲 Yes, this fits our problem above! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rectifier_(neural_networks)&quot;&gt;Rectified Linear Unit&lt;/a&gt; : A more common name is ReLU. This function returns the output only if this is a positive number otherwise it returns 0. Using ReLu can add up computational efficiency to our network &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperbolic_functions&quot;&gt;Hyperbolic Tangent&lt;/a&gt; : Also called Tanh. This is activation function maps any input to a value between -1 and 1. This activation function is mainly used for cyclical or periodic data. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Softmax_function&quot;&gt;Softmax&lt;/a&gt; : This is like Sigmoid, but instead of just one class (dog-no dog) it is used to produce a probability distribution amongst classes and find out the most suitable one. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more activation functions if you search around though those are the ones used the most. An appropriate activation function choice is a crucial part for the performance of our network. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/intro_to_nn/2_activation_funcs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Activation Functions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Neural Network - Uses and limits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas! We reached the final part, the exciting one. Artificial Neural Networks is a powerful tool and by getting to know it better and better you can complete resolve complex tasks in wide variety of fields. Some of the most common applications of neural networks are :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Speech Recognition &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Image Classification &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Recommender Systems &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Anomaly Detection &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are only some examples of the range of tasks one can complete with the help of Neural Networks. With the right knowledge and the patience to get the details, ANNs can become the ace up your sleeve. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course everything has its own price. This very saying applies to our case as well. Some of the limitations you should consider are &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Amount of data : ANNs require big amount of data which are well prepared and of course labeled, in order to train the network. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Expensive : In order to train ANN can become a vary expensive procedure. When I say expensive I mean on one hand to obtain well preserved data as well the computational power needed for preparing data and training the network. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Time Consuming : Artificial neural networks are highly sensitive to the hyperparameters used, such as the learning rate, the number of hidden layers, and the number of neurons in each layer. Which makes it a slow process to find the ones that fit your purpose. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Overfitting : Artificial Neural Networks can easily overfit data during the training process. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt; But still, don't let yourself down. Neural Networks is still a very useful and powerful tool. Knowing the limitations, can only be a positive thing as we shall keep in mind what to be cautious about and what to avoid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all I wanted to tell you about Artificial Neural Networks. I hope you got the whole process and learned a thing or two. Stay tuned for some applications on this subject. Thank you for reading this post! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be safe, code safer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Kavour</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="project" />
      
        <category term="Deep Learning" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Introduction</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
