<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-24T14:03:49+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kavour</title><subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introducing Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces by Perplexity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/perplexity" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces by Perplexity" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/perplexity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/perplexity">&lt;p&gt;Perplexity AI has launched Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces, innovative features designed to enhance information retrieval and collaboration within teams. These tools aim to streamline access to knowledge and improve productivity by allowing users to create customized environments for their specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LqKZAHeCkEg?si=Lbi6TDCAYDz_0fvn&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an era where information overload is a common challenge, Perplexity AI has introduced two groundbreaking features: &lt;strong&gt;Internal Knowledge Search&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spaces&lt;/strong&gt;. These tools are designed to empower users by enhancing their ability to find relevant information quickly and collaborate effectively within their teams. By focusing on personalized knowledge management, Perplexity AI aims to transform how individuals and organizations interact with data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effective knowledge management is crucial for organizations looking to maintain a competitive edge. As teams grow and projects become more complex, the ability to access and share information seamlessly becomes paramount. Internal Knowledge Search addresses this need by providing a powerful search capability that allows users to sift through vast amounts of data effortlessly. This feature not only enhances individual productivity but also fosters a culture of collaboration as team members can easily share insights and findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internal Knowledge Search feature enables users to conduct deep searches across internal documents, notes, and other resources, making it easier to locate specific information quickly. This capability is enhanced by advanced filtering options that allow users to refine their searches based on various criteria. Meanwhile, Spaces offers a customizable environment where teams can organize their projects, share resources, and collaborate in real-time. Users can create dedicated spaces for different projects or topics, ensuring that relevant information is always at hand. Together, these features create a cohesive ecosystem that enhances both individual and team productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of Internal Knowledge Search into the Perplexity platform is designed with user experience in mind. Users can initiate searches using natural language queries, making the process intuitive and accessible even for those who may not be tech-savvy. The results are displayed in a user-friendly format, allowing individuals to quickly identify the most pertinent information. In addition, the Spaces feature enables teams to set up their workspaces tailored to their specific workflows, facilitating smoother collaboration and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations across various sectors can benefit from these new features. For instance, research teams can utilize Internal Knowledge Search to locate relevant studies or data points swiftly, while marketing teams can leverage Spaces to brainstorm ideas and track campaign progress in a centralized location. By streamlining access to information and enhancing collaborative efforts, these tools empower teams to work more efficiently and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Perplexity AI continues to innovate, the introduction of Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces represents a significant step toward improving how individuals manage knowledge and collaborate within teams. The company is committed to refining these features based on user feedback, ensuring they meet the evolving needs of its user base. With these tools at their disposal, organizations can look forward to a future where accessing and sharing knowledge becomes second nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces by Perplexity AI marks an important milestone in the realm of knowledge management and collaboration tools. By focusing on user-friendly interfaces and powerful search capabilities, these features are set to transform how teams interact with information. As organizations strive for greater efficiency in their operations, the ability to harness internal knowledge effectively will be crucial for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To to explore these new features further, visit Perplexity AI's official &amp;lt; a href='https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/introducing-internal-knowledge-search-and-spaces?fob=fX3q7wR73cDzq5Dk'&amp;gt;blog post&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Perplexity AI has launched Internal Knowledge Search and Spaces, innovative features designed to enhance information retrieval and collaboration within teams. These tools aim to streamline access to knowledge and improve productivity by allowing users to create customized environments for their specific needs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing the prompt() Function:Enhancing SQL with LLMs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/LLMwSQL" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing the prompt() Function:Enhancing SQL with LLMs" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/LLMwSQL</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/LLMwSQL">&lt;p&gt;MotherDuck has launched the &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function, a groundbreaking feature that integrates large language models (LLMs) directly into SQL, allowing users to generate, summarize, and extract structured data efficiently. This new capability democratizes access to advanced natural language processing techniques, making it easier for developers to leverage AI in their data workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the costs associated with running large language models (LLMs) have significantly decreased, making advanced natural language processing techniques more accessible. The emergence of small language models (SLMs) like OpenAI’s gpt-4o-mini has further contributed to this trend, enabling cost-effective integration of AI capabilities into various applications. MotherDuck is excited to announce the introduction of the &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function, which simplifies the use of LLMs and SLMs within SQL queries, allowing users to generate and summarize text as well as extract structured data without needing separate infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function currently supports OpenAI's gpt-4o-mini and gpt-4o models, providing flexibility in terms of cost-effectiveness and performance. In its preview release, users can apply gpt-4o-mini-based prompts to all rows in a table, unlocking use cases such as bulk text summarization and structured data extraction. The function allows for single-row and constant inputs with gpt-4o, enabling high-quality responses ideal for retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) scenarios. Users can specify the model for inference using the optional (model:=) parameter, which enhances customization based on specific needs. Additionally, the prompt function supports returning structured output through parameters like &lt;stron g=&quot;&quot;&gt;struct&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; and &lt;strong&gt;struct_descr&lt;/strong&gt;, facilitating integration into analytical workflows.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function is designed for various practical applications. One prominent use case is text summarization; for instance, users can retrieve concise summaries from a text column in a dataset by executing a simple SQL query that applies the prompt function across multiple rows. In testing, processing 100 rows took approximately 2.8 seconds, showcasing significant speed improvements compared to traditional methods that would take hours without concurrency. Another compelling application is converting unstructured data into structured formats. By utilizing the struct and struct_descr parameters, users can extract specific information—such as topics, sentiments, and technologies mentioned in comments—transforming raw text into easily analyzable structured outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performance of the &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function is noteworthy; it allows for concurrent processing of multiple requests to enhance efficiency significantly. For example, when extracting structured information from a dataset like Hacker News, users can achieve high accuracy while maintaining reasonable compute costs. However, it is essential to consider practical limitations; for certain tasks like extracting email addresses from text, traditional SQL methods such as regex may be more efficient and reliable than using LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function is currently available in Preview for MotherDuck users on both Free Trial and Standard Plans. To start exploring this functionality, users are encouraged to consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherduck.com/docs/sql-reference/motherduck-sql-reference/ai-functions/prompt/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; provided by MotherDuck. Notably, while running the &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function over large datasets can incur higher compute costs compared to other analytical queries, MotherDuck has set quotas to manage usage effectively—Free Trial users receive 40 compute unit hours per day while Standard Plan users have similar limits that can be adjusted upon request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the &lt;code&gt;prompt()&lt;/code&gt; function represents a significant advancement in integrating LLMs with SQL databases. By enabling users to harness the power of AI within their existing workflows seamlessly, MotherDuck is paving the way for more efficient data processing and analysis. As developers explore this new functionality, they are invited to share their experiences and feedback through community channels to foster collaboration and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further details on how to utilize the prompt() function and its capabilities, visit MotherDuck's &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherduck.com/&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt; or check &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherduck.com/blog/sql-llm-prompt-function-gpt-models&quot;&gt;official announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/stron&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">MotherDuck has launched the prompt() function, a groundbreaking feature that integrates large language models (LLMs) directly into SQL, allowing users to generate, summarize, and extract structured data efficiently. This new capability democratizes access to advanced natural language processing techniques, making it easier for developers to leverage AI in their data workflows.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PyTorch 2.5 Speeding things up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/PyTorchUpdate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PyTorch 2.5 Speeding things up" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/PyTorchUpdate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/PyTorchUpdate">&lt;p&gt;The release of PyTorch 2.5 introduces significant enhancements, including a new CuDNN backend for SDPA and optimizations in the TorchInductor CPU backend. These updates aim to improve performance and streamline user experience across various machine learning tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Key Features and Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Beta Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CuDNN Backend for SDPA:&lt;/strong&gt; This new backend offers speed improvements by default on NVIDIA H100 GPUs, achieving up to 75% faster performance compared to FlashAttentionV2.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regional Compilation:&lt;/strong&gt; The torch.compile feature allows for regional compilation of repeated nn.Module instances without recompilation, reducing cold startup times while maintaining performance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TorchInductor CPU Backend Optimization:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhancements include CPP backend code generation and support for various data types, delivering consistent performance improvements across multiple benchmark suites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Prototype Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FlexAttention:&lt;/strong&gt; A flexible API for implementing diverse attention mechanisms with improved memory efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compiled Autograd:&lt;/strong&gt; Captures the entire backward pass, allowing for deferred tracing that is resilient to forward pass disruptions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flight Recorder:&lt;/strong&gt; A debugging tool that helps identify issues in stuck jobs by capturing runtime information.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max-autotune Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Profiles multiple implementations at compile time to select the best-performing one for GEMM operations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Intel GPU Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved support for Intel GPUs to accelerate machine learning workflows on both Data Center and Client GPUs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP16 Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Float16 is now supported on CPU paths for both eager mode and TorchInductor, enhancing performance in neural network tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autoload Device Extension:&lt;/strong&gt; Streamlines integration of out-of-tree device extensions by automating loading processes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TorchInductor on Windows:&lt;/strong&gt; The Inductor CPU backend is now compatible with Windows environments, supporting multiple compilers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release comprises 4095 commits from 504 contributors, reflecting the ongoing commitment of the PyTorch community to enhance its capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read full article and explore all new updates provided by this update check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pytorch.org/blog/pytorch2-5/&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt; by PyTorch&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The release of PyTorch 2.5 introduces significant enhancements, including a new CuDNN backend for SDPA and optimizations in the TorchInductor CPU backend. These updates aim to improve performance and streamline user experience across various machine learning tasks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Agent-as-a-Judge:Evaluate Agents with Agents</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agent-as-a-Judge:Evaluate Agents with Agents" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AgentJudge">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Contemporary evaluation techniques are inadequate for agentic systems. These approaches either focus exclusively on final outcomes -- ignoring the step-by-step nature of agentic systems, or require excessive manual labour. To address this, we introduce the Agent-as-a-Judge framework, wherein agentic systems are used to evaluate agentic systems. This is an organic extension of the LLM-as-a-Judge framework, incorporating agentic features that enable intermediate feedback for the entire task-solving process. We apply the Agent-as-a-Judge to the task of code generation. To overcome issues with existing benchmarks and provide a proof-of-concept testbed for Agent-as-a-Judge, we present DevAI, a new benchmark of 55 realistic automated AI development tasks. It includes rich manual annotations, like a total of 365 hierarchical user requirements. We benchmark three of the popular agentic systems using Agent-as-a-Judge and find it dramatically outperforms LLM-as-a-Judge and is as reliable as our human evaluation baseline. Altogether, we believe that Agent-as-a-Judge marks a concrete step forward for modern agentic systems -- by providing rich and reliable reward signals necessary for dynamic and scalable self-improvement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhuge,+M&quot;&gt;Mingchen Zhuge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhao,+C&quot;&gt;Changsheng Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ashley,+D&quot;&gt;Dylan Ashley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+W&quot;&gt;Wenyi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Khizbullin,+D&quot;&gt;Dmitrii Khizbullin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xiong,+Y&quot;&gt;Yunyang Xiong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+Z&quot;&gt;Zechun Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chang,+E&quot;&gt;Ernie Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Krishnamoorthi,+R&quot;&gt;Raghuraman Krishnamoorthi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tian,+Y&quot;&gt;Yuandong Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shi,+Y&quot;&gt;Yangyang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chandra,+V&quot;&gt;Vikas Chandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Schmidhuber,+J&quot;&gt;Jürgen Schmidhuber&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10934&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zamba2-7B:Setting New Standards for Small Language Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Zamba" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zamba2-7B:Setting New Standards for Small Language Models" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Zamba</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Zamba">&lt;p&gt;Zyphra has introduced Zamba2-7B, a state-of-the-art small language model that outperforms leading competitors in both quality and performance. Designed for on-device and consumer GPU applications, Zamba2-7B offers exceptional efficiency and capabilities for natural language tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of natural language processing (NLP) has led to the development of increasingly sophisticated models. Zyphra's latest offering, Zamba2-7B, is a small language model that stands out in a crowded field by delivering superior performance while maintaining a compact size. This model is particularly suited for applications requiring efficient processing on consumer-grade hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zamba2-7B excels in standard language modeling evaluation sets, demonstrating remarkable latency and generation speed. Among small language models with fewer than 9 billion parameters, Zamba2-7B leads the pack in both quality and performance metrics. Its design allows it to outperform notable models from Mistral, Google’s Gemma, and Meta’s Llama3 series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/669abfd62b0d2313e8024f30/670b31c473f57e3c96e35298_ttft_mmlu-p-800.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The key features that you will come across while using it and reasons why you should try this model out are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exceptional Pretraining Quality:&lt;/strong&gt; The model benefits from high-quality pretraining and annealing datasets, which significantly enhance its performance on a per-training-token basis.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizing an advanced hybrid SSM-attention architecture, Zamba2-7B features Mamba layers interleaved with shared attention layers to optimize parameter efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LoRA Projection Matrices:&lt;/strong&gt; These matrices allow for increased expressivity within each block while keeping additional parameter overhead minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core architecture of Zamba2-7B builds upon the original Zamba model but introduces enhancements that improve its functionality. The backbone consists of Mamba layers interspersed with shared attention layers—two in Zamba2 compared to one in its predecessor. This innovative design minimizes the parameter cost while maximizing performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A notable feature of the architecture is the concatenation of original model embeddings with the attention block. This approach helps maintain information across depth, resulting in better overall performance during generation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zamba2-7B was trained on 128 H100 GPUs over approximately 50 days using Zyphra's internal training framework built atop Megatron-LM. This extensive training process demonstrates that even at the 7 billion parameter scale, significant advancements can be achieved with a small team and moderate budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model achieves state-of-the-art inference efficiency across various metrics, including latency, throughput, and memory usage. These efficiencies make it an attractive option for enterprises looking to deploy powerful AI solutions without extensive computational resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zyphra is committed to democratizing access to advanced AI systems by releasing Zamba2-7B under an open-source license. This decision allows researchers, developers, and companies to leverage its capabilities freely. The broader AI community is invited to explore Zamba's unique architecture and contribute to ongoing advancements in efficient foundation models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Hugging Face integration is available for easy access to &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/Zyphra/Zamba2-7B&quot;&gt;Zamba2-7B&lt;/a&gt;, alongside a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zyphra/Zamba2&quot;&gt;pure-PyTorch&lt;/a&gt; implementation that facilitates further customization and experimentation by developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zyphra's team aims to continue pushing the boundaries of what small language models can achieve. By exploring novel architectures and enhancing their understanding of powerful models, they are dedicated to advancing the field of AI research and application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of Zamba2-7B marks a significant milestone in the development of small language models. With its exceptional performance metrics and efficient architecture, it sets a new standard for what can be achieved in natural language processing on consumer hardware. As Zyphra opens up this technology to the community, the potential for innovation in AI applications continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Zamba2-7B and its capabilities, visit Zyphra's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zyphra.com&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;, or the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zyphra.com/post/zamba2-7b&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; presenting the afforementioned results.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Zyphra has introduced Zamba2-7B, a state-of-the-art small language model that outperforms leading competitors in both quality and performance. Designed for on-device and consumer GPU applications, Zamba2-7B offers exceptional efficiency and capabilities for natural language tasks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adobe Launches Firefly Video Model</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AdobeFirefly" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adobe Launches Firefly Video Model" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AdobeFirefly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AdobeFirefly">&lt;p&gt;Adobe has unveiled the Firefly Video Model, expanding its suite of generative AI tools to include video capabilities designed for commercial safety. With enhanced features for video editing and integration into popular Adobe applications, this model aims to revolutionize content creation for professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/puEgugluadk?si=P4KsYVEHdZMkaaMC&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 14, 2024, during Adobe MAX, the world’s largest creativity conference, Adobe announced the launch of the Firefly Video Model (beta). This model marks a significant expansion of Adobe's Firefly family of generative AI models, which has already gained traction in image generation since its initial release. With over 13 billion images generated since March 2023, the Firefly suite is rapidly becoming a go-to resource for creative professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Firefly Video Model is the first publicly available video model explicitly designed to be safe for commercial use. This innovative tool allows creators to generate and edit video content efficiently while ensuring compliance with licensing and copyright considerations. As part of its beta launch, Adobe is gathering feedback from a select group of creative professionals to refine the model further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Firefly Video Model includes several standout features that enhance its functionality. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2024/10/14/generative-extend-in-premiere-pro&quot;&gt;Generative Extend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; feature allows users to seamlessly extend video clips, filling gaps in footage and smoothing transitions within Adobe Premiere Pro. Additionally, users can generate videos directly from text prompts with controls for camera angles and motion through the &lt;strong&gt;Text to Video&lt;/strong&gt; feature. The &lt;strong&gt;Image to Video&lt;/strong&gt; capability enables creators to transform still images or illustrations into dynamic video clips, adding a new dimension to their visual storytelling. Furthermore, the latest Firefly Image 3 model offers image generation that is up to four times faster than previous iterations, while the &lt;strong&gt;Generative Workspace in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2024/10/14/photoshop-delivers-powerful-innovation-for-image-editing-ideation-3d-design-more&quot;&gt;Photoshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; fosters creativity and collaboration by enabling designers to brainstorm and iterate concepts quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Firefly Video Model integrates seamlessly with various Adobe applications including Photoshop, Illustrator, and Premiere Pro. This integration enhances workflows by allowing users to leverage generative AI capabilities across different platforms. For instance, the Generative Shape Fill and Text to Pattern features in Illustrator empower designers to create unique artwork rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adobe also introduced new offerings aimed at enterprises through Firefly Services. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2024/10/14/oliver-supercharges-its-ai-content-creation-with-help-from-adobe-firefly-services&quot;&gt;Dubbing and Lip Sync&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; This feature uses generative AI to translate spoken dialogue into multiple languages while maintaining the original voice's sound and lip movements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bulk Create:&lt;/strong&gt; Aimed at enhancing efficiency, this tool allows creative professionals to edit large volumes of images quickly, streamlining tasks such as resizing and background removal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading brands like PepsiCo/Gatorade, IBM, Mattel, and Deloitte have already utilized Adobe Firefly to optimize their workflows and scale content creation. By automating repetitive tasks, these companies can focus more on exploring their creative visions rather than getting bogged down by technical details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adobe emphasizes responsible innovation through its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/ai/overview/ethics.html&quot;&gt;AI Ethics principles—accountability&lt;/a&gt;, responsibility, and transparency. The company has trained its Firefly models on licensed content from Adobe Stock and public domain sources. Furthermore, Adobe promotes Content Credentials as a standard for transparency in digital content creation, allowing users to understand how content was generated or modified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Firefly Video Model is currently available in a limited public beta at firefly.adobe.com (there is a waiting list &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/products/firefly/features/ai-video-generator.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). During this phase, generations are free of charge. Adobe plans to provide additional information regarding pricing and offers once the model moves beyond beta testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of the Firefly Video Model represents a significant leap forward in generative AI tools for creative professionals. By integrating advanced video capabilities into its existing suite of applications, Adobe is empowering users to create high-quality content more efficiently than ever before. As feedback from the beta phase rolls in, Adobe aims to refine these tools further, solidifying its position as a leader in creative technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Firefly Video Model and other innovations from &amp;lt;a href=https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.adobe.com&amp;amp;esheet=53380676&amp;amp;newsitemid=20230413005364&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=www.adobe.com&amp;amp;index=10&amp;amp;md5=415c333dd2658050a4e133a58c1983ec'&amp;gt;Adobe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, visit their &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.adobe.com/news/2024/10/101424-adobe-launches-firefly-video-model&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Adobe has unveiled the Firefly Video Model, expanding its suite of generative AI tools to include video capabilities designed for commercial safety. With enhanced features for video editing and integration into popular Adobe applications, this model aims to revolutionize content creation for professionals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thinking LLMs:General Instruction Following with Thought Generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thinking LLMs:General Instruction Following with Thought Generation" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ThinkingLLM">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; LLMs are typically trained to answer user questions or follow instructions similarly to how human experts respond. However, in the standard alignment framework they lack the basic ability of explicit thinking before answering. Thinking is important for complex questions that require reasoning and planning -- but can be applied to any task. We propose a training method for equipping existing LLMs with such thinking abilities for general instruction following without use of additional human data. We achieve this by an iterative search and optimization procedure that explores the space of possible thought generations, allowing the model to learn how to think without direct supervision. For each instruction, the thought candidates are scored using a judge model to evaluate their responses only, and then optimized via preference optimization. We show that this procedure leads to superior performance on AlpacaEval and Arena-Hard, and shows gains from thinking on non-reasoning categories such as marketing, health and general knowledge, in addition to more traditional reasoning &amp;amp; problem-solving tasks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wu,+T&quot;&gt;Tianhao Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lan,+J&quot;&gt;Janice Lan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yuan,+W&quot;&gt;Weizhe Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jiao,+J&quot;&gt;Jiantao Jiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Weston,+J&quot;&gt;Jason Weston&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sukhbaatar,+S&quot;&gt;Sainbayar Sukhbaatar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.10630&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scaling Laws For Diffusion Transformers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scaling Laws For Diffusion Transformers" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ScalingLaws">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Diffusion transformers (DiT) have already achieved appealing synthesis and scaling properties in content recreation, e.g., image and video generation. However, scaling laws of DiT are less explored, which usually offer precise predictions regarding optimal model size and data requirements given a specific compute budget. Therefore, experiments across a broad range of compute budgets, from 1e17 to 6e18 FLOPs are conducted to confirm the existence of scaling laws in DiT for the first time. Concretely, the loss of pretraining DiT also follows a power-law relationship with the involved compute. Based on the scaling law, we can not only determine the optimal model size and required data but also accurately predict the text-to-image generation loss given a model with 1B parameters and a compute budget of 1e21 FLOPs. Additionally, we also demonstrate that the trend of pre-training loss matches the generation performances (e.g., FID), even across various datasets, which complements the mapping from compute to synthesis quality and thus provides a predictable benchmark that assesses model performance and data quality at a reduced cost. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liang,+Z&quot;&gt;Zhengyang Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+H&quot;&gt;Hao He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+C&quot;&gt;Ceyuan Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Dai,+B&quot;&gt;Bo Dai&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.08184&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing ARIA:The First Open Multimodal Native MoE Model</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Aria" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing ARIA:The First Open Multimodal Native MoE Model" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Aria</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Aria">&lt;p&gt;Rhymes.ai has launched ARIA, the first open multimodal native mixture of experts (MoE) model, designed to enhance AI capabilities across various applications. With its innovative architecture and advanced features, ARIA aims to set a new standard in the realm of multimodal AI, enabling more efficient processing of diverse data types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhymes.ai/images/blog/Aria-intro-10062024/aria-is-onellm.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field of artificial intelligence is rapidly evolving, with new models emerging to tackle complex tasks involving multiple data modalities. Rhymes.ai has taken a significant step forward with the introduction of ARIA, the first open multimodal native mixture of experts (MoE) model. This groundbreaking model is engineered to process and integrate various types of data—such as text, images, and audio—allowing for more sophisticated AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multimodal models are essential for understanding and generating content that reflects the complexity of real-world information. By combining different forms of data, these models can provide richer insights and more accurate outputs. ARIA's architecture leverages the strengths of MoE technology to optimize resource allocation, enabling it to handle diverse tasks efficiently while maintaining high performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARIA boasts several innovative features that enhance its functionality and usability. It utilizes a mixture of experts architecture that allows for dynamic routing of inputs to specialized sub-models, optimizing computational resources based on task requirements. This design not only improves efficiency but also enhances the model's ability to learn from various data types. Additionally, ARIA supports seamless integration with existing frameworks, making it easier for developers to incorporate its capabilities into their applications. The model is open-source, promoting collaboration and innovation within the AI community while ensuring transparency in its development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The versatility of ARIA opens up numerous possibilities for its application across different domains. In healthcare, it can analyze patient records alongside medical images to provide comprehensive insights for diagnosis and treatment planning. In creative industries, ARIA can assist in generating multimedia content by integrating text descriptions with visual elements, enhancing storytelling capabilities. Furthermore, its ability to process audio data allows for advancements in speech recognition and natural language understanding, making it a valuable tool for developers working on voice-activated applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial tests have shown that ARIA outperforms many existing models in various benchmarks related to multimodal tasks. Its unique architecture allows it to achieve higher accuracy rates while reducing latency during processing. This performance boost is particularly beneficial in real-time applications where quick responses are crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rhymes.ai/images/blog/Aria-intro-10062024/barChart.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As AI continues to evolve, the demand for models that can seamlessly integrate multiple data types will only increase. ARIA represents a significant advancement in this area, providing a robust framework for future developments in multimodal AI. Rhymes.ai is committed to refining ARIA further based on user feedback and ongoing research, ensuring that it remains at the forefront of technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of ARIA marks a pivotal moment in the development of multimodal AI models. By combining advanced features with an open-source approach, Rhymes.ai is paving the way for more efficient and effective AI solutions across various industries. As developers and researchers explore the capabilities of ARIA, the potential for groundbreaking applications in fields such as healthcare, creative arts, and beyond becomes increasingly apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about ARIA and its features, visit Rhymes.ai's official &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhymes.ai/blog-details/aria-first-open-multimodal-native-moe-model&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; where you can real case scenarios including prompts and results.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Rhymes.ai has launched ARIA, the first open multimodal native mixture of experts (MoE) model, designed to enhance AI capabilities across various applications. With its innovative architecture and advanced features, ARIA aims to set a new standard in the realm of multimodal AI, enabling more efficient processing of diverse data types.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pixtral 12B</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Pixtral" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pixtral 12B" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Pixtral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Pixtral">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We introduce Pixtral-12B, a 12--billion-parameter multimodal language model. Pixtral-12B is trained to understand both natural images and documents, achieving leading performance on various multimodal benchmarks, surpassing a number of larger models. Unlike many open-source models, Pixtral is also a cutting-edge text model for its size, and does not compromise on natural language performance to excel in multimodal tasks. Pixtral uses a new vision encoder trained from scratch, which allows it to ingest images at their natural resolution and aspect ratio. This gives users flexibility on the number of tokens used to process an image. Pixtral is also able to process any number of images in its long context window of 128K tokens. Pixtral 12B substanially outperforms other open models of similar sizes (Llama-3.2 11B \&amp;amp; Qwen-2-VL 7B). It also outperforms much larger open models like Llama-3.2 90B while being 7x smaller. We further contribute an open-source benchmark, MM-MT-Bench, for evaluating vision-language models in practical scenarios, and provide detailed analysis and code for standardized evaluation protocols for multimodal LLMs. Pixtral-12B is released under Apache 2.0 license. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Agrawal,+P&quot;&gt;Pravesh Agrawal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Antoniak,+S&quot;&gt;Szymon Antoniak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hanna,+E+B&quot;&gt;Emma Bou Hanna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Bout,+B&quot;&gt;Baptiste Bout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chaplot,+D&quot;&gt;Devendra Chaplot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chudnovsky,+J&quot;&gt;Jessica Chudnovsky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Costa,+D&quot;&gt;Diogo Costa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=De+Monicault,+B&quot;&gt;Baudouin De Monicault&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Garg,+S&quot;&gt;Saurabh Garg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Gervet,+T&quot;&gt;Theophile Gervet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ghosh,+S&quot;&gt;Soham Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=H%C3%A9liou,+A&quot;&gt;Amélie Héliou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jacob,+P&quot;&gt;Paul Jacob&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jiang,+A+Q&quot;&gt;Albert Q. Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Khandelwal,+K&quot;&gt;Kartik Khandelwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lacroix,+T&quot;&gt;Timothée Lacroix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lample,+G&quot;&gt;Guillaume Lample&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Casas,+D+L&quot;&gt;Diego Las Casas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lavril,+T&quot;&gt;Thibaut Lavril&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Scao,+T+L&quot;&gt;Teven Le Scao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lo,+A&quot;&gt;Andy Lo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Marshall,+W&quot;&gt;William Marshall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Martin,+L&quot;&gt;Louis Martin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Mensch,+A&quot;&gt;Arthur Mensch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Muddireddy,+P&quot;&gt;Pavankumar Muddireddy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Nemychnikova,+V&quot;&gt;Valera Nemychnikova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Pellat,+M&quot;&gt;Marie Pellat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Von+Platen,+P&quot;&gt;Patrick Von Platen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Raghuraman,+N&quot;&gt;Nikhil Raghuraman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Rozi%C3%A8re,+B&quot;&gt;Baptiste Rozière&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sablayrolles,+A&quot;&gt;Alexandre Sablayrolles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Saulnier,+L&quot;&gt;Lucile Saulnier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sauvestre,+R&quot;&gt;Romain Sauvestre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shang,+W&quot;&gt;Wendy Shang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Soletskyi,+R&quot;&gt;Roman Soletskyi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Stewart,+L&quot;&gt;Lawrence Stewart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Stock,+P&quot;&gt;Pierre Stock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Studnia,+J&quot;&gt;Joachim Studnia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Subramanian,+S&quot;&gt;Sandeep Subramanian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Vaze,+S&quot;&gt;Sagar Vaze&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+T&quot;&gt;Thomas Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+S&quot;&gt;Sophia Yang&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07073&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry></feed>