<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-01T12:10:38+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kavour</title><subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Updated production-ready Gemini models, reduced 1.5 Pro pricing, increased rate limits, and more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Xeon6NGaudi3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updated production-ready Gemini models, reduced 1.5 Pro pricing, increased rate limits, and more" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Xeon6NGaudi3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Xeon6NGaudi3">&lt;p&gt; Intel has announced the release of its new Xeon 6 with Performance-cores (P-cores) and Gaudi 3 AI accelerators, offering double the performance for AI and HPC workloads. These innovations deliver significant improvements in performance per watt, with optimized total cost of ownership (TCO), enabling businesses to scale AI infrastructure efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Intel Expands AI Capabilities with Xeon 6 and Gaudi 3 AI Accelerators&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; In response to the growing demand for scalable and efficient AI infrastructure, Intel has introduced two powerful new products: Xeon 6 with Performance-cores (P-cores) and Gaudi 3 AI accelerators. These advancements underscore Intel's focus on delivering high-performance AI systems with reduced TCO, enabling enterprises to meet AI and high-performance computing (HPC) workloads with enhanced efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Intel's Xeon 6 processor is engineered for compute-intensive tasks, offering twice the performance of its predecessor and integrating AI acceleration capabilities in every core. Alongside this, the Gaudi 3 AI accelerator is optimized for large-scale generative AI, providing advanced networking capabilities and seamless integration with AI frameworks like PyTorch and Hugging Face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Key Features of Intel Xeon 6 and Gaudi 3 AI Accelerators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Intel® Xeon® 6 with P-cores&lt;/strong&gt;: Xeon 6 delivers substantial improvements in AI processing, including an increased core count and double the memory bandwidth, making it suitable for workloads ranging from edge devices to cloud environments. Its embedded AI acceleration in each core ensures high efficiency, doubling performance over its predecessor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Intel® Gaudi® 3 AI Accelerator&lt;/strong&gt;: Gaudi 3 is designed to handle the intensive demands of generative AI, featuring 64 Tensor processor cores (TPCs) and eight matrix multiplication engines (MMEs). With 128 GB of HBM2e memory and advanced networking features, Gaudi 3 accelerates deep learning processes, offering up to 20% more throughput and twice the price-performance compared to competing solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Optimized AI Systems and Cost Efficiency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Intel’s latest innovations offer enterprises an optimized AI infrastructure with significant cost savings and performance benefits. The company has partnered with major OEMs such as Dell Technologies and Supermicro to co-engineer systems specifically tailored for AI deployments. Notably, Intel’s robust x86 architecture, used in 73% of GPU-accelerated servers, ensures flexibility and compatibility across AI workloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; By enhancing AI infrastructure with TCO advantages and boosting performance per watt, Intel is helping businesses efficiently scale their AI capabilities from prototype to production environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Accelerating Enterprise AI Adoption with Co-Engineering and New Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Intel's collaboration with partners enables seamless integration of generative AI solutions into production-ready systems. Through co-engineering efforts, Intel is addressing the challenges of real-time monitoring, error handling, and security, ensuring smoother transitions for enterprises deploying AI at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opea.dev/&quot;&gt;Open Platform Enterprise AI (OPEA)&lt;/a&gt; platform integrates microservices optimized for Xeon 6 and Gaudi 3 systems. This platform allows for efficient deployment and scalability of retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) solutions, ensuring businesses can rapidly adopt cutting-edge AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Expanding Enterprise Access with Intel Tiber Portfolio and Developer Cloud&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Intel's commitment to expanding access to AI technology is evident in its Tiber portfolio, which addresses the challenges enterprises face in deploying AI across cloud, edge, and data center environments. The Intel Tiber Developer Cloud provides early access to Xeon 6 and Gaudi 3 for testing and tech evaluation, with production-ready Gaudi 3 clusters rolling out next quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Moreover, new service offerings such as SeekrFlow, an AI platform from Seekr, offer businesses an end-to-end solution for developing trusted AI applications. The platform is powered by Intel’s AI tools, including the latest Gaudi 3 software, enabling developers to create high-performance AI models with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Intel’s release of Xeon 6 with P-cores and Gaudi 3 AI accelerators marks a significant step forward in the evolution of AI infrastructure. These new products offer unparalleled performance for AI and HPC workloads while optimizing cost efficiency, making them essential tools for enterprises looking to scale AI capabilities. Through its partnerships, co-engineering efforts, and expanded access to AI technologies, Intel continues to lead the way in transforming AI systems for the future. Read full articl from Intel's blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/next-generation-ai-solutions-xeon-6-gaudi-3.html#gs.f3jjfe&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Intel has announced the release of its new Xeon 6 with Performance-cores (P-cores) and Gaudi 3 AI accelerators, offering double the performance for AI and HPC workloads. These innovations deliver significant improvements in performance per watt, with optimized total cost of ownership (TCO), enabling businesses to scale AI infrastructure efficiently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Updated production-ready Gemini models, reduced 1.5 Pro pricing, increased rate limits, and more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GeminiModelsUpdate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updated production-ready Gemini models, reduced 1.5 Pro pricing, increased rate limits, and more" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GeminiModelsUpdate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GeminiModelsUpdate">&lt;p&gt;Google has released two updated AI models, Gemini-1.5-Pro-002 and Gemini-1.5-Flash-002, featuring enhanced performance, faster outputs, and significantly reduced costs. These models improve upon the Gemini 1.5 series with a focus on text, code, and multimodal tasks, making them highly versatile and accessible for developers through &lt;a href=&quot;https://aistudio.google.com/app/prompts/new_chat?model=gemini-1.5-pro-002&quot;&gt;Google AI Studio&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/models/gemini&quot;&gt;Gemini API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has introduced two powerful updates to its Gemini 1.5 model series: the Gemini-1.5-Pro-002 and Gemini-1.5-Flash-002. These models bring significant improvements in speed, efficiency, and cost, continuing the momentum from previous releases. With a focus on providing developers with faster outputs, reduced latency, and more affordable pricing, these models are ideal for a wide range of use cases, from long-context text synthesis to advanced multimodal applications. Both models are accessible via Google AI Studio and the Gemini API, making them easier to integrate for developers and larger organizations using Google Cloud and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai&quot;&gt;Vertex AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gemini 1.5 models are designed to perform exceptionally well across various text, code, and multimodal tasks. These capabilities allow them to handle complex tasks like processing &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/document-processing&quot;&gt;1,000-page PDFs&lt;/a&gt;, answering questions about large code repositories, and analyzing hour-long videos. The latest updates to Gemini 1.5 Pro and Flash build on these strengths, with significant improvements in performance metrics and model efficiency. For example, both models have seen a ~20% boost in math benchmarks and 7% better results in the MMLU-Pro benchmark, positioning them as top performers in their class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the models more developer-friendly, Google has reduced the default output length by 5-20%, ensuring concise responses without sacrificing accuracy. Additionally, the models now offer faster output generation and drastically lower latency, allowing developers to work more efficiently and at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Some of the key features we can clearly see reading though the official post are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Massive Cost Reduction: Gemini 1.5 Pro now offers a 64% price reduction for input tokens and a 52% reduction for output tokens for prompts under 128K tokens, driving down the cost of development.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-developer-goog-blog-assets/images/Gemini_Pro_Price_Chart_GRHV7Tk.original.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Increased Rate Limits: Paid tier rate limits are doubled for 1.5 Flash (up to 2,000 RPM) and tripled for 1.5 Pro (up to 1,000 RPM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Speed and Latency Improvements: Both models are now 2x faster and feature 3x less latency, allowing for quicker and more efficient processing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-developer-goog-blog-assets/images/image3_HthRi7g.original.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Multimodal Capabilities: Enhanced support for complex tasks like video understanding, large-scale document synthesis, and code generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Developer-Controlled Filters: Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/safety-settings&quot;&gt;safety filters&lt;/a&gt; allow developers to configure the models to best suit their needs, with filters no longer applied by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release of the Gemini-1.5-Pro-002 and Gemini-1.5-Flash-002 models underscores Google’s commitment to making AI development more efficient, affordable, and versatile. With substantial improvements in speed, accuracy, and cost-efficiency, these models are a powerful tool for developers working on text, code, and multimodal projects. The reduction in costs, coupled with increased rate limits and faster output, ensures that Gemini 1.5 models can cater to diverse needs in AI development, from startups to large-scale enterprises. As Google continues to refine these models, the future of AI-driven innovation looks brighter than ever. To read full article, in the Google for Developers blog, go &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.googleblog.com/en/updated-gemini-models-reduced-15-pro-pricing-increased-rate-limits-and-more/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Google has released two updated AI models, Gemini-1.5-Pro-002 and Gemini-1.5-Flash-002, featuring enhanced performance, faster outputs, and significantly reduced costs. These models improve upon the Gemini 1.5 series with a focus on text, code, and multimodal tasks, making them highly versatile and accessible for developers through Google AI Studio and the Gemini API.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NVIDIA Unveils Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Nemotron51B" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NVIDIA Unveils Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B" /><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Nemotron51B</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Nemotron51B">&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA has introduced the Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B language model, derived from Meta’s Llama-3.1-70B, showcasing superior accuracy and efficiency. This model leverages Neural Architecture Search (NAS) to balance performance with cost, making it accessible for diverse applications on a single NVIDIA H100 GPU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA's release of the Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B marks a significant milestone in language model technology, blending cutting-edge efficiency with accuracy. This model, derived from Meta’s Llama-3.1-70B, is tailored using a novel Neural Architecture Search (NAS) approach that prioritizes workload efficiency and cost optimization. By fitting seamlessly on a single NVIDIA H100 GPU, it brings down the cost of running advanced AI models, opening new opportunities for both enterprises and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://build.nvidia.com/nvidia/llama-3_1-nemotron-51b-instruct&quot;&gt;Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B-Instruct&lt;/a&gt;, developed using NAS and knowledge distillation techniques, delivers a groundbreaking balance between accuracy and cost-efficiency. While maintaining nearly the same accuracy as its reference model, Llama-3.1-70B, the Nemotron version achieves 2.2x faster inference. The model reduces the memory footprint and enables running 4x larger workloads on a single GPU, significantly enhancing throughput and reducing costs. Optimized for use in cloud, data centers, and edge devices, the model offers flexibility for various deployment scenarios, including Kubernetes and NIM blueprints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; On the positive side of things we can say that Nemotron-51B is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2.2x faster inference compared to Llama-3.1-70B&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MT Bench&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MMLU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text generation (128/1024)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summarization/ RAG (2048/128)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Llama-3.1- Nemotron-51B- Instruct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.99&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;80.2%&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;6472&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;653&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Llama 3.1-70B- Instruct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.93&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;81.66%&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2975&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;339&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Llama 3.1-70B- Instruct (single GPU)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1274&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;301&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Llama 3-70B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.94&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;80.17%&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2975&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;339&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;li&gt; reduced memory footprint and FLOPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; can run larger workloads on a single GPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; superior cost-efficiency (accuracy per dollar)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer-blogs.nvidia.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Accuracy-vs.-Throughput-performance-of-Llama-3.1-Nemotron-51B.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;li&gt; simplified deployment through NVIDIA NIM microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; On the other hanb we can clearly see that there is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a slight accuracy tradeoff in favor of cost and efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the key features presented are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Neural Architecture Search (NAS): NAS allows the model to efficiently utilize a zoo of non-standard transformer blocks, optimizing for specific hardware constraints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Optimized for NVIDIA H100: The model fits on a single H100 GPU, making it accessible for high-demand workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Reduced Memory and FLOPs: The unique architecture reduces memory usage while maintaining competitive accuracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; High Throughput: The model supports larger batch sizes and delivers tokens per second efficiently, making it ideal for real-time applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; NIM Integration: Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B is packaged as a microservice through NVIDIA NIM, simplifying the deployment process for developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B sets a new benchmark in the balance between efficiency and accuracy. By leveraging advanced Neural Architecture Search (NAS), NVIDIA has created a model that breaks the efficient frontier, delivering unparalleled performance at reduced costs. This model represents a significant leap forward for developers looking to deploy powerful AI models in real-world scenarios, offering an ideal tradeoff between performance and affordability. If interested and want to find out more, you can go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/advancing-the-accuracy-efficiency-frontier-with-llama-3-1-nemotron-51b/&quot;&gt; official blog post&lt;/a&gt; of NVIDIA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">NVIDIA has introduced the Llama 3.1-Nemotron-51B language model, derived from Meta’s Llama-3.1-70B, showcasing superior accuracy and efficiency. This model leverages Neural Architecture Search (NAS) to balance performance with cost, making it accessible for diverse applications on a single NVIDIA H100 GPU.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IBM and NASA Unveil Open-Source AI Model for Weather and Climate Innovation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IBMnNasa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IBM and NASA Unveil Open-Source AI Model for Weather and Climate Innovation" /><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IBMnNasa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IBMnNasa">&lt;p&gt;IBM and NASA have introduced a groundbreaking AI foundation model designed to address weather and climate challenges. The open-source model promises a more flexible and scalable approach, providing advanced solutions for short-term weather forecasting and long-term climate projections, available for download on Hugging Face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;IBM and NASA Launch a New AI Model for Weather and Climate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a significant step for meteorology and climate science, IBM and NASA have collaborated to develop a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/topics/artificial-intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt; foundation model tailored for a wide range of weather and climate use cases. With contributions from Oak Ridge National Laboratory, this model, dubbed &amp;lt;a href=https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.13598'&amp;gt;Prithvi WxC&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, stands out for its versatility and scalability, offering an advanced tool for tackling weather forecasts and climate predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional models, Prithvi WxC can be fine-tuned to suit different scales—global, regional, or local—making it adaptable for various scientific and industry applications. Whether it’s creating localized weather forecasts or refining long-term climate simulations, this AI model represents a leap forward in environmental analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Groundbreaking Applications: From Severe Weather to Climate Projections&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather and climate foundation model offers more than just incremental improvements—it opens new possibilities for tackling complex environmental problems. The model's flexible architecture enables it to be used for multiple applications, including creating targeted forecasts from local data and improving the resolution of global climate simulations. In one notable experiment, the model reconstructed global surface temperatures using only 5% of the original data, highlighting its potential for data assimilation and forecasting in data-sparse environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two specialized fine-tuned versions of the model are available for specific use cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Climate and Weather Data Downscaling: This version enhances spatial resolution by up to 12x, making it ideal for generating high-resolution climate projections from low-resolution inputs such as temperature, precipitation, and wind data. This version is now available on the IBM Granite Hugging Face page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Gravity Wave Parameterization: Gravity waves, which influence atmospheric processes like cloud formation and turbulence, have long posed challenges for accurate modeling. The AI model’s ability to better estimate these waves could significantly improve numerical weather and climate models. This fine-tuned version is part of the NASA-IBM Prithvi models on Hugging Face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Collaborative Innovation and the Path Forward: The model builds on years of collaboration between IBM, NASA, and Oak Ridge National Laboratory, with each partner contributing their expertise to enhance AI's role in climate science. Pre-trained on 40 years of Earth observation data from NASA’s MERRA-2 dataset, the model's ability to operate on various scales makes it unique in the field.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to IBM’s Juan Bernabe-Moreno, the model’s flexibility sets it apart from other large AI models, which often focus on specific datasets or singular applications like forecasting. The new weather and climate foundation model, however, is designed to accommodate multiple inputs and outputs, allowing it to run on both global and local contexts. This opens new doors for studying phenomena like hurricanes, atmospheric rivers, and long-term climate risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Open Access and Future Impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the model open-source on Hugging Face is a pivotal step (you can access it through the &amp;lt;a href=https://huggingface.co/Prithvi-WxC'&amp;gt;NASA-IBM Hugging Face&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; page and the downscaling mode can be accessed thgouth the &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/ibm-granite&quot;&gt;IBM Granite Hugging Face&lt;/a&gt; page ), democratizing access to cutting-edge climate AI tools. Two versions—the downscaling and gravity wave parameterization models—are now accessible to researchers, developers, and businesses alike. This move follows IBM and NASA’s prior success with the Prithvi geospatial foundation model, which has been used to study disaster patterns, biodiversity, and land-use changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already, IBM is collaborating with Environment and Climate Change Canada (ECCC) to test the model’s capacity for short-term precipitation forecasting and other advanced use cases. This type of real-time application shows the model’s potential to transform not just climate research but also the way industries, governments, and communities respond to weather events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;IBM’s Broader Vision for AI and Climate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IBM's long-standing commitment to AI and climate solutions is evident in its continued partnerships and innovations. This model is part of a broader effort to use AI to address some of the world’s most pressing environmental challenges. As Arjun Shankar of Oak Ridge National Laboratory notes, this collaboration is key to supporting breakthroughs in computational science, a critical component in improving the accuracy of climate models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With rapid climate change altering weather patterns globally, models like Prithvi WxC are poised to play an increasingly vital role in both understanding and mitigating the impacts of climate change. By making advanced AI tools available to the scientific and business communities, IBM and NASA are empowering more stakeholders to engage with climate science and make informed decisions in the face of future risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, IBM and NASA's release of the Prithvi WxC weather and climate foundation model marks a major milestone in the integration of AI with environmental science. Its open-source availability promises to accelerate innovation across industries and research fields, making advanced weather forecasting and climate modeling more accessible than ever before. With this new tool in the hands of developers and scientists, the future of climate research is looking smarter, faster, and more scalable. If are as excited as I am and want to find out more about it check out full article &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.ibm.com/2024-09-23-ibm-and-nasa-release-open-source-ai-model-on-hugging-face-for-weather-and-climate-applications&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">IBM and NASA have introduced a groundbreaking AI foundation model designed to address weather and climate challenges. The open-source model promises a more flexible and scalable approach, providing advanced solutions for short-term weather forecasting and long-term climate projections, available for download on Hugging Face.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rereading Improves Reasoning in Large Language Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rereading" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rereading Improves Reasoning in Large Language Models" /><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rereading</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rereading">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; To enhance the reasoning capabilities of off-the-shelf Large Language Models (LLMs), we introduce a simple, yet general and effective prompting method, Re2, i.e., &lt;strong&gt;Re&lt;/strong&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;Re&lt;/strong&gt;ading the question as input. Unlike most thought-eliciting prompting methods, such as Chain-of-Thought (CoT), which aim to elicit the reasoning process in the output, Re2 shifts the focus to the input by processing questions twice, thereby enhancing the understanding process. Consequently, Re2 demonstrates strong generality and compatibility with most thought-eliciting prompting methods, including CoT. Crucially, Re2 facilitates a &quot;bidirectional&quot; encoding in unidirectional decoder-only LLMs because the first pass could provide global information for the second pass. We begin with a preliminary empirical study as the foundation of Re2, illustrating its potential to enable &quot;bidirectional&quot; attention mechanisms. We then evaluate Re2 on extensive reasoning benchmarks across 14 datasets, spanning 112 experiments, to validate its effectiveness and generality. Our findings indicate that, with the exception of a few scenarios on vanilla ChatGPT, Re2 consistently enhances the reasoning performance of LLMs through a simple re-reading strategy. Further analyses reveal Re2's adaptability, showing how it can be effectively integrated with different LLMs, thought-eliciting prompting, and ensemble strategies. Our code is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tebmer/Rereading-LLM-Reasoning/&quot;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+X&quot;&gt;Xiaohan Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tao,+C&quot;&gt;Chongyang Tao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shen,+T&quot;&gt;Tao Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+C&quot;&gt;Can Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+H&quot;&gt;Hongbo Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Long,+G&quot;&gt;Guodong Long&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lou,+J&quot;&gt;Jian-guang Lou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ma,+S&quot;&gt;Shuai Ma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.06275&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LLMs Still Can’t Plan; Can LRMs? A Preliminary Evaluation of OpenAI’s o1 on PlanBench</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/EvaluationOpenAIo1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LLMs Still Can’t Plan; Can LRMs? A Preliminary Evaluation of OpenAI’s o1 on PlanBench" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/EvaluationOpenAIo1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/EvaluationOpenAIo1">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The ability to plan a course of action that achieves a desired state of affairs has long been considered a core competence of intelligent agents and has been an integral part of AI research since its inception. With the advent of large language models (LLMs), there has been considerable interest in the question of whether or not they possess such planning abilities. PlanBench, an extensible benchmark we developed in 2022, soon after the release of GPT3, has remained an important tool for evaluating the planning abilities of LLMs. Despite the slew of new private and open source LLMs since GPT3, progress on this benchmark has been surprisingly slow. OpenAI claims that their recent o1 (Strawberry) model has been specifically constructed and trained to escape the normal limitations of autoregressive LLMs--making it a new kind of model: a Large Reasoning Model (LRM). Using this development as a catalyst, this paper takes a comprehensive look at how well current LLMs and new LRMs do on PlanBench. As we shall see, while o1's performance is a quantum improvement on the benchmark, outpacing the competition, it is still far from saturating it. This improvement also brings to the fore questions about accuracy, efficiency, and guarantees which must be considered before deploying such systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Valmeekam,+K&quot;&gt;Karthik Valmeekam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Stechly,+K&quot;&gt;Kaya Stechly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Kambhampati,+S&quot;&gt;Subbarao Kambhampati&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.13373&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PDLP - A Breakthrough in Large-Scale Linear Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/PDLP" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PDLP - A Breakthrough in Large-Scale Linear Programming" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/PDLP</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/PDLP">&lt;p&gt;Linear programming (LP) has been a cornerstone of optimization across various industries for decades, but traditional methods face challenges when applied to large-scale problems. PDLP, a groundbreaking first-order method-based solver, overcomes these limitations by offering improved scalability and efficiency, making it a powerful tool for solving complex LP tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_programming&quot;&gt;Linear programming&lt;/a&gt; (LP) problems has long been a fundamental component of optimization in numerous industries, including manufacturing, networking, and logistics. Since its inception in the 1940s, methods like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simplex_algorithm&quot;&gt;simplex algorithm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interior-point_method&quot;&gt;interior-point&lt;/a&gt; techniques have been widely used but face challenges in scaling to larger problems. PDLP (Primal-Dual Hybrid Gradient Enhanced for LP) is an innovative solver that addresses these limitations. Developed since 2018 and recently awarded the Beale–Orchard-Hays Prize, PDLP offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:First_order_methods&quot;&gt;first-order&lt;/a&gt; method (FOM) based approach that excels at large-scale linear programming tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional LP solvers often struggle with memory and hardware-related challenges, particularly when faced with large problem sizes. These issues arise due to the reliance on matrix factorizations, which demand significant memory and are incompatible with modern computational technologies such as GPUs and distributed systems. PDLP, however, utilizes &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matrix_multiplication#Definitions&quot;&gt;matrix-vector multiplication&lt;/a&gt;, which reduces memory requirements and enhances computational scalability. Built on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10851-010-0251-1&quot;&gt;primal-dual hybrid gradient&lt;/a&gt; (PDHG) algorithm, PDLP improves its reliability through adaptive restarts, preconditioning, and step-size adjustments. These enhancements allow it to converge faster and more efficiently, making it ideal for solving large-scale LP problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDLP is a game-changer for computational optimization, enabling faster and more scalable LP solving across a variety of applications. Whether optimizing network traffic in Google’s data centers or solving the massive Traveling Salesman Problem, PDLP pushes the boundaries of what is achievable in the field. Its open-source nature and growing adoption in both academic and commercial settings reflect its potential for broader impact, paving the way for new innovations in optimization technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more about its enhancements, applications and the way everything is accomplished, read more on Google Research &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.google/blog/scaling-up-linear-programming-with-pdlp/&quot;&gt;blob post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Linear programming (LP) has been a cornerstone of optimization across various industries for decades, but traditional methods face challenges when applied to large-scale problems. PDLP, a groundbreaking first-order method-based solver, overcomes these limitations by offering improved scalability and efficiency, making it a powerful tool for solving complex LP tasks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Michelangelo-Long Context Evaluations Beyond Haystacks via Latent Structure Queries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Michelangelo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Michelangelo-Long Context Evaluations Beyond Haystacks via Latent Structure Queries" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Michelangelo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Michelangelo">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We introduce Michelangelo: a minimal, synthetic, and unleaked long-context reasoning evaluation for large language models which is also easy to automatically score. This evaluation is derived via a novel, unifying framework for evaluations over arbitrarily long contexts which measure the model's ability to do more than retrieve a single piece of information from its context. The central idea of the Latent Structure Queries framework (LSQ) is to construct tasks which require a model to ``chisel away'' the irrelevant information in the context, revealing a latent structure in the context. To verify a model's understanding of this latent structure, we query the model for details of the structure. Using LSQ, we produce three diagnostic long-context evaluations across code and natural-language domains intended to provide a stronger signal of long-context language model capabilities. We perform evaluations on several state-of-the-art models and demonstrate both that a) the proposed evaluations are high-signal and b) that there is significant room for improvement in synthesizing long-context information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Vodrahalli,+K&quot;&gt;Kiran Vodrahalli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ontanon,+S&quot;&gt;Santiago Ontanon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tripuraneni,+N&quot;&gt;Nilesh Tripuraneni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+K&quot;&gt;Kelvin Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jain,+S&quot;&gt;Sanil Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shivanna,+R&quot;&gt;Rakesh Shivanna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hui,+J&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Hui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Dikkala,+N&quot;&gt;Nishanth Dikkala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Kazemi,+M&quot;&gt;Mehran Kazemi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Fatemi,+B&quot;&gt;Bahare Fatemi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Anil,+R&quot;&gt;Rohan Anil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Dyer,+E&quot;&gt;Ethan Dyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shakeri,+S&quot;&gt;Siamak Shakeri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Vij,+R&quot;&gt;Roopali Vij&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Mehta,+H&quot;&gt;Harsh Mehta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ramasesh,+V&quot;&gt;Vinay Ramasesh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Le,+Q&quot;&gt;Quoc Le&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chi,+E&quot;&gt;Ed Chi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lu,+Y&quot;&gt;Yifeng Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Firat,+O&quot;&gt;Orhan Firat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lazaridou,+A&quot;&gt;Angeliki Lazaridou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lespiau,+J&quot;&gt;Jean-Baptiste Lespiau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Attaluri,+N&quot;&gt;Nithya Attaluri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Olszewska,+K&quot;&gt;Kate Olszewska&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12640&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Training Language Models to Self-Correct via Reinforcement Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/SelfCorrection" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training Language Models to Self-Correct via Reinforcement Learning" /><published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/SelfCorrection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/SelfCorrection">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Self-correction is a highly desirable capability of large language models (LLMs), yet it has consistently been found to be largely ineffective in modern LLMs. Existing approaches for training self-correction either require multiple models or rely on a more capable model or other forms of supervision. To this end, we develop a multi-turn online reinforcement learning (RL) approach, SCoRe, that significantly improves an LLM's self-correction ability using entirely self-generated data. To build SCoRe, we first show that variants of supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on offline model-generated correction traces are insufficient for instilling self-correction behavior. In particular, we observe that training via SFT either suffers from a distribution mismatch between the training data and the model's own responses or implicitly prefers only a certain mode of correction behavior that is often not effective at test time. SCoRe addresses these challenges by training under the model's own distribution of self-generated correction traces and using appropriate regularization to steer the learning process into learning a self-correction strategy that is effective at test time as opposed to simply fitting high-reward responses for a given prompt. This regularization prescribes running a first phase of RL on a base model to generate a policy initialization that is less susceptible to collapse and then using a reward bonus to amplify self-correction during training. When applied to Gemini 1.0 Pro and 1.5 Flash models, we find that SCoRe achieves state-of-the-art self-correction performance, improving the base models' self-correction by 15.6% and 9.1% respectively on the MATH and HumanEval benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Kumar,+A&quot;&gt;Aviral Kumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhuang,+V&quot;&gt;Vincent Zhuang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Agarwal,+R&quot;&gt;Rishabh Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Su,+Y&quot;&gt;Yi Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Co-Reyes,+J+D&quot;&gt;John D Co-Reyes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Singh,+A&quot;&gt;Avi Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Baumli,+K&quot;&gt;Kate Baumli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Iqbal,+S&quot;&gt;Shariq Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Bishop,+C&quot;&gt;Colton Bishop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Roelofs,+R&quot;&gt;Rebecca Roelofs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+L+M&quot;&gt;Lei M Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=McKinney,+K&quot;&gt;Kay McKinney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shrivastava,+D&quot;&gt;Disha Shrivastava&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Paduraru,+C&quot;&gt;Cosmin Paduraru&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tucker,+G&quot;&gt;George Tucker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Precup,+D&quot;&gt;Doina Precup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Behbahani,+F&quot;&gt;Feryal Behbahani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Faust,+A&quot;&gt;Aleksandra Faust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12917&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source Generative AI Platform by Together AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Llamacoder" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source Generative AI Platform by Together AI" /><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Llamacoder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Llamacoder">&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.together.ai/&quot;&gt;Together AI&lt;/a&gt;, a leading AI acceleration cloud, is transforming the way developers and businesses design, develop, and manage generative AI applications. By focusing on open-source models like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.llama.com/&quot;&gt;Llama&lt;/a&gt;, Together AI is enabling developers to seamlessly navigate the entire AI lifecycle with tools that are both accessible and powerful. With the launch of innovative applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://llamacoder.together.ai/&quot;&gt;LlamaCoder&lt;/a&gt;, the company continues to push the boundaries of what open-source generative AI can achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To inspire developers working with Llama models, Together AI created LlamaCoder, an open-source web application that generates full applications from simple text prompts using the Llama 3.1 405B model. Since its release, LlamaCoder has gained rapid popularity, with more than 200,000 apps generated and over 2,000 GitHub stars. This success highlights the potential of Llama 3.1 405B, the first open-source model to excel at coding-based use cases. Developers have used LlamaCoder to create a range of applications, including quiz apps, pomodoro timers, and budgeting tools, demonstrating the model’s versatility and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to LlamaCoder, Together AI has also developed other example apps using Llama 3.1, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://llamatutor.together.ai/&quot;&gt;LlamaTutor&lt;/a&gt; for learning and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.turboseek.io/&quot;&gt;TurboSeek&lt;/a&gt;, an AI-powered search engine. These applications showcase the extensive capabilities of the Llama models, which rival closed-source models while maintaining robust safety features for responsible development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video class=&quot;gdm-video-embed__player&quot; muted=&quot;&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; data-autoplay=&quot;true&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;https://video.fath7-1.fna.fbcdn.net/o1/v/t2/f2/m69/AQPsmAks9NYq2Exz3Q9ipg8z8OSFrGOZ4-feeJNtDRttY4W0Ln48hJy6bDsH7pJ2ayMUG-8N_hYAA2V1tmtzpIOs.mp4?efg=eyJ2ZW5jb2RlX3RhZyI6Im9lcF9oZCJ9&amp;amp;_nc_ht=video.fath7-1.fna.fbcdn.net&amp;amp;_nc_cat=100&amp;amp;strext=1&amp;amp;vs=1352f9b7ee1846d2&amp;amp;_nc_vs=HBkcFQIYOnBhc3N0aHJvdWdoX2V2ZXJzdG9yZS9HTWRhYWh0aDlPU0hHNWdCQUxpZFNwYWV2UlFkYm1kakFBQUYVAALIAQBLB4gScHJvZ3Jlc3NpdmVfcmVjaXBlATENc3Vic2FtcGxlX2ZwcwAQdm1hZl9lbmFibGVfbnN1YgAgbWVhc3VyZV9vcmlnaW5hbF9yZXNvbHV0aW9uX3NzaW0AKGNvbXB1dGVfc3NpbV9vbmx5X2F0X29yaWdpbmFsX3Jlc29sdXRpb24AHXVzZV9sYW5jem9zX2Zvcl92cW1fdXBzY2FsaW5nABFkaXNhYmxlX3Bvc3RfcHZxcwAVACUAHIwXQAAAAAAAAAAREQAAACbAw4v_pOaIBRUCKAJDMxgLdnRzX3ByZXZpZXccF0BAk5WBBiTdGBlkYXNoX2gyNjQtYmFzaWMtZ2VuMl83MjBwEgAYGHZpZGVvcy52dHMuY2FsbGJhY2sucHJvZDgSVklERU9fVklFV19SRVFVRVNUGwqIFW9lbV90YXJnZXRfZW5jb2RlX3RhZwZvZXBfaGQTb2VtX3JlcXVlc3RfdGltZV9tcwEwDG9lbV9jZmdfcnVsZQd1bm11dGVkE29lbV9yb2lfcmVhY2hfY291bnQDOTk3EW9lbV9pc19leHBlcmltZW50AAxvZW1fdmlkZW9faWQPODY5NjA1MDU1MTM0NDIwEm9lbV92aWRlb19hc3NldF9pZA80MTIyMDc2MDg1NTk4ODgVb2VtX3ZpZGVvX3Jlc291cmNlX2lkEDE0MjY3MjQzODEzNTYyNTYcb2VtX3NvdXJjZV92aWRlb19lbmNvZGluZ19pZA84Mzc1NDQwNTE5MTQ3NDkOdnRzX3JlcXVlc3RfaWQAJQIcACW-ARsHiAFzBDkyMDQCY2QKMjAyNC0wOS0xNwNyY2IDOTAwA2FwcAVWaWRlbwJjdBFDTVNfTUVESUFfTUFOQUdFUhNvcmlnaW5hbF9kdXJhdGlvbl9zCTMzLjEzMzMzMwJ0cxVwcm9ncmVzc2l2ZV9lbmNvZGluZ3MA&amp;amp;ccb=9-4&amp;amp;oh=00_AYDGX13YwRdhTcLpLp10vqWSwagUlMQ06M72ImpDH8FhZg&amp;amp;oe=66F71DBF&amp;amp;_nc_sid=1d576d&amp;amp;_nc_rid=860686001678256&amp;amp;_nc_store_type=1&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 150,000 developers and companies using the Together AI platform, the applications for Llama models are expanding across industries—from gaming to customer service and AI-driven benchmarks. The platform’s advanced inference engine, powered by technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/html/2407.08608v1&quot;&gt;FlashAttention-3 kernels&lt;/a&gt; and RedPajama-based speculators, ensures unmatched performance and cost-efficiency for generative AI applications. Together AI’s commitment to open-source innovation is driving the rapid adoption of its platform, allowing developers and enterprises to maintain control over their data and models while fostering faster technological advancements. Find out more &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.meta.com/blog/together-ai-llamacoder/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Together AI, a leading AI acceleration cloud, is transforming the way developers and businesses design, develop, and manage generative AI applications. By focusing on open-source models like Llama, Together AI is enabling developers to seamlessly navigate the entire AI lifecycle with tools that are both accessible and powerful. With the launch of innovative applications like LlamaCoder, the company continues to push the boundaries of what open-source generative AI can achieve.</summary></entry></feed>