<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-12T12:24:44+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kavour</title><subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meta’s Movie GenAI for Video</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MetaMovie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meta’s Movie GenAI for Video" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MetaMovie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MetaMovie">&lt;p&gt;Meta has introduced Movie Gen, a groundbreaking generative AI model designed to enhance creativity in video and audio production. This model offers advanced capabilities in video generation, personalized video creation, precise editing, and audio generation, aiming to empower creators of all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta's latest innovation, Movie Gen, is set to transform the landscape of generative AI in media production. Designed for aspiring filmmakers and content creators alike, this model leverages simple text inputs to produce high-quality videos and sounds, while also enabling users to edit existing content seamlessly. With its ability to outperform similar models in various tasks, Movie Gen represents a significant advancement in AI technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://video.fath4-2.fna.fbcdn.net/o1/v/t2/f2/m69/AQPiVwlpt0o56n5kQnldQ-we0lKIfuMSlf2lM95Qmas72Go9TJysToEl6buU1jqT1QnEVTAizFxQpbhKHlJiFJiY.mp4?efg=eyJ2ZW5jb2RlX3RhZyI6Im9lcF9oZCJ9&amp;amp;_nc_ht=video.fath4-2.fna.fbcdn.net&amp;amp;_nc_cat=107&amp;amp;strext=1&amp;amp;vs=3d8ab693f43fa921&amp;amp;_nc_vs=HBksFQIYOnBhc3N0aHJvdWdoX2V2ZXJzdG9yZS9HQWJwaHh2aWozQmFxeUVEQU1kUnNVTmt2RUl6Ym1kakFBQUYVAALIAQAVAhg6cGFzc3Rocm91Z2hfZXZlcnN0b3JlL0dPbVJoaHNvYTdpRHk4TURBQkVSZVhnUTJkSlhickZxQUFBRhUCAsgBAEsHiBJwcm9ncmVzc2l2ZV9yZWNpcGUBMQ1zdWJzYW1wbGVfZnBzABB2bWFmX2VuYWJsZV9uc3ViACBtZWFzdXJlX29yaWdpbmFsX3Jlc29sdXRpb25fc3NpbQAoY29tcHV0ZV9zc2ltX29ubHlfYXRfb3JpZ2luYWxfcmVzb2x1dGlvbgAddXNlX2xhbmN6b3NfZm9yX3ZxbV91cHNjYWxpbmcAEWRpc2FibGVfcG9zdF9wdnFzABUAJQAcjBdAAAAAAAAAABERAAAAJr7Mjd7xmusNFQIoA0MzZRgLdnRzX3ByZXZpZXccF0A6G-dsi0OWGBlkYXNoX2gyNjQtYmFzaWMtZ2VuMl83MjBwEgAYGHZpZGVvcy52dHMuY2FsbGJhY2sucHJvZDgSVklERU9fVklFV19SRVFVRVNUGwqIFW9lbV90YXJnZXRfZW5jb2RlX3RhZwZvZXBfaGQTb2VtX3JlcXVlc3RfdGltZV9tcwEwDG9lbV9jZmdfcnVsZQd1bm11dGVkE29lbV9yb2lfcmVhY2hfY291bnQDOTk3EW9lbV9pc19leHBlcmltZW50AAxvZW1fdmlkZW9faWQPNTIzNTI5ODIwNjM2Nzg0Em9lbV92aWRlb19hc3NldF9pZA8zODg5NTMzMzQyNjgzNjIVb2VtX3ZpZGVvX3Jlc291cmNlX2lkEDM4OTQ5MzIxMjc0NjIxNzUcb2VtX3NvdXJjZV92aWRlb19lbmNvZGluZ19pZA81Mzk4NDQzNTUwODI0MTcOdnRzX3JlcXVlc3RfaWQAJQIcACW-ARsHiAFzBDE3MDUCY2QKMjAyNC0xMC0wMwNyY2IDOTAwA2FwcAVWaWRlbwJjdBFDTVNfTUVESUFfTUFOQUdFUhNvcmlnaW5hbF9kdXJhdGlvbl9zCTI2LjEwOTQxNwJ0cxVwcm9ncmVzc2l2ZV9lbmNvZGluZ3MA&amp;amp;ccb=9-4&amp;amp;oh=00_AYBDxIAh0BZG36VY4IE--vV8XLgjKngY7T4tE9Al2dkvZg&amp;amp;oe=670C1C0A&amp;amp;_nc_sid=1d576d&amp;amp;_nc_rid=299321509316915&amp;amp;_nc_store_type=1&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movie Gen is part of Meta's ongoing commitment to sharing foundational AI research with the community. This journey began with the Make-A-Scene series, which enabled the creation of images, audio, video, and 3D animations. Following this, the Llama Image foundation models improved the quality of image and video generation. Now, Movie Gen combines these advancements into a comprehensive suite that allows for unprecedented control over creative outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movie Gen boasts four primary capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Generates high-definition videos from text prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalized Video Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Creates customized videos featuring specific individuals based on their images and text prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precise Video Editing:&lt;/strong&gt; Allows for detailed edits on existing videos using both video and text inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Produces high-quality audio that syncs with generated or edited videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video generation feature utilizes a 30B parameter transformer model capable of producing videos up to 16 seconds long at a rate of 16 frames per second. This model excels at reasoning about object motion and interactions within the scene, making it a state-of-the-art solution for generating dynamic video content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature takes personalization a step further by combining a person's image with relevant text prompts to create unique videos that maintain the individual's identity and motion. The results have been recognized as state-of-the-art in preserving human likeness while generating engaging content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The editing variant of Movie Gen allows users to make localized edits—like adding or removing elements—while preserving the original content. This capability combines advanced image editing techniques with video generation, enabling users to achieve desired outcomes without requiring specialized skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio generation model can produce high-fidelity audio that complements video content. It supports various audio elements such as ambient sounds and instrumental music, achieving state-of-the-art performance in aligning audio with both video and text prompts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of these models involved numerous technical innovations in architecture and training methodologies. A/B human evaluations show that users prefer Movie Gen’s outputs over competing models across all four capabilities. While these results are promising, Meta acknowledges that further optimizations are necessary to enhance inference speed and overall quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, Meta aims to collaborate closely with filmmakers and creators to refine Movie Gen based on user feedback. The goal is to create tools that not only enhance creativity but also open new avenues for self-expression. Future applications could include personalized animated greetings or dynamic storytelling videos shared across social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Movie Gen marks a pivotal moment in generative AI technology for media production. By providing powerful tools that democratize access to high-quality video and audio creation, Meta is empowering individuals to bring their artistic visions to life like never before. As this technology continues to evolve, the possibilities for creativity and innovation are boundless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for further developments as Meta continues to push the boundaries of what generative AI can achieve in the world of media! You can read full article &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.meta.com/blog/movie-gen-media-foundation-models-generative-ai-video/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Meta has introduced Movie Gen, a groundbreaking generative AI model designed to enhance creativity in video and audio production. This model offers advanced capabilities in video generation, personalized video creation, precise editing, and audio generation, aiming to empower creators of all backgrounds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B Available for Developers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gemini15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B Available for Developers" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gemini15</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gemini15">&lt;p&gt;Google has officially launched Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B, a lightweight and efficient model optimized for various tasks, now available for production use. This release aims to empower developers with the lowest cost per intelligence among Gemini models, enhancing capabilities in chat, transcription, and long-context language translation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an exciting development for AI enthusiasts and developers, Google has announced that Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B is now generally available for use. This latest variant of the Gemini model is designed to be lightweight and efficient, making it particularly suitable for high-volume tasks across multiple applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B is a smaller and faster version of the original Gemini 1.5 Flash model, which was introduced earlier this year at Google I/O. Over the past few months, Google DeepMind has worked diligently to refine this model based on developer feedback, pushing the boundaries of its performance capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-developer-goog-blog-assets/images/image2_st96QjR.original.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Key Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimized Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Flash-8B nearly matches the performance of its predecessor across various benchmarks, excelling in tasks such as chat, transcription, and long-context language translation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Volume Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; The model is particularly well-suited for high-volume multimodal use cases and long-context summarization tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; It offers the lowest cost per intelligence of any Gemini model, making it an attractive option for developers looking to manage expenses while maximizing output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers can access Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B for free via &lt;a href=&quot;https://aistudio.google.com/app/prompts/new_chat?model=gemini-1.5-flash-8b-002&quot;&gt;Google AI Studio&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/models/gemini&quot;&gt;Gemini API&lt;/a&gt;. This accessibility allows developers to integrate the model into their applications seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pricing for using Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B will begin on Monday, October 14th, for those on the paid tier. This new pricing structure reflects Google's ongoing commitment to reducing developer costs while providing powerful tools for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enhance usability, Google has doubled the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.google.dev/pricing&quot;&gt;rate limits&lt;/a&gt; for the 1.5 Flash-8B model, allowing developers to send up to 4,000 requests per minute (RPM). This increase facilitates smoother operations and better handling of high-volume tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release of Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B marks a significant step in Google's efforts to provide best-in-class small models informed by developer feedback and rigorous testing. As Google continues to innovate in this space, further updates and enhancements are anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general availability of Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B opens new avenues for developers looking to leverage advanced AI capabilities in their projects. With its focus on speed, efficiency, and cost-effectiveness, this model is poised to become a valuable asset in various applications ranging from chatbots to language translation services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read full article click &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.googleblog.com/en/gemini-15-flash-8b-is-now-generally-available-for-use/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Happy building and stay tuned for more updates!&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Google has officially launched Gemini 1.5 Flash-8B, a lightweight and efficient model optimized for various tasks, now available for production use. This release aims to empower developers with the lowest cost per intelligence among Gemini models, enhancing capabilities in chat, transcription, and long-context language translation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Canvas-A New Era for ChatGPT Collaboration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/OpenAICanvas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Canvas-A New Era for ChatGPT Collaboration" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/OpenAICanvas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/OpenAICanvas">&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has unveiled Canvas, a new interface for ChatGPT that enhances collaboration on writing and coding projects. This innovative feature allows users to work side by side with the AI, providing tools for inline feedback, version control, and targeted editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has taken a significant step forward in the realm of AI-assisted creativity and coding with the introduction of Canvas. This new interface transforms how users interact with ChatGPT, enabling a more collaborative and efficient workflow that goes beyond simple text-based conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canvas is an early beta feature built on the GPT-4o model that opens in a separate window, allowing users to collaborate with ChatGPT on projects in real-time. This interface is designed to facilitate writing and coding tasks that require iterative editing and revisions, making it easier for users to refine their ideas and outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional chat interface often falls short for complex projects requiring detailed edits. Canvas addresses this limitation by allowing users to highlight specific sections of text or code, enabling ChatGPT to provide inline feedback and suggestions tailored to the entire project context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Key Features of Canvas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct Editing:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can directly edit text or code within the Canvas interface.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline Suggestions:&lt;/strong&gt; ChatGPT offers real-time suggestions and feedback on highlighted sections.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can restore previous versions of their work easily using a back button.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing Shortcuts:&lt;/strong&gt; A variety of shortcuts enable quick adjustments such as changing document length or reading level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is inherently iterative, and Canvas simplifies this process by allowing users to track changes more effectively. The model provides various coding shortcuts that enhance the development experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Coding Shortcuts Include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review Code:&lt;/strong&gt; Inline suggestions help improve code quality.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Logs:&lt;/strong&gt; Print statements can be inserted to assist with debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Comments:&lt;/strong&gt; Comments can be added for clarity within the code.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix Bugs:&lt;/strong&gt; The model can detect and rewrite problematic code snippets.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port to Other Languages:&lt;/strong&gt; Code can be translated into various programming languages like JavaScript, Python, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying GPT-4o model has been trained specifically for collaboration, allowing it to understand when to open a Canvas and how to make targeted edits. OpenAI's research team has focused on developing core behaviors that enhance this collaborative experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Core Behaviors Include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Triggering Canvas:&lt;/strong&gt; The model intelligently decides when to open a Canvas based on user prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diverse Content Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; It can generate various types of content effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit and Rewrite:&lt;/strong&gt; The model makes targeted edits or rewrites based on user selections.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline Critique:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides constructive feedback on user-generated content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Canvas marks a significant evolution in how users interact with AI tools. OpenAI plans to rapidly improve its capabilities based on user feedback during this early beta phase, aiming to enhance both functionality and user experience further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of Canvas represents a transformative approach to working with ChatGPT, making it an invaluable tool for writers and developers alike. As OpenAI continues to refine this feature, users can look forward to an even more powerful collaborative experience that enhances creativity and productivity in their projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new interface not only streamlines workflows but also empowers users by providing them with greater control over their creative processes. Stay tuned for future updates as OpenAI expands the capabilities of Canvas! Check for more infor and integration videos in the OpenAI's official &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/introducing-canvas/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">OpenAI has unveiled Canvas, a new interface for ChatGPT that enhances collaboration on writing and coding projects. This innovative feature allows users to work side by side with the AI, providing tools for inline feedback, version control, and targeted editing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Were RNNs All We Needed?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/RNNneeded" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Were RNNs All We Needed?" /><published>2024-10-02T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/RNNneeded</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/RNNneeded">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The scalability limitations of Transformers regarding sequence length have renewed interest in recurrent sequence models that are parallelizable during training. As a result, many novel recurrent architectures, such as S4, Mamba, and Aaren, have been proposed that achieve comparable performance. In this work, we revisit traditional recurrent neural networks (RNNs) from over a decade ago: LSTMs (1997) and GRUs (2014). While these models were slow due to requiring to backpropagate through time (BPTT), we show that by removing their hidden state dependencies from their input, forget, and update gates, LSTMs and GRUs no longer need to BPTT and can be efficiently trained in parallel. Building on this, we introduce minimal versions (minLSTMs and minGRUs) that (1) use significantly fewer parameters than their traditional counterparts and (2) are fully parallelizable during training (175x faster for a sequence of length 512). Lastly, we show that these stripped-down versions of decade-old RNNs match the empirical performance of recent sequence models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Feng,+L&quot;&gt;Leo Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tung,+F&quot;&gt;Frederick Tung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ahmed,+M+O&quot;&gt;Mohamed Osama Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Bengio,+Y&quot;&gt;Yoshua Bengio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hajimirsadegh,+H&quot;&gt;Hossein Hajimirsadegh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.01201&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing FLUX1.1 Pro and the BFL API</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Flux11pro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing FLUX1.1 Pro and the BFL API" /><published>2024-10-02T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Flux11pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Flux11pro">&lt;p&gt;Black Forest Labs has announced the launch of FLUX1.1 Pro, their most advanced generative model to date, alongside the beta release of the BFL API. This development aims to enhance the capabilities of creators and developers by providing faster, higher-quality image generation and customizable API options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blackforestlabs.ai/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/g312-1-2048x997.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a significant leap forward for generative technology, Black Forest Labs has unveiled FLUX1.1 Pro and the BFL API. This release not only enhances the speed and quality of image generation but also introduces advanced customization options for developers and enterprises alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FLUX1.1 Pro is designed to deliver exceptional performance, boasting six times faster generation rates compared to its predecessor. This model improves not only the speed but also enhances image quality, prompt adherence, and diversity in outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Key Features of FLUX1.1 Pro as presented in the official blog post are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superior Speed and Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; The model offers reduced latency, making workflows more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Under the codename “blueberry,” FLUX1.1 Pro has been benchmarked against other models and achieved the highest overall Elo score on Artificial Analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Resolution Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Upcoming features will allow users to generate images up to 2k resolution without losing prompt fidelity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FLUX1.1 Pro will be available through various platforms including together.ai, Replicate, fal.ai, and Freepik, broadening access for users across different sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newly launched beta version of the BFL API provides developers with powerful tools to customize their applications effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the BFL API Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Customization:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can tailor outputs based on model choice, image resolution, and content moderation requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; The API supports projects of all sizes, from small applications to enterprise-level solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competitive Pricing:&lt;/strong&gt; The pricing structure is designed to offer high-quality images at a lower cost compared to competitors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pricing Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Price per Image&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FLUX.1 [dev]&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;$0.025&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FLUX.1 [pro]&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;$0.05&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FLUX1.1 [pro]&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;$0.04&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BFL API is now available for developers eager to explore its capabilities. Interested users can begin their journey by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.bfl.ml/&quot;&gt;docs.bfl.ml&lt;/a&gt; for comprehensive documentation. In case this sounds interesting to you and want to find out more check everything &lt;a href=&quot;https://blackforestlabs.ai/announcing-flux-1-1-pro-and-the-bfl-api/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Black Forest Labs has announced the launch of FLUX1.1 Pro, their most advanced generative model to date, alongside the beta release of the BFL API. This development aims to enhance the capabilities of creators and developers by providing faster, higher-quality image generation and customizable API options.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An AI Companion for Everyone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MicAICopilot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An AI Companion for Everyone" /><published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MicAICopilot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MicAICopilot">&lt;p&gt;This article discusses Microsoft's vision for a new AI companion, Copilot, designed to enhance human experiences by providing personalized support and assistance. With features like voice interaction and contextual understanding, Copilot aims to simplify daily tasks while prioritizing user privacy and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we navigate through a technological paradigm shift, the role of artificial intelligence in our daily lives is becoming increasingly significant. Microsoft is at the forefront of this evolution, focusing on creating an AI companion that is not just a tool but a supportive presence in users' lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Philosophy Behind Copilot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft AI, the mission extends beyond technical advancements; it emphasizes the importance of enhancing human well-being. The goal is to ensure that technology serves humanity by enriching lives, fostering connections, and supporting individual uniqueness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot is designed to be a dynamic and evolving companion that understands the context of users' lives while safeguarding their privacy. Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual Understanding:&lt;/strong&gt; Copilot learns from interactions to provide relevant support tailored to individual needs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task Management:&lt;/strong&gt; It assists with everyday tasks such as planning events or taking notes during appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotional Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Copilot offers encouragement and advice during challenging moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Op1kuT3zu_I?si=be_w4oNFzC9g1yRC&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;New Capabilities and Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest updates to Copilot introduce several advanced capabilities aimed at enhancing user interaction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copilot Voice:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can engage with Copilot through voice commands, making interactions more natural and intuitive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copilot Daily:&lt;/strong&gt; This feature provides daily summaries of news and weather, helping users stay informed without feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalized Discover:&lt;/strong&gt; A guide that offers customized suggestions based on user interactions with Microsoft services.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copilot in Microsoft Edge:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrated directly into the Edge browser for quick access to information and assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copilot Labs:&lt;/strong&gt; A platform for users to test experimental features like Copilot Vision and Think Deeper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vSOp4uhgSjw&quot; title=&quot;Copilot Vision&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot Vision represents a groundbreaking way to interact with technology. It can see what users see in real time, providing contextual help based on visual input. This feature is designed with user safety in mind, ensuring that sessions are opt-in and ephemeral, meaning no data is stored post-session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User feedback plays a crucial role in shaping the development of Copilot. Features like Think Deeper allow for more complex reasoning through questions, enhancing the AI's ability to assist with nuanced decisions. This collaborative approach ensures that the technology evolves according to user needs and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey towards creating an effective AI companion is ongoing. Microsoft aims to expand Copilot’s capabilities across various platforms while maintaining a commitment to user privacy and security. As new features roll out, including generative search capabilities in Bing, the focus remains on enhancing user experience through thoughtful design and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Copilot marks a significant step forward in how we interact with technology. By prioritizing human connection and support, Microsoft envisions an AI companion that enriches lives rather than diminishes them. This journey promises to reshape our relationship with technology in profound ways. If you want to find out more about integrating this technological advancement to your toolkit read more from Microsoft's official &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/10/01/an-ai-companion-for-everyone/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">This article discusses Microsoft's vision for a new AI companion, Copilot, designed to enhance human experiences by providing personalized support and assistance. With features like voice interaction and contextual understanding, Copilot aims to simplify daily tasks while prioritizing user privacy and security.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anaconda AI Navigator Empowering Generative AI on Desktops</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AnacondaGenAI" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anaconda AI Navigator Empowering Generative AI on Desktops" /><published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AnacondaGenAI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AnacondaGenAI">&lt;p&gt;Anaconda has launched AI Navigator, a free desktop application that allows users to securely access and run over 200 pre-trained generative AI models locally. This innovative tool aims to democratize AI access while ensuring data privacy and security for both individuals and enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 1, 2024, Anaconda Inc. announced the general release of its new desktop application, &lt;strong&gt;AI Navigator&lt;/strong&gt;. This tool is designed to bring the capabilities of large language models (LLMs) directly to users’ desktops, allowing them to interact with these models without compromising their private information. With the increasing demand for secure AI solutions, AI Navigator addresses various challenges associated with adopting and managing generative AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI Navigator offers several key features that enhance its usability and appeal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Model Access:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can access over 200 pre-trained LLMs, including more than 50 unique models tailored for different hardware configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private, Local Environment:&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike cloud-based models, AI Navigator allows users to run models locally, ensuring sensitive data remains on their devices.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intuitive User Interface:&lt;/strong&gt; The user-friendly design makes it accessible for both technical and non-technical users to browse, download, and interact with various models.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Deployment:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can utilize built-in chat interfaces or integrate with external applications via the API inference server.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Control and Governance:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2025, centralized management tools will allow IT administrators to curate and govern the AI models used within their organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early response to AI Navigator has been overwhelmingly positive, with over 10,000 users actively engaging with the platform. Notably, there has been significant interest in code generation and debugging functionalities. The insights gathered during the public beta phase have led to a remarkable 300% increase in platform launch speeds, demonstrating Anaconda's commitment to continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI Navigator is not just a tool for individual developers; it has significant implications for various industries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finance:&lt;/strong&gt; Development of AI agents for market analysis and automated risk assessments.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare:&lt;/strong&gt; Assistance in diagnostics and personalized treatment plans through AI-powered agents.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manufacturing:&lt;/strong&gt; Creation of intelligent systems for predictive maintenance and supply chain optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Service:&lt;/strong&gt; Design of AI-driven virtual assistants to enhance customer support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government:&lt;/strong&gt; Secure AI agents addressing public service challenges and delivering personalized services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anaconda envisions a future where generative AI is accessible and practical for businesses without requiring deep technical expertise. By 2025, users will be able to create and share their own autonomous AI agents capable of executing tasks independently. This aligns with Anaconda's broader mission of making AI creation, distribution, and governance as accessible as any everyday digital tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of AI Navigator marks a significant step in Anaconda's efforts to democratize access to generative AI technologies while ensuring data privacy and security. With its robust features and user-friendly design, AI Navigator is poised to empower individuals and organizations alike in harnessing the full potential of enterprise-ready AI solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anaconda invites users to explore the capabilities of AI Navigator by downloading it for free on Mac and Windows desktops. For more information about this innovative tool, visit Anaconda's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anaconda.com/products/ai-navigator?utm_source=pressrelease&amp;amp;utm_medium=anaconda&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ai-navigator&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to find out more or to read full article on Anaconda Navigator go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anaconda.com/press/anaconda-ai-navigator-generative-ai-desktop-agent&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Anaconda has launched AI Navigator, a free desktop application that allows users to securely access and run over 200 pre-trained generative AI models locally. This innovative tool aims to democratize AI access while ensuring data privacy and security for both individuals and enterprises.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Logic-of-Thought. Injecting Logic into Contexts for Full Reasoning in Large Language Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/redefineRLHF" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Logic-of-Thought. Injecting Logic into Contexts for Full Reasoning in Large Language Models" /><published>2024-09-30T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/redefineRLHF</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/redefineRLHF">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) has become the leading approach for fine-tuning large language models (LLM). However, RLHF has limitations in multi-task learning (MTL) due to challenges of reward hacking and extreme multi-objective optimization (i.e., trade-off of multiple and/or sometimes conflicting objectives). Applying RLHF for MTL currently requires careful tuning of the weights for reward model and data combinations. This is often done via human intuition and does not generalize. In this work, we introduce a novel post-training paradigm which we called Constrained Generative Policy Optimization (CGPO). The core of CGPO is Mixture of Judges (MoJ) with cost-efficient constrained policy optimization with stratification, which can identify the perfect blend in RLHF in a principled manner. It shows strong empirical results with theoretical guarantees, does not require extensive hyper-parameter tuning, and is plug-and-play in common post-training pipelines. Together, this can detect and mitigate reward hacking behaviors while reaching a pareto-optimal point across an extremely large number of objectives.
Our empirical evaluations demonstrate that CGPO significantly outperforms standard RLHF algorithms like PPO and DPO across various tasks including general chat, STEM questions, instruction following, and coding. Specifically, CGPO shows improvements of 7.4% in AlpacaEval-2 (general chat), 12.5% in Arena-Hard (STEM &amp;amp; reasoning), and consistent gains in other domains like math and coding. Notably, PPO, while commonly used, is prone to severe reward hacking in popular coding benchmarks, which CGPO successfully addresses. This breakthrough in RLHF not only tackles reward hacking and extreme multi-objective optimization challenges but also advances the state-of-the-art in aligning general-purpose LLMs for diverse applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+T&quot;&gt;Tengyu Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Helenowski,+E&quot;&gt;Eryk Helenowski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sankararaman,+K+A&quot;&gt;Karthik Abinav Sankararaman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jin,+D&quot;&gt;Di Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Peng,+K&quot;&gt;Kaiyan Peng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Han,+E&quot;&gt;Eric Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Nie,+S&quot;&gt;Shaoliang Nie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhu,+C&quot;&gt;Chen Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+H&quot;&gt;Hejia Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhou,+W&quot;&gt;Wenxuan Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zeng,+Z&quot;&gt;Zhouhao Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+Y&quot;&gt;Yun He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Mandyam,+K&quot;&gt;Karishma Mandyam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Talabzadeh,+A&quot;&gt;Arya Talabzadeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Khabsa,+M&quot;&gt;Madian Khabsa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Cohen,+G&quot;&gt;Gabriel Cohen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Tian,+Y&quot;&gt;Yuandong Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ma,+H&quot;&gt;Hao Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+S&quot;&gt;Sinong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Fang,+H&quot;&gt;Han Fang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.20370&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Logic-of-Thought. Injecting Logic into Contexts for Full Reasoning in Large Language Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/LogicOfThough" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Logic-of-Thought. Injecting Logic into Contexts for Full Reasoning in Large Language Models" /><published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/LogicOfThough</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/LogicOfThough">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across various tasks but their performance in complex logical reasoning tasks remains unsatisfactory. Although some prompting methods, such as Chain-of-Thought, can improve the reasoning ability of LLMs to some extent, they suffer from an unfaithful issue where derived conclusions may not align with the generated reasoning chain. To address this issue, some studies employ the approach of propositional logic to further enhance logical reasoning abilities of LLMs. However, the potential omissions in the extraction of logical expressions in these methods can cause information loss in the logical reasoning process, thereby generating incorrect results. To this end, we propose Logic-of-Thought (LoT) prompting which employs propositional logic to generate expanded logical information from input context, and utilizes the generated logical information as an additional augmentation to the input prompts, thereby enhancing the capability of logical reasoning. The LoT is orthogonal to existing prompting methods and can be seamlessly integrated with them. Extensive experiments demonstrate that LoT boosts the performance of various prompting methods with a striking margin across five logical reasoning tasks. In particular, the LoT enhances Chain-of-Thought's performance on the ReClor dataset by +4.35%; moreover, it improves Chain-of-Thought with Self-Consistency's performance on LogiQA by +5%; additionally, it boosts performance of Tree-of-Thoughts on ProofWriter dataset by +8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+T&quot;&gt;Tongxuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+W&quot;&gt;Wenjiang Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Huang,+W&quot;&gt;Weizhe Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+X&quot;&gt;Xingyu Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+J&quot;&gt;Jiaxing Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+H&quot;&gt;Hailong Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+J&quot;&gt;Jing Li&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.17539&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Diffusion-based Visual Foundation Model for High-quality Dense Prediction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Lotus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diffusion-based Visual Foundation Model for High-quality Dense Prediction" /><published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Lotus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Lotus">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Leveraging the visual priors of pre-trained text-to-image diffusion models offers a promising solution to enhance zero-shot generalization in dense prediction tasks. However, existing methods often uncritically use the original diffusion formulation, which may not be optimal due to the fundamental differences between dense prediction and image generation. In this paper, we provide a systemic analysis of the diffusion formulation for the dense prediction, focusing on both quality and efficiency. And we find that the original parameterization type for image generation, which learns to predict noise, is harmful for dense prediction; the multi-step noising/denoising diffusion process is also unnecessary and challenging to optimize. Based on these insights, we introduce Lotus, a diffusion-based visual foundation model with a simple yet effective adaptation protocol for dense prediction. Specifically, Lotus is trained to directly predict annotations instead of noise, thereby avoiding harmful variance. We also reformulate the diffusion process into a single-step procedure, simplifying optimization and significantly boosting inference speed. Additionally, we introduce a novel tuning strategy called detail preserver, which achieves more accurate and fine-grained predictions. Without scaling up the training data or model capacity, Lotus achieves SoTA performance in zero-shot depth and normal estimation across various datasets. It also enhances efficiency, being significantly faster than most existing diffusion-based methods. Lotus' superior quality and efficiency also enable a wide range of practical applications, such as joint estimation, single/multi-view 3D reconstruction, etc. Project page: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lotus3d.github.io/&quot;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+J&quot;&gt;Jing He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+H&quot;&gt;Haodong Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yin,+W&quot;&gt;Wei Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liang,+Y&quot;&gt;Yixun Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+L&quot;&gt;Leheng Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhou,+K&quot;&gt;Kaiqiang Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+H&quot;&gt;Hongbo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+B&quot;&gt;Bingbing Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chen,+Y&quot;&gt;Ying-Cong Chen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.18124&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry></feed>