<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-29T16:25:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kavour</title><subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Can AI art become too real (and steal your job)?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Ideogram" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can AI art become too real (and steal your job)?" /><published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Ideogram</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Ideogram">&lt;p&gt; Just when you thought AI image generators couldn't get any more mind-blowing, Ideogram drops &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.ideogram.ai/3.0?&quot;&gt;version 3.0&lt;/a&gt;, and it's like they've been sneaking lessons from Rembrandt and Spielberg. We're talking about an AI so good, it might just replace your graphic designer... and possibly your therapist, because the existential dread is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the days when asking an AI for a &quot;retro-futuristic cyberpunk bowling alley&quot; resulted in something that looked like a toddler's fever dream? Well, Ideogram 3.0 introduces Style References. Now, you can upload up to three images of your desired aesthetic, and the AI will actually listen. It’s like teaching a robot to appreciate art, except instead of questioning its existence, it just spits out stunning visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling adventurous? Hit the &quot;Random style&quot; button and dive into their library of 4.3 &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt; presets. That's right, billion. It’s like shuffling through the world's largest mood board, curated by an AI with impeccable taste (or at least, a very broad one). Find a style you love? Save it with a Style Code. Because nothing says &quot;cutting-edge creativity&quot; like sharing a secret code for the perfect digital aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's be honest, AI-generatd text has traditionally been about as coherent as a politician's promise. But Ideogram 3.0 is changing the game. Imagine crafting beautiful, stylized text for posters, ads, and even book covers, all with remarkable precision. We're talking about complex compositions that would make a seasoned graphic designer weep with envy (or maybe just weep, period).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The examples speak for themselves. A movie poster for &quot;marion et ludo&quot; that looks like it was hand-lettered by a Parisian artist? Check. A fashion poster featuring magenta trousers and the word &quot;zenith&quot; in a minimalist typeface? &lt;em&gt;Très chic&lt;/em&gt;. A book cover split down the middle, with a rabbit on one side and a snarling big cat on the other? Absolutely bonkers, but also strangely compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For small businesses and entrepreneurs, Ideogram 3.0 is either a godsend or the harbinger of doom for traditional design agencies. Now you can generate professional-quality logos, promotional posters, landing page concepts, and product photography in seconds, at a fraction of the cost. It's like having a full creative team at your beck and call, without the awkward office holiday parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to customize graphics at scale? The Batch Generation feature lets you ideate quickly and effortlessly. It's the perfect tool for A/B testing your way to marketing glory, or for overwhelming your competitors with an endless barrage of visually stunning content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most impressive aspect of Ideogram 3.0 is its ability to generate images that are so realistic, they blur the line between the real and the digital. Intricate backgrounds, precise lighting, nuanced colors, and lifelike environmental detail – it's all there. You can create sophisticated spatial compositions that look like they were shot by a professional photographer with a Hollywood budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From origami frogs holding floral books to underwater portraits surrounded by shimmering fish, the possibilities are endless. And while we're not quite at the point where AI can perfectly replicate the human experience, Ideogram 3.0 is getting awfully close. So close, in fact, that you might start questioning the very nature of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideogram 3.0 is a game-changer. It's a powerful tool that empowers creators, streamlines workflows, and pushes the boundaries of what's possible with AI. Whether you're a seasoned designer, a small business owner, or just someone who enjoys playing around with cutting-edge tech, this is an AI you need to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be warned: once you've experienced the magic of Ideogram 3.0, there's no going back. You'll start seeing the world through the lens of AI, imagining endless possibilities for digital art and design. And who knows, maybe you'll even start questioning whether that sunset you're looking at is real, or just a cleverly generated simulation. If you don't believe me and the words you just read, take a step and try everything yourself. Sweet dreams! &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Just when you thought AI image generators couldn't get any more mind-blowing, Ideogram drops version 3.0, and it's like they've been sneaking lessons from Rembrandt and Spielberg. We're talking about an AI so good, it might just replace your graphic designer... and possibly your therapist, because the existential dread is real.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qwen 2.5 Omni - The Model That Does Everything But Your Taxes (Probably)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/QweenOmni" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qwen 2.5 Omni - The Model That Does Everything But Your Taxes (Probably)" /><published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/QweenOmni</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/QweenOmni">&lt;p&gt;Alright, tech enthusiasts, buckle up! The wizards over at Qwen have cooked up something &lt;a href=&quot;https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2.5-omni/?&quot;&gt;truly magical&lt;/a&gt; – or, you know, meticulously engineered – called &lt;strong&gt;Qwen2.5-Omni&lt;/strong&gt;. And no, it's not a new kitchen appliance (though I bet it could write a killer recipe). It's an end-to-end multimodal model so comprehensive, it might just replace your entire tech support team...and maybe your dog walker. Just kidding... mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes Qwen2.5-Omni stand out from the ever-growing crowd of AI models? It juggles &lt;strong&gt;text, images, audio, and video&lt;/strong&gt; inputs like a digital circus performer, yes you read correctly, text, images, audio and video. And it doesn't just process them; it responds in real-time, spitting out both text and suspiciously human-like speech. Imagine chatting with an AI that can not only understand your rambling voice memos but also generate a soothing voice reply. We're living in the future, people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;896&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yKcANdkRuNI&quot; title=&quot;Qwen2.5-Omni-7B: Voice Chat + Video Chat! Powerful New Opensource end-to-end multimodal model&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omni-Capabilities:&lt;/strong&gt; As the name suggests, Qwen2.5-Omni handles multiple modalities. It's like the Swiss Army knife of AI, but instead of a corkscrew, it has advanced speech synthesis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinker-Talker Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where things get interesting. The model uses a &quot;Thinker-Talker&quot; architecture. The &quot;Thinker&quot; processes the inputs and generates fancy representations (think high-level thoughts). The &quot;Talker&quot; then turns those thoughts into lovely spoken (or written) words. It's basically the AI equivalent of having a really smart friend who can explain complex topics in simple terms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Shenanigans:&lt;/strong&gt; Forget waiting for hours to get a response. This model is built for real-time interaction. Chunked input? Immediate output? It's all in a day's work for Qwen2.5-Omni.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speech That Doesn't Sound Like a Robot:&lt;/strong&gt; Apparently, the speech generation is so natural and robust, it puts other models to shame. Finally, we can have AI conversations without feeling like we're talking to a dial-up modem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance That Pops:&lt;/strong&gt; It can measure itself against others in the field, and it turns out that Qwen2.5-Omni performs admirably against competitors, even closed-source ones!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, let's get a little technical. The &quot;Thinker&quot; part of the architecture is a Transformer decoder (ooooh, fancy!), while the &quot;Talker&quot; is a dual-track autoregressive Transformer Decoder (double ooooh! 🫣). Basically, it's all about processing information efficiently and generating coherent outputs. The model even has a special position embedding (TMRoPE) to keep audio and video timestamps in sync. Because nobody wants an AI that can't keep up with the beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qwen2.5-Omni isn't just talk; it's got the performance to back it up. It excels in tasks that require integrating multiple modalities and also shines in single-modality tasks like speech recognition, translation, and image/video understanding. It's basically the overachiever of the AI world. But in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Qwen team isn't resting on its recent success. They're planning to improve the model's ability to follow voice commands and enhance audio-visual understanding. And, of course, they want to integrate even more modalities because why stop at four when you can have them all? The dream is an omni-model that can do it all, from writing blog posts (like this one!) to composing symphonies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to take Qwen2.5-Omni for a spin? You can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/Qwen/Qwen2.5-Omni-7B&quot;&gt;Hugging Face&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://modelscope.cn/models/Qwen/Qwen2.5-Omni-7B&quot;&gt;ModelScope&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.aliyun.com/zh/model-studio/user-guide/qwen-omni&quot;&gt;DashScope&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/QwenLM/Qwen2.5-Omni&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Or you could just go test it from within&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.qwenlm.ai/&quot;&gt;qwen chat&lt;/a&gt;.  Plus, you can try out a demo and join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/invite/yPEP2vHTu4&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; community to discuss all things Qwen. Go forth and explore the future of multimodal AI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Qwen2.5-Omni is a significant step forward in the world of AI. It's versatile, powerful, and, dare I say, kinda fun. So, go check it out and prepare to be amazed (or at least mildly impressed). And if it ever figures out how to do taxes, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Alright, tech enthusiasts, buckle up! The wizards over at Qwen have cooked up something truly magical – or, you know, meticulously engineered – called Qwen2.5-Omni. And no, it's not a new kitchen appliance (though I bet it could write a killer recipe). It's an end-to-end multimodal model so comprehensive, it might just replace your entire tech support team...and maybe your dog walker. Just kidding... mostly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revolutionizing PDF Text Extraction with Vision Language Models by AllenAI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/OlmOCR" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revolutionizing PDF Text Extraction with Vision Language Models by AllenAI" /><published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/OlmOCR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/OlmOCR">&lt;p&gt; The Allen Institute for AI has introduced olmOCR, an open-source tool that leverages Vision Language Models to extract text from PDFs with high accuracy, preserving the natural reading order and supporting complex elements like tables, equations, and handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./olmocr-v3-light-crf8wznq.png&quot; alt=&quot;olmOCR pipeline&quot; class=&quot;css-1hz6c62&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of digital documents in Portable Document Format (PDF) has necessitated advanced tools capable of accurate and efficient text extraction. Traditional Optical Character Recognition (OCR) systems often struggle with complex layouts, leading to inaccuracies and loss of information. Addressing these challenges, the Allen Institute for AI has developed olmOCR, an open-source OCR tool designed to convert PDFs into plain text while preserving the natural reading order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;olmOCR distinguishes itself by its ability to handle complex document structures, including tables, equations, and handwritten content. By leveraging Vision Language Models, olmOCR ensures that the extracted text maintains the context and formatting of the original document, facilitating more accurate data analysis and processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool's high-throughput capabilities make it particularly suitable for large-scale document processing tasks. Researchers and professionals dealing with extensive PDF archives can utilize olmOCR to streamline their workflows, reducing the time and effort required for manual data extraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the notable features of olmOCR is its open-source nature, encouraging collaboration and continuous improvement within the community. Developers and researchers can contribute to the project's development, customize the tool to specific use cases, and integrate it into existing systems, thereby enhancing its versatility and applicability across various domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to its technical capabilities, olmOCR emphasizes user accessibility. The tool is designed with a user-friendly interface, allowing individuals with varying levels of technical expertise to utilize its features effectively. Comprehensive documentation and support further facilitate the adoption and integration of olmOCR into diverse workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of olmOCR aligns with the Allen Institute for AI's commitment to advancing artificial intelligence research and applications. By providing a robust solution for PDF text extraction, olmOCR contributes to the broader goal of making information more accessible and actionable, thereby supporting data-driven decision-making processes across various sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future developments for olmOCR may include expanding its language support, enhancing its ability to recognize and process diverse handwriting styles, and improving its integration capabilities with other data processing tools. Such advancements would further solidify its position as a leading OCR solution in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, olmOCR represents a significant advancement in OCR technology, offering a reliable and efficient solution for extracting text from complex PDF documents. Its open-source nature, coupled with its advanced features, positions it as a valuable tool for researchers, professionals, and organizations seeking to enhance their document processing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The Allen Institute for AI has introduced olmOCR, an open-source tool that leverages Vision Language Models to extract text from PDFs with high accuracy, preserving the natural reading order and supporting complex elements like tables, equations, and handwriting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advancing AI Language Models with OpenAI’s GPT 4.5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gpt45" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advancing AI Language Models with OpenAI’s GPT 4.5" /><published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gpt45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gpt45">&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has released GPT-4.5, its largest and most advanced AI language model to date, offering enhanced pattern recognition, broader knowledge, and improved user interactions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-4-5/&quot;&gt;OpenAI unveiled GPT-4.5&lt;/a&gt;, marking a significant milestone in the evolution of AI language models. This release is part of OpenAI's ongoing efforts to scale up pre-training and post-training processes, thereby enhancing the model's ability to recognize patterns, draw connections, and generate creative insights without explicit reasoning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-4.5 represents an advancement in unsupervised learning, a paradigm focused on improving a model's intuitive understanding of the world. By leveraging extensive computational resources and data, along with innovations in architecture and optimization, GPT-4.5 has achieved a broader and deeper knowledge base. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early testing indicates that interactions with GPT-4.5 feel more natural compared to its predecessors. The model's enhanced ability to follow user intent and its higher &quot;emotional quotient&quot; (EQ) make it particularly useful for tasks such as writing improvement, programming assistance, and practical problem-solving. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the notable improvements in GPT-4.5 is its reduction in generating inaccuracies, commonly referred to as &quot;hallucinations.&quot; This enhancement contributes to more reliable and trustworthy outputs, addressing a critical challenge in AI language models. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;svg width=&quot;784&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; class=&quot;overflow-visible&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(150, 10)&quot;&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;307&quot; y1=&quot;0&quot; x2=&quot;307&quot; y2=&quot;335&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; stroke-dasharray=&quot;4,4&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 233.48484848484847)&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;visx-bar-rounded&quot; d=&quot;M2,29.530303030303024 h344.93620000000004 a2,2 0 0 1 2,2 v26 a2,2 0 0 1 -2,2 h-344.93620000000004 h-2v-2 v-26 v-2h2z&quot; fill=&quot;#71B436&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;0&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; style=&quot;overflow:visible&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; x=&quot;348.93620000000004&quot; y=&quot;21.530303030303024&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; class=&quot;color-copy-primary&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;348.93620000000004&quot; dy=&quot;0em&quot;&gt;56.8%&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;319.77119999999996&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;319.77119999999996&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;319.77119999999996&quot; y1=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;378.1012&quot; y2=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;378.1012&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;378.1012&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 131.96969696969697)&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;visx-bar-rounded&quot; d=&quot;M2,29.530303030303024 h384.048 a2,2 0 0 1 2,2 v26 a2,2 0 0 1 -2,2 h-384.048 h-2v-2 v-26 v-2h2z&quot; fill=&quot;#71B436&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;0&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; style=&quot;overflow:visible&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; x=&quot;388.048&quot; y=&quot;21.530303030303024&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; class=&quot;color-copy-primary&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;388.048&quot; dy=&quot;0em&quot;&gt;63.2%&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;380.37300000000005&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;380.37300000000005&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;380.37300000000005&quot; y1=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;395.72300000000007&quot; y2=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;395.72300000000007&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;395.72300000000007&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 30.454545454545467)&quot;&gt;&lt;path class=&quot;visx-bar-rounded&quot; d=&quot;M2,29.530303030303024 h346.1028 a2,2 0 0 1 2,2 v26 a2,2 0 0 1 -2,2 h-346.1028 h-2v-2 v-26 v-2h2z&quot; fill=&quot;#71B436&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;0&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; style=&quot;overflow:visible&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; x=&quot;350.1028&quot; y=&quot;21.530303030303024&quot; font-size=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; class=&quot;color-copy-primary&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;350.1028&quot; dy=&quot;0em&quot;&gt;57.0%&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;335.18260000000004&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;335.18260000000004&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;335.18260000000004&quot; y1=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;365.023&quot; y2=&quot;44.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line text-primary-44&quot; x1=&quot;365.023&quot; y1=&quot;40.530303030303024&quot; x2=&quot;365.023&quot; y2=&quot;48.530303030303024&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis visx-axis-left text-primary-12&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 257.0151515151515)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;-150&quot; y=&quot;0.25&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;start&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.71em&quot;&gt;Creative&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;1em&quot;&gt;intelligence&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 155.5)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;-150&quot; y=&quot;0.25&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;start&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.71em&quot;&gt;Professional&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;1em&quot;&gt;queries&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 59.9848484848485)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;-150&quot; y=&quot;0.25&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;start&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.71em&quot;&gt;Everyday queries&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line visx-axis-line&quot; x1=&quot;0&quot; y1=&quot;335.5&quot; x2=&quot;0&quot; y2=&quot;0.5&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis visx-axis-bottom text-primary-12&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 335)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;0&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(61.400000000000006, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;10&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(122.80000000000001, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;20&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(184.2, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;30&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(245.60000000000002, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;40&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(307, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;50&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(368.4, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;60&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(429.79999999999995, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;70&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(491.20000000000005, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;80&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(552.6, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;90&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group visx-axis-tick text-caption text-primary-60&quot; transform=&quot;translate(0, 0)&quot;&gt;&lt;g class=&quot;visx-group&quot; transform=&quot;translate(614, 18)&quot;&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;-2&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow: visible;&quot;&gt;&lt;text transform=&quot;&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; stroke=&quot;transparent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;text-caption text-primary-60 whitespace-pre-line&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;0&quot; dy=&quot;0.355em&quot;&gt;100&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;line class=&quot;visx-line visx-axis-line&quot; x1=&quot;0.5&quot; y1=&quot;0&quot; x2=&quot;614.5&quot; y2=&quot;0&quot; fill=&quot;transparent&quot; shape-rendering=&quot;crispEdges&quot; stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&lt;svg x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;24&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; style=&quot;overflow:visible&quot;&gt;&lt;text class=&quot;visx-axis-label text-caption text-primary-60&quot; x=&quot;307&quot; y=&quot;26&quot; font-family=&quot;inherit&quot; font-size=&quot;inherit&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; font-weight=&quot;inherit&quot; text-anchor=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;tspan x=&quot;307&quot; dy=&quot;0em&quot;&gt;GPT-4.5 win-rate vs GPT-4o&lt;/tspan&gt;&lt;/text&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenAI emphasizes that GPT-4.5 is not considered a frontier AI model but rather a step forward in scaling existing paradigms. The company has released GPT-4.5 as a research preview to better understand its strengths and limitations, inviting users to explore its capabilities and provide feedback. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of GPT-4.5 aligns with OpenAI's commitment to advancing AI responsibly. The model has undergone rigorous evaluations to ensure safety and ethical considerations are addressed, following OpenAI's preparedness framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;py-3xs @2xl:[&amp;amp;_table]:table-fixed [&amp;amp;_td]:p-3xs [&amp;amp;_th]:p-4xs [&amp;amp;_td]:min-w-3xl prose max-w-none [&amp;amp;_table]:w-full [&amp;amp;_table]:table-auto [&amp;amp;_table]:border-collapse [&amp;amp;_table]:text-left mb-s&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:font-bold&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:font-bold&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GPT‑4.5&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:font-bold&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GPT‑4o&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:font-bold&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;OpenAI o3‑mini (high)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPQA (science)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;71.4%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;53.6%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;79.7%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;AIME ‘24 (math)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;36.7%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;9.3%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;87.3%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;MMMLU (multilingual)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;85.1%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;81.5%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;81.1%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;MMMU (multimodal)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;74.4%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;69.1%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SWE-Lancer Diamond (coding)*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;32.6%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;$186,125&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;23.3%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;$138,750&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.8%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;$89,625&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;border-black-12 dark:border-white-12 border-t-[1px] last:border-b-[1px]&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SWE-Bench Verified (coding)*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;38.0%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;30.7%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;[&amp;amp;_p]:text-p2 [&amp;amp;&amp;gt;p]:break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;61.0%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, GPT-4.5 signifies a meaningful advancement in AI language modeling, offering users enhanced capabilities and more natural interactions. As a research preview, it provides an opportunity for the community to engage with the model, explore its potential applications, and contribute to its ongoing development. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">OpenAI has released GPT-4.5, its largest and most advanced AI language model to date, offering enhanced pattern recognition, broader knowledge, and improved user interactions. OpenAI unveiled GPT-4.5, marking a significant milestone in the evolution of AI language models. This release is part of OpenAI's ongoing efforts to scale up pre-training and post-training processes, thereby enhancing the model's ability to recognize patterns, draw connections, and generate creative insights without explicit reasoning. GPT-4.5 represents an advancement in unsupervised learning, a paradigm focused on improving a model's intuitive understanding of the world. By leveraging extensive computational resources and data, along with innovations in architecture and optimization, GPT-4.5 has achieved a broader and deeper knowledge base. Early testing indicates that interactions with GPT-4.5 feel more natural compared to its predecessors. The model's enhanced ability to follow user intent and its higher &quot;emotional quotient&quot; (EQ) make it particularly useful for tasks such as writing improvement, programming assistance, and practical problem-solving. One of the notable improvements in GPT-4.5 is its reduction in generating inaccuracies, commonly referred to as &quot;hallucinations.&quot; This enhancement contributes to more reliable and trustworthy outputs, addressing a critical challenge in AI language models.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Next Generation of the Phi Family</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Next Generation of the Phi Family" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phi">&lt;p&gt; The latest additions to Microsoft's Phi family of small language models (SLMs) was &lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/empowering-innovation-the-next-generation-of-the-phi-family/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;, introducing Phi-4-multimodal and Phi-4-mini. These models are designed to enhance AI capabilities across various applications, offering developers advanced tools for innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its ongoing commitment to advancing artificial intelligence, Microsoft has announced two new models in its Phi family of small language models (SLMs): Phi-4-multimodal and Phi-4-mini. These models are engineered to provide developers with sophisticated AI tools, facilitating the creation of innovative and context-aware applications. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phi-4-multimodal stands out with its ability to process speech, vision, and text simultaneously. This multimodal capability opens new avenues for developing applications that require a comprehensive understanding of diverse data types, enabling more nuanced and effective AI solutions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; data-wp-class--hide=&quot;state.isContentHidden&quot; data-wp-class--show=&quot;state.isContentVisible&quot; data-wp-init=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; data-wp-on-async--click=&quot;actions.showLightbox&quot; data-wp-on-async--load=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; data-wp-on-async-window--resize=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; src=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/F1-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A table comparing the performance of different models on various benchmarks. The benchmarks listed are SAi2D, SChartQA, SDocVQA, and SInfoVQA. The models compared are Phi-4-multimodal-instruct, InternOmni-7B, Gemini-2.0-Flash-Lite-prvview-02-05, Gemini-2.0-Flash, and Gemini1.5-Pro.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-38741 webp-format&quot; srcset=&quot;&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/F1-1.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Phi-4-mini is optimized for text-based tasks, offering high accuracy and scalability in a compact form. This model is particularly beneficial for applications where computational resources are limited but high performance is still required, making it a versatile tool for various text processing needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; data-wp-class--hide=&quot;state.isContentHidden&quot; data-wp-class--show=&quot;state.isContentVisible&quot; data-wp-init=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; data-wp-on-async--click=&quot;actions.showLightbox&quot; data-wp-on-async--load=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; data-wp-on-async-window--resize=&quot;callbacks.setButtonStyles&quot; src=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/F1-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A table comparing the performance of different models on various benchmarks. The benchmarks listed are SAi2D, SChartQA, SDocVQA, and SInfoVQA. The models compared are Phi-4-multimodal-instruct, InternOmni-7B, Gemini-2.0-Flash-Lite-prvview-02-05, Gemini-2.0-Flash, and Gemini1.5-Pro.&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-38741 webp-format&quot; srcset=&quot;&quot; data-orig-src=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/F1-1.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of these models reflects Microsoft's dedication to providing diverse AI tools that cater to different development needs. By expanding the Phi family, Microsoft continues to support developers in creating applications that are both innovative and efficient, pushing the boundaries of what is possible with AI technology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These advancements in the Phi family are part of Microsoft's broader strategy to empower innovation through accessible and powerful AI models. As AI continues to evolve, the availability of such models ensures that developers have the resources necessary to build cutting-edge applications that can adapt to the ever-changing technological landscape. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The latest additions to Microsoft's Phi family of small language models (SLMs) was announced, introducing Phi-4-multimodal and Phi-4-mini. These models are designed to enhance AI capabilities across various applications, offering developers advanced tools for innovation. In its ongoing commitment to advancing artificial intelligence, Microsoft has announced two new models in its Phi family of small language models (SLMs): Phi-4-multimodal and Phi-4-mini. These models are engineered to provide developers with sophisticated AI tools, facilitating the creation of innovative and context-aware applications. Phi-4-multimodal stands out with its ability to process speech, vision, and text simultaneously. This multimodal capability opens new avenues for developing applications that require a comprehensive understanding of diverse data types, enabling more nuanced and effective AI solutions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alexa+, Amazon’s Next-Generation AI Assistant</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AlexaPlus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alexa+, Amazon’s Next-Generation AI Assistant" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AlexaPlus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AlexaPlus">&lt;p&gt;Amazon has unveiled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/new-alexa-generative-artificial-intelligence&quot;&gt;Alexa+&lt;/a&gt;, an advanced AI-powered personal assistant designed to offer more natural, conversational, and efficient interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexa+ is a significant evolution of its voice assistant, now powered by generative AI. This advancement enables Alexa+ to engage in more natural and expansive conversations, understanding colloquial expressions and complex ideas, thereby transforming interactions into experiences akin to conversing with an insightful friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Echo Show conversation in motion.&quot; height=&quot;743&quot; role=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.aboutamazon.com/dims4/default/3940e98/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1600x900+0+0/resize/1320x743!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Famazon-blogs-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F8e%2Ff6%2Fb6c5d6d943eea6091686d78a069a%2Finline001-aboutamazon-alexa-alexa-conversational-cx-hiking-reccomendations-1-1600x900.GIF&quot; width=&quot;1320&quot; class=&quot;v2&quot; pinger-seen=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of Alexa+'s architecture are powerful large language models (LLMs) available on Amazon Bedrock. These models facilitate Alexa+'s ability to orchestrate across tens of thousands of services and devices, a capability achieved through the creation of &quot;experts.&quot; These experts are groups of systems, capabilities, APIs, and instructions that enable Alexa+ to perform specific tasks for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these experts, Alexa+ can control smart home devices from brands like Philips Hue and Roborock, make reservations via platforms such as OpenTable and Vagaro, explore and play music from providers including Amazon Music, Spotify, Apple Music, and iHeartRadio, order groceries from Amazon Fresh and Whole Foods Market, and even arrange deliveries through services like Grubhub and Uber Eats. Additionally, Alexa+ can provide reminders for events like ticket sales on Ticketmaster and use Ring to alert users of visitors approaching their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Alexa+ is its agentic capabilities, which allow it to navigate the internet autonomously to complete tasks on behalf of users. For instance, if a user needs to schedule an appliance repair, Alexa+ can independently search for service providers, authenticate, arrange the repair, and notify the user upon completion, all without requiring supervision or intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalization is a key aspect of Alexa+. The assistant can remember user-specific information such as purchase history, media consumption, shipping addresses, and payment preferences. Users can also input additional personal details like family recipes, important dates, and dietary preferences, which Alexa+ can utilize to provide tailored assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, Alexa+ represents a significant advancement in AI-powered personal assistants. By leveraging generative AI and integrating extensive capabilities, Alexa+ offers users a more natural, personalized, and efficient experience, positioning itself as a valuable tool in managing daily tasks and enhancing digital interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Amazon has unveiled Alexa+, an advanced AI-powered personal assistant designed to offer more natural, conversational, and efficient interactions. Alexa+ is a significant evolution of its voice assistant, now powered by generative AI. This advancement enables Alexa+ to engage in more natural and expansive conversations, understanding colloquial expressions and complex ideas, thereby transforming interactions into experiences akin to conversing with an insightful friend.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ElevenLabs’ Breakthrough in Speech-to-Text Technology is called Scribe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ElLabs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ElevenLabs’ Breakthrough in Speech-to-Text Technology is called Scribe" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ElLabs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ElLabs">&lt;p&gt; ElevenLabs has introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://elevenlabs.io/blog/meet-scribe&quot;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt;, a state-of-the-art Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) model that transcribes speech in 99 languages with unparalleled accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ElevenLabs unveiled Scribe, their inaugural Speech-to-Text model, acclaimed as the world's most accurate transcription system. Engineered to handle the unpredictability of real-world audio, Scribe transcribes speech across 99 languages, offering features such as word-level timestamps, speaker diarization, and audio-event tagging, all delivered in a structured format for seamless integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scribe's precision is evident through its performance in benchmark tests. In both FLEURS and Common Voice assessments across 99 languages, Scribe consistently outperformed leading models like Gemini 2.0 Flash, Whisper Large V3, and Deepgram Nova-3. Notably, it achieved the lowest automated transcription word error rates in Italian (98.7%), English (96.7%), and 97 other languages, underscoring its exceptional accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; disableremoteplayback=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;metadata&quot; src=&quot;https://eleven-public-cdn.elevenlabs.io/payloadcms/w814e04tfy-ElevenLabs Scribe - FINAL v3.mp4&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Scribe's significant contributions is its ability to make ASR universally accessible. It dramatically reduces errors in traditionally underserved languages such as Serbian, Cantonese, and Malayalam, where competing models often exhibit word error rates exceeding 40%. This advancement ensures more inclusive and accurate transcription services across diverse linguistic communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers can integrate Scribe into their applications via ElevenLabs' Speech-to-Text API, receiving structured JSON transcripts that include speaker diarization, word-level timestamps, and non-speech event markers like laughter. A low-latency version tailored for real-time applications is slated for future release, expanding Scribe's utility in various contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creators and businesses also stand to benefit from Scribe's capabilities. Through the ElevenLabs dashboard, users can upload audio or video files and generate formatted transcripts, streamlining content creation processes such as meeting summaries, movie subtitles, or even song lyrics. This user-friendly interface ensures that Scribe's advanced features are accessible to a broad audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, Scribe represents a significant advancement in speech-to-text technology. Its unparalleled accuracy across a vast array of languages, coupled with features like speaker diarization and audio-event tagging, positions it as a valuable tool for developers, creators, and businesses seeking reliable transcription solutions. By making ASR more accessible and reducing errors in underserved languages, Scribe contributes to a more inclusive and efficient digital communication landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">ElevenLabs has introduced Scribe, a state-of-the-art Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) model that transcribes speech in 99 languages with unparalleled accuracy. ElevenLabs unveiled Scribe, their inaugural Speech-to-Text model, acclaimed as the world's most accurate transcription system. Engineered to handle the unpredictability of real-world audio, Scribe transcribes speech across 99 languages, offering features such as word-level timestamps, speaker diarization, and audio-event tagging, all delivered in a structured format for seamless integration. Scribe's precision is evident through its performance in benchmark tests. In both FLEURS and Common Voice assessments across 99 languages, Scribe consistently outperformed leading models like Gemini 2.0 Flash, Whisper Large V3, and Deepgram Nova-3. Notably, it achieved the lowest automated transcription word error rates in Italian (98.7%), English (96.7%), and 97 other languages, underscoring its exceptional accuracy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chain of Draft:Thinking Faster by Writing Less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ThinkFaster" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chain of Draft:Thinking Faster by Writing Less" /><published>2025-02-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ThinkFaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ThinkFaster">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance in solving complex reasoning tasks through mechanisms like Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting, which emphasizes verbose, step-by-step reasoning. However, humans typically employ a more efficient strategy: drafting concise intermediate thoughts that capture only essential information. In this work, we propose Chain of Draft (CoD), a novel paradigm inspired by human cognitive processes, where LLMs generate minimalistic yet informative intermediate reasoning outputs while solving tasks. By reducing verbosity and focusing on critical insights, CoD matches or surpasses CoT in accuracy while using as little as only 7.6% of the tokens, significantly reducing cost and latency across various reasoning tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xu,+S&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Silei Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Xie,+W&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wenhao Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhao,+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lingxiao Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=He,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pengcheng He&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18600&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Introduces Free Gemini Code Assist for Developers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GeminiCodeAssistant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Introduces Free Gemini Code Assist for Developers" /><published>2025-02-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GeminiCodeAssistant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GeminiCodeAssistant">&lt;p&gt; Google's latest blog post announces the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeassist.google/products/individual&quot;&gt;Gemini Code Assist&lt;/a&gt;, a free AI-powered coding assistant designed to enhance developer productivity. This article provides a summary of the key features, benefits, and implications of this tool for developers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s Gemini Code Assist is an AI-driven coding assistant that helps developers write, debug, and optimize their code more efficiently. The tool integrates seamlessly into popular development environments, providing real-time code suggestions, explanations, and auto-completions to streamline the coding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Gemini Code Assist is its ability to understand and generate code in multiple programming languages. By leveraging advanced AI models, it offers high-quality code suggestions that align with best practices, making it particularly useful for both beginner and experienced developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google highlights that Gemini Code Assist is designed to improve code quality and efficiency. Developers can use the tool to automatically generate code snippets, detect potential bugs, and even refactor code to improve readability and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key advantage of the tool is its deep integration with Google Cloud and other development ecosystems. This enables seamless collaboration between teams, as developers can receive context-aware suggestions based on their specific projects and environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is another major focus of Gemini Code Assist. Google has incorporated safeguards to prevent the generation of insecure or vulnerable code. The tool is continuously updated with best practices to ensure that developers write secure and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making Gemini Code Assist free, Google aims to democratize access to AI-powered development tools. This move is expected to empower a wider audience of developers, including students, hobbyists, and professionals, by giving them access to cutting-edge AI-driven coding assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another noteworthy aspect of Gemini Code Assist is its role in boosting developer productivity. By reducing the time spent on repetitive coding tasks and debugging, developers can focus more on creative problem-solving and building innovative applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Google's launch of Gemini Code Assist marks a significant step in AI-driven software development. By providing a free, intelligent coding assistant, Google is equipping developers with a powerful tool to enhance efficiency, security, and collaboration in modern software projects. You can find more on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/developers/gemini-code-assist-free/&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Give it a shot and try it out, it may be the case for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Google's latest blog post announces the release of Gemini Code Assist, a free AI-powered coding assistant designed to enhance developer productivity. This article provides a summary of the key features, benefits, and implications of this tool for developers worldwide. Google’s Gemini Code Assist is an AI-driven coding assistant that helps developers write, debug, and optimize their code more efficiently. The tool integrates seamlessly into popular development environments, providing real-time code suggestions, explanations, and auto-completions to streamline the coding process. One of the standout features of Gemini Code Assist is its ability to understand and generate code in multiple programming languages. By leveraging advanced AI models, it offers high-quality code suggestions that align with best practices, making it particularly useful for both beginner and experienced developers. Google highlights that Gemini Code Assist is designed to improve code quality and efficiency. Developers can use the tool to automatically generate code snippets, detect potential bugs, and even refactor code to improve readability and performance. A key advantage of the tool is its deep integration with Google Cloud and other development ecosystems. This enables seamless collaboration between teams, as developers can receive context-aware suggestions based on their specific projects and environments. Security is another major focus of Gemini Code Assist. Google has incorporated safeguards to prevent the generation of insecure or vulnerable code. The tool is continuously updated with best practices to ensure that developers write secure and efficient software. By making Gemini Code Assist free, Google aims to democratize access to AI-powered development tools. This move is expected to empower a wider audience of developers, including students, hobbyists, and professionals, by giving them access to cutting-edge AI-driven coding assistance. Another noteworthy aspect of Gemini Code Assist is its role in boosting developer productivity. By reducing the time spent on repetitive coding tasks and debugging, developers can focus more on creative problem-solving and building innovative applications. In conclusion, Google's launch of Gemini Code Assist marks a significant step in AI-driven software development. By providing a free, intelligent coding assistant, Google is equipping developers with a powerful tool to enhance efficiency, security, and collaboration in modern software projects. You can find more on the official blog post. Give it a shot and try it out, it may be the case for your needs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Claude 3.7 Sonnet-Pioneering Hybrid Reasoning in AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Sonnet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Claude 3.7 Sonnet-Pioneering Hybrid Reasoning in AI" /><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Sonnet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Sonnet">&lt;p&gt;Anthropic has unveiled Claude 3.7 Sonnet, a groundbreaking AI model that seamlessly integrates rapid responses with in-depth reasoning capabilities. This release also introduces Claude Code, an agentic coding tool designed to enhance developer productivity directly from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Recently, Anthropic announced the launch of Claude 3.7 Sonnet, marking a significant advancement in artificial intelligence technology. This model stands out as the first hybrid reasoning AI, adept at delivering both swift answers and comprehensive, step-by-step analyses, thereby offering users unparalleled flexibility in addressing a wide array of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet introduces an &quot;extended thinking mode,&quot; enabling the AI to delve deeper into complex problems. Users can toggle this mode based on the intricacy of the query, allowing the model to allocate more cognitive resources when necessary. This feature is particularly beneficial for tasks requiring meticulous reasoning, such as complex mathematical computations or intricate coding challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the new model, Anthropic has launched Claude Code, a command-line tool currently available as a limited research preview. Claude Code empowers developers to delegate substantial engineering tasks directly to Claude from their terminals. This agentic coding assistant can autonomously search and read code, edit files, write and run tests, and even commit and push code to repositories, streamlining the development workflow and enhancing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a key aspect of this release. Claude 3.7 Sonnet is available across all Anthropic platforms, including the Claude app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/about-claude/models&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/bedrock/claude/&quot;&gt;Amazon Bedrock&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai/generative-ai/docs/partner-models/use-claude&quot;&gt;Google Cloud's Vertex AI&lt;/a&gt;. Notably, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/build-with-claude/extended-thinking&quot;&gt;extended thinking mode&lt;/a&gt; is accessible on all tiers except the free version, ensuring that a broad spectrum of users can benefit from its advanced capabilities. Despite its enhanced features, the model maintains the same operational costs as its predecessors, offering a cost-effective solution for businesses and developers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development philosophy behind Claude 3.7 Sonnet emphasizes the integration of reasoning within a single model, mirroring human cognitive processes that balance quick responses with deep reflection. This unified approach not only simplifies the user experience but also enhances the model's versatility across various applications. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/claude/sonnet&quot;&gt;Internal testing&lt;/a&gt; has demonstrated significant performance improvements, particularly in coding and front-end web development, positioning Claude 3.7 Sonnet as a leading tool for real-world software engineering tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Benchmark table comparing frontier reasoning models&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2600&quot; height=&quot;2360&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; data-nimg=&quot;1&quot; srcset=&quot;/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F654cf6680d32858dfba9af644f8c4a5b04425af1-2600x2360.png&amp;amp;w=3840&amp;amp;q=75 1x&quot; src=&quot;/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F654cf6680d32858dfba9af644f8c4a5b04425af1-2600x2360.png&amp;amp;w=3840&amp;amp;q=75&quot; style=&quot;color: transparent;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters have reported notable successes with Claude 3.7 Sonnet. For instance, the AI has achieved state-of-the-art performance on SWE-bench Verified, an evaluation framework assessing AI models' proficiency in solving real-world software issues. Additionally, in TAU-bench assessments, which test AI agents on complex tasks involving user and tool interactions, Claude 3.7 Sonnet has outperformed previous models, showcasing its advanced reasoning and problem-solving capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AJpK3YTTKZ4&quot; title=&quot;Introducing Claude Code&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the introduction of Claude 3.7 Sonnet and Claude Code represents a significant leap forward in AI technology. By combining rapid response capabilities with deep, extended reasoning within a single model, Anthropic offers a versatile and powerful tool tailored to meet the diverse needs of users and developers. This release not only enhances productivity but also sets a new standard for AI integration in complex, real-world applications. If you feel like finding out more you can visit official blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-3-7-sonnet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Anthropic has unveiled Claude 3.7 Sonnet, a groundbreaking AI model that seamlessly integrates rapid responses with in-depth reasoning capabilities. This release also introduces Claude Code, an agentic coding tool designed to enhance developer productivity directly from the command line.</summary></entry></feed>