<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-26T11:20:18+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kavour</title><subtitle>Data Science and AI News</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introducing Claude 3.7 Sonnet-Pioneering Hybrid Reasoning in AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Sonnet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Claude 3.7 Sonnet-Pioneering Hybrid Reasoning in AI" /><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Sonnet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Sonnet">&lt;p&gt;Anthropic has unveiled Claude 3.7 Sonnet, a groundbreaking AI model that seamlessly integrates rapid responses with in-depth reasoning capabilities. This release also introduces Claude Code, an agentic coding tool designed to enhance developer productivity directly from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Recently, Anthropic announced the launch of Claude 3.7 Sonnet, marking a significant advancement in artificial intelligence technology. This model stands out as the first hybrid reasoning AI, adept at delivering both swift answers and comprehensive, step-by-step analyses, thereby offering users unparalleled flexibility in addressing a wide array of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet introduces an &quot;extended thinking mode,&quot; enabling the AI to delve deeper into complex problems. Users can toggle this mode based on the intricacy of the query, allowing the model to allocate more cognitive resources when necessary. This feature is particularly beneficial for tasks requiring meticulous reasoning, such as complex mathematical computations or intricate coding challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the new model, Anthropic has launched Claude Code, a command-line tool currently available as a limited research preview. Claude Code empowers developers to delegate substantial engineering tasks directly to Claude from their terminals. This agentic coding assistant can autonomously search and read code, edit files, write and run tests, and even commit and push code to repositories, streamlining the development workflow and enhancing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a key aspect of this release. Claude 3.7 Sonnet is available across all Anthropic platforms, including the Claude app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/about-claude/models&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/bedrock/claude/&quot;&gt;Amazon Bedrock&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai/generative-ai/docs/partner-models/use-claude&quot;&gt;Google Cloud's Vertex AI&lt;/a&gt;. Notably, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/build-with-claude/extended-thinking&quot;&gt;extended thinking mode&lt;/a&gt; is accessible on all tiers except the free version, ensuring that a broad spectrum of users can benefit from its advanced capabilities. Despite its enhanced features, the model maintains the same operational costs as its predecessors, offering a cost-effective solution for businesses and developers alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development philosophy behind Claude 3.7 Sonnet emphasizes the integration of reasoning within a single model, mirroring human cognitive processes that balance quick responses with deep reflection. This unified approach not only simplifies the user experience but also enhances the model's versatility across various applications. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/claude/sonnet&quot;&gt;Internal testing&lt;/a&gt; has demonstrated significant performance improvements, particularly in coding and front-end web development, positioning Claude 3.7 Sonnet as a leading tool for real-world software engineering tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Benchmark table comparing frontier reasoning models&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2600&quot; height=&quot;2360&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; data-nimg=&quot;1&quot; srcset=&quot;/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F654cf6680d32858dfba9af644f8c4a5b04425af1-2600x2360.png&amp;amp;w=3840&amp;amp;q=75 1x&quot; src=&quot;/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F654cf6680d32858dfba9af644f8c4a5b04425af1-2600x2360.png&amp;amp;w=3840&amp;amp;q=75&quot; style=&quot;color: transparent;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters have reported notable successes with Claude 3.7 Sonnet. For instance, the AI has achieved state-of-the-art performance on SWE-bench Verified, an evaluation framework assessing AI models' proficiency in solving real-world software issues. Additionally, in TAU-bench assessments, which test AI agents on complex tasks involving user and tool interactions, Claude 3.7 Sonnet has outperformed previous models, showcasing its advanced reasoning and problem-solving capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AJpK3YTTKZ4&quot; title=&quot;Introducing Claude Code&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the introduction of Claude 3.7 Sonnet and Claude Code represents a significant leap forward in AI technology. By combining rapid response capabilities with deep, extended reasoning within a single model, Anthropic offers a versatile and powerful tool tailored to meet the diverse needs of users and developers. This release not only enhances productivity but also sets a new standard for AI integration in complex, real-world applications. If you feel like finding out more you can visit official blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-3-7-sonnet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Anthropic has unveiled Claude 3.7 Sonnet, a groundbreaking AI model that seamlessly integrates rapid responses with in-depth reasoning capabilities. This release also introduces Claude Code, an agentic coding tool designed to enhance developer productivity directly from the command line.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Real-Time Self-Improvement for LLMs with RAGSys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/selfimpRAG" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real-Time Self-Improvement for LLMs with RAGSys" /><published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/selfimpRAG</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/selfimpRAG">&lt;p&gt;This article provides a concise summary of Crossing Minds' blog post on using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to enable real-time self-improvement in large language models. It highlights the core concepts of dynamic context retrieval, prompt optimization, and continuous feedback integration that allow LLMs to evolve and adapt without retraining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog post introduces a novel framework that transforms the traditional RAG approach from a static retrieval system into a dynamic optimization process. Instead of simply appending relevant documents or examples to a query, this system refines the prompt in real time by selecting the most useful contexts based on their measured utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central to the framework is the breakdown of RAG into its key components: the query, the prompt, the response, and, importantly, the context. The retriever identifies high-utility information—whether documents, tailored instructions, or few-shot examples—while the composer integrates this information into a well-structured prompt that maximizes the LLM's output quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This innovative approach allows LLMs to benefit from continuous feedback. Every interaction, whether it results in a positive or negative outcome, is recorded and used to adjust the retrieval strategy. Negative outcomes trigger corrective instructions that are automatically generated and stored, enabling the system to self-correct over time without needing to retrain the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, when an interaction produces a desirable response, it is stored as a high-utility example. These examples reinforce successful behavior and are used as few-shot prompts in future queries, ensuring that the model continuously learns and adapts based on its real-world performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the blog explains that this dynamic retrieval approach shifts the focus from similarity-based selection to utility-driven optimization. By measuring how each piece of context improves response quality, the system can prioritize information that has a tangible impact on the LLM’s performance, ultimately creating a feedback loop that drives continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the framework presented in the blog post represents a significant evolution in the way LLMs are fine-tuned and optimized. By integrating real-time feedback and leveraging dynamic retrieval to tailor each prompt, the system closes the loop between interaction and improvement, enabling LLMs to become more accurate, reliable, and adaptable to the ever-changing landscape of user needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach not only enhances the quality of responses but also offers a scalable solution for deploying LLMs in diverse applications, where rapid adaptation and continuous learning are critical for success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">This article provides a concise summary of Crossing Minds' blog post on using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) to enable real-time self-improvement in large language models. It highlights the core concepts of dynamic context retrieval, prompt optimization, and continuous feedback integration that allow LLMs to evolve and adapt without retraining. The blog post introduces a novel framework that transforms the traditional RAG approach from a static retrieval system into a dynamic optimization process. Instead of simply appending relevant documents or examples to a query, this system refines the prompt in real time by selecting the most useful contexts based on their measured utility. Central to the framework is the breakdown of RAG into its key components: the query, the prompt, the response, and, importantly, the context. The retriever identifies high-utility information—whether documents, tailored instructions, or few-shot examples—while the composer integrates this information into a well-structured prompt that maximizes the LLM's output quality. This innovative approach allows LLMs to benefit from continuous feedback. Every interaction, whether it results in a positive or negative outcome, is recorded and used to adjust the retrieval strategy. Negative outcomes trigger corrective instructions that are automatically generated and stored, enabling the system to self-correct over time without needing to retrain the model. On the other hand, when an interaction produces a desirable response, it is stored as a high-utility example. These examples reinforce successful behavior and are used as few-shot prompts in future queries, ensuring that the model continuously learns and adapts based on its real-world performance. Furthermore, the blog explains that this dynamic retrieval approach shifts the focus from similarity-based selection to utility-driven optimization. By measuring how each piece of context improves response quality, the system can prioritize information that has a tangible impact on the LLM’s performance, ultimately creating a feedback loop that drives continuous improvement. In conclusion, the framework presented in the blog post represents a significant evolution in the way LLMs are fine-tuned and optimized. By integrating real-time feedback and leveraging dynamic retrieval to tailor each prompt, the system closes the loop between interaction and improvement, enabling LLMs to become more accurate, reliable, and adaptable to the ever-changing landscape of user needs. This approach not only enhances the quality of responses but also offers a scalable solution for deploying LLMs in diverse applications, where rapid adaptation and continuous learning are critical for success.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goku-Flow Based Video Generative Foundation Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Goku" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goku-Flow Based Video Generative Foundation Models" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Goku</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Goku">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This paper introduces Goku, a state-of-the-art family of joint image-and-video generation models leveraging rectified flow Transformers to achieve industry-leading performance. We detail the foundational elements enabling high-quality visual generation, including the data curation pipeline, model architecture design, flow formulation, and advanced infrastructure for efficient and robust large-scale training. The Goku models demonstrate superior performance in both qualitative and quantitative evaluations, setting new benchmarks across major tasks. Specifically, Goku achieves 0.76 on GenEval and 83.65 on DPG-Bench for text-to-image generation, and 84.85 on VBench for text-to-video tasks. We believe that this work provides valuable insights and practical advancements for the research community in developing joint image-and-video generation models. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chen,+S&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Shoufa Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ge,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chongjian Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yuqi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yida Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhu,+F&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fengda Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hao Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hao,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hongxiang Hao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wu,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hui Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lai,+Z&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zhichao Lai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hu,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yifei Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Lin,+T&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ting-Che Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zhang,+S&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Shilong Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+F&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+C&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chuan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Wang,+X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Xing Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Peng,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yanghua Peng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Sun,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Peize Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Luo,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ping Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jiang,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yi Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yuan,+Z&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zehuan Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Peng,+B&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bingyue Peng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liu,+X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Xiaobing Liu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04896&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Codeium’s Windsurf Wave 3-A Leap Forward in AI-Powered Coding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/WindsurfWave3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codeium’s Windsurf Wave 3-A Leap Forward in AI-Powered Coding" /><published>2025-02-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/WindsurfWave3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/WindsurfWave3">&lt;p&gt;The latest update from Codeium, Windsurf Wave 3, introduces significant improvements in AI-powered code completion and development workflows. Let's take a closer look though, on the updates and changes provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codeium has consistently pushed the boundaries of AI-driven coding assistance, and Windsurf Wave 3 is no exception. Since the release of the initial Windsurf version (I hope you've tryied it when I suggested you) there have been some major updates. With this latest updated version, developers can expect better code suggestions, improved latency, and a more intuitive user experience. These advancements make AI-assisted programming even more seamless, reducing friction in the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Windsurf Wave 3 is its enhanced model accuracy. By leveraging deep learning techniques and training on vast datasets, Codeium's AI provides more contextually relevant code suggestions. This leads to reduced debugging time and helps developers write cleaner, more efficient code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance optimization has also been a key focus of this update. Faster response times mean that AI-generated code suggestions appear almost instantaneously, maintaining a smooth coding workflow. This speed improvement is especially beneficial for large-scale projects where efficiency is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to core improvements, Windsurf Wave 3 introduces better multi-language support. Whether developers work with Python, JavaScript, Java, or other popular programming languages, they can now enjoy a more consistent and accurate AI-powered coding experience. This broadens Codeium’s appeal to a more diverse group of developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another notable enhancement is the refinement of inline suggestions. The AI now better understands user intent, reducing instances of irrelevant or redundant code completions. This allows for a more intuitive interaction between the developer and the AI assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codeium’s continued innovation in AI-driven development tools positions it as a strong competitor in the space. Windsurf Wave 3 reaffirms its commitment to providing cutting-edge AI solutions for developers, making coding more efficient, intelligent, and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As AI continues to reshape software development, updates like Windsurf Wave 3 pave the way for more sophisticated and reliable coding assistance. With these improvements, Codeium ensures that developers can harness the full power of AI to streamline their work and focus on solving complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find details about this version updates and many more detailes in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeium.com/blog/windsurf-wave-3&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt; where everything is explained thoroughly. Take a minute and eplore the features provided here because I believe you can benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The latest update from Codeium, Windsurf Wave 3, introduces significant improvements in AI-powered code completion and development workflows. Let's take a closer look though, on the updates and changes provided.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet the New Sonar-Perplexity AI’s Enhanced Search Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/PerplexitySonar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet the New Sonar-Perplexity AI’s Enhanced Search Experience" /><published>2025-02-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/PerplexitySonar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/PerplexitySonar">&lt;p&gt;Perplexity AI has unveiled the new Sonar, an advanced search technology designed to provide more accurate, relevant, and insightful responses. This update enhances how users interact with AI-driven search, improving precision and usability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perplexity AI continues to redefine search by leveraging cutting-edge AI models, and the new Sonar represents a significant leap in this journey. By focusing on delivering highly relevant results with better contextual awareness, Sonar makes information retrieval faster and more intuitive for users. I don't know about you but I don't google any more, I use Perplexity instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key improvements in Sonar is its refined ranking system. By analyzing queries more intelligently, it prioritizes the most relevant and credible sources, reducing noise and misinformation. This ensures that users get high-quality answers without sifting through unnecessary data, and users do seem to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://framerusercontent.com/images/YCALu2CFaq4OlGXciooTP0YucY.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another notable enhancement is the system’s improved ability to understand nuanced queries. Whether users are searching for technical information, general knowledge, or complex research topics, Sonar provides deeper insights by grasping context more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perplexity has also worked on making Sonar more interactive. With real-time response generation and dynamic follow-ups, users can refine their searches seamlessly. This feature mimics natural conversation, making AI-powered search feel more like an intelligent dialogue rather than a static lookup tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to accuracy, Sonar emphasizes transparency. It provides clear citations and source references, allowing users to verify information easily. This approach enhances trust in AI-generated responses, setting a new standard for responsible AI-driven search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By combining speed, accuracy, and contextual awareness, the new Sonar positions Perplexity AI as a leader in next-generation search technologies. This update ensures that users can access information more efficiently while maintaining the reliability and credibility they expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As AI continues to evolve, innovations like Sonar demonstrate the potential of AI-driven search engines to enhance knowledge discovery. With its commitment to improving user experience, Perplexity AI is shaping the future of intelligent search, making it more intuitive, informative, and impactful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find further information and more details in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perplexity.ai/hub/blog/meet-new-sonar&quot;&gt;official blog post&lt;/a&gt; and maybe try it our instead of using the usual way of googling staff up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Perplexity AI has unveiled the new Sonar, an advanced search technology designed to provide more accurate, relevant, and insightful responses. This update enhances how users interact with AI-driven search, improving precision and usability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unveiling the Anthropic Economic Index-AI’s Real-World Impact on Labor Markets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AnthropicEconomicIndex" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unveiling the Anthropic Economic Index-AI’s Real-World Impact on Labor Markets" /><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AnthropicEconomicIndex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AnthropicEconomicIndex">&lt;p&gt;Anthropic has introduced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/economic-index&quot;&gt;Anthropic Economic Index&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneering initiative aimed at analyzing AI's influence on labor markets and the broader economy. This inaugural report offers unprecedented insights into how AI is being integrated into various occupational tasks, based on extensive data from millions of anonymized interactions with Claude.ai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2025, Anthropic launched the Anthropic Economic Index, an initiative designed to monitor and understand the evolving impact of artificial intelligence on labor markets and the economy. This effort is grounded in the analysis of millions of anonymized conversations with &lt;a href=&quot;http://claude.ai/&quot;&gt;Claude.ai&lt;/a&gt;, providing a unique perspective on AI's real-world applications across diverse professional sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial findings of the Index reveal that AI usage is predominantly concentrated in software development and technical writing tasks. Notably, over one-third of occupations (approximately 36%) incorporate AI in at least a quarter of their associated tasks, while about 4% of occupations utilize AI in three-quarters of their tasks. This indicates a significant, though varied, integration of AI into modern workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the data suggests that AI is more commonly employed for augmentation purposes—enhancing and collaborating with human capabilities—rather than for automation. Specifically, 57% of AI applications are aimed at augmenting human tasks, whereas 43% are focused on automating tasks. This trend underscores AI's role as a supportive tool that amplifies human productivity and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI adoption appears to be more prevalent in mid-to-high wage occupations, such as computer programmers and data scientists. Conversely, both the lowest and highest-paid roles exhibit lower levels of AI integration. This pattern likely reflects the current limitations of AI technologies and practical challenges associated with their implementation in certain job categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To facilitate further research and policy development, Anthropic has &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/datasets/Anthropic/EconomicIndex/&quot;&gt;open-sourced the dataset&lt;/a&gt; underpinning this analysis. By inviting economists, policy experts, and researchers to engage with the data, Anthropic aims to foster a collaborative approach to understanding and addressing the transformative effects of AI on employment and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive analysis builds upon existing economic research by focusing on occupational tasks rather than entire professions. Recognizing that many jobs share common tasks and skills, this approach provides a nuanced understanding of how AI is selectively adopted across different functions and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research leverages &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/research/clio&quot;&gt;Clio&lt;/a&gt;, an automated tool developed by Anthropic, to analyze conversations with Claude.ai while ensuring user privacy. By mapping these interactions to specific occupational tasks, classified according to the U.S. Department of Labor's Occupational Information Network (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onetonline.org/&quot;&gt;O*NET&lt;/a&gt;), the study offers a detailed examination of AI's role in the contemporary workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the Anthropic Economic Index serves as a vital resource for comprehending AI's current and potential impact on labor markets. By providing empirical data and fostering an open dialogue among stakeholders, this initiative aims to inform policy decisions and guide the responsible integration of AI into various economic sectors. Find our more about Antrhopic Economic Index &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onetonline.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Anthropic has introduced the Anthropic Economic Index, a pioneering initiative aimed at analyzing AI's influence on labor markets and the broader economy. This inaugural report offers unprecedented insights into how AI is being integrated into various occupational tasks, based on extensive data from millions of anonymized interactions with Claude.ai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GitHub Copilot - The Agent Awakens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GitAgent" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GitHub Copilot - The Agent Awakens" /><published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GitAgent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GitAgent">&lt;p&gt;GitHub has unveiled a groundbreaking &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot/whats-new?utm_source=agent-awakens-announcement&amp;amp;utm_medium=blogtop&amp;amp;utm_campaign=agentic-ai&quot;&gt;update to Copilot&lt;/a&gt;: the new agent mode. This enhancement empowers Copilot to autonomously iterate on its code, identify errors, and rectify them, significantly boosting developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;699&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/of--3Fq1M3w&quot; title=&quot;Agent mode and new models in GitHub Copilot Chat: Visual Studio Code&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub announced the agent mode for Copilot, available in Visual Studio Code. This feature enables Copilot to suggest terminal commands and prompts developers to execute them. It also analyzes runtime errors with self-healing capabilities, allowing it to recognize and automatically fix issues in the code. This advancement transforms Copilot from a passive assistant into an active collaborator in the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside agent mode, GitHub announced the general availability of Copilot Edits. This feature allows developers to make code changes more efficiently, streamlining the development process and reducing the time spent on manual edits. Copilot Edits leverages AI to suggest contextually relevant modifications, enhancing code quality and consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub also provided a preview of their Software Engineering (SWE) agent. This agent is designed to assist developers by providing intelligent code suggestions, automating repetitive tasks, and improving overall code quality. The SWE agent represents a significant step forward in integrating AI into the software development lifecycle, offering developers a powerful tool to enhance their coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of agent mode, the general availability of Copilot Edits, and the preview of the SWE agent, GitHub is redefining the role of AI in software development. These innovations aim to make coding more efficient, intuitive, and collaborative, ushering in a new era of intelligent development tools. There are many more capabilities and resources in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/news-insights/product-news/github-copilot-the-agent-awakens/&quot;&gt;official announcement&lt;/a&gt; for you to explore. So don't hacitate if you are interested and get your hands dirty!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">GitHub has unveiled a groundbreaking update to Copilot: the new agent mode. This enhancement empowers Copilot to autonomously iterate on its code, identify errors, and rectify them, significantly boosting developer productivity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gold-medalist Performance in Solving Olympiad Geometry with AlphaGeometry2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Olymp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gold-medalist Performance in Solving Olympiad Geometry with AlphaGeometry2" /><published>2025-02-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Olymp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Olymp">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We present AlphaGeometry2, a significantly improved version of AlphaGeometry introduced in Trinh et al. (2024), which has now surpassed an average gold medalist in solving Olympiad geometry problems. To achieve this, we first extend the original AlphaGeometry language to tackle harder problems involving movements of objects, and problems containing linear equations of angles, ratios, and distances. This, together with other additions, has markedly improved the coverage rate of the AlphaGeometry language on International Math Olympiads (IMO) 2000-2024 geometry problems from 66% to 88%. The search process of AlphaGeometry2 has also been greatly improved through the use of Gemini architecture for better language modeling, and a novel knowledge-sharing mechanism that combines multiple search trees. Together with further enhancements to the symbolic engine and synthetic data generation, we have significantly boosted the overall solving rate of AlphaGeometry2 to 84% for all geometry problems over the last 25 years, compared to 54% previously. AlphaGeometry2 was also part of the system that achieved silver-medal standard at IMO 2024 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dpmd.ai/imo-silver&quot;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;. Last but not least, we report progress towards using AlphaGeometry2 as a part of a fully automated system that reliably solves geometry problems directly from natural language input. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Chervonyi,+Y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yuri Chervonyi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Trinh,+T+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Trieu H. Trinh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Ol%C5%A1%C3%A1k,+M&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Miroslav Olšák&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Xiaomeng Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Nguyen,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hoang Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Menegali,+M&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Marcelo Menegali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Jung,+J&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Junehyuk Jung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Verma,+V&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vikas Verma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Le,+Q+V&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Quoc V. Le&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Luong,+T&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Thang Luong&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.03544&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">s1-Simple test-time scaling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TestScaling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="s1-Simple test-time scaling" /><published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TestScaling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TestScaling">&lt;h2&gt; Abstract &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Test-time scaling is a promising new approach to language modeling that uses extra test-time compute to improve performance. Recently, OpenAI's o1 model showed this capability but did not publicly share its methodology, leading to many replication efforts. We seek the simplest approach to achieve test-time scaling and strong reasoning performance. First, we curate a small dataset s1K of 1,000 questions paired with reasoning traces relying on three criteria we validate through ablations: difficulty, diversity, and quality. Second, we develop budget forcing to control test-time compute by forcefully terminating the model's thinking process or lengthening it by appending &quot;Wait&quot; multiple times to the model's generation when it tries to end. This can lead the model to double-check its answer, often fixing incorrect reasoning steps. After supervised finetuning the Qwen2.5-32B-Instruct language model on s1K and equipping it with budget forcing, our model s1-32B exceeds o1-preview on competition math questions by up to 27% (MATH and AIME24). Further, scaling s1-32B with budget forcing allows extrapolating beyond its performance without test-time intervention: from 50% to 57% on AIME24. Our model, data, and code are open-source at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/simplescaling/s1&quot;&gt;this https URL&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Authors &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Muennighoff,+N&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Niklas Muennighoff&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Yang,+Z&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zitong Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Shi,+W&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weijia Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Li,+X+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Xiang Lisa Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Fei-Fei,+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Li Fei-Fei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hajishirzi,+H&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hannaneh Hajishirzi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Zettlemoyer,+L&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Luke Zettlemoyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Liang,+P&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Percy Liang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Cand%C3%A8s,+E&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Emmanuel Candès&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/search/cs?searchtype=author&amp;amp;query=Hashimoto,+T&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tatsunori Hashimoto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information go &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.19393&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="research" /><summary type="html">Abstract</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tülu 3 405B The New Heavyweight Champion in AI Models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tulu3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tülu 3 405B The New Heavyweight Champion in AI Models" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tulu3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tulu3">&lt;p&gt;Hold onto your hats, all of you people! The Allen Institute for AI has just unleashed &lt;a href=&quot;https://allenai.org/blog/tulu-3-technical&quot;&gt;Tülu 3 405B&lt;/a&gt;, a colossal 405-billion-parameter model that's not just flexing its muscles but also outpacing the competition. This update is setting new benchmarks, leaving rivals like DeepSeek V3 and GPT-4o &lt;i&gt;in the dust&lt;/i&gt;, all while being as open-source as a community cookbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/64837/1738270804-image-23.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=webp&amp;amp;h=810&amp;amp;w=1550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 30, 2025, the Allen Institute for AI (Ai2) proudly introduced Tülu 3 405B, marking the first time fully open post-training recipes have been applied to such a massive open-weight model. Building upon the success of their previous Tülu 3 release, this model demonstrates that size does matter, especially when combined with innovative training techniques. Tülu 3 405B doesn't just compete; it often surpasses models like DeepSeek V3 and GPT-4o, and leaves prior open-weight models, including Llama 3.1 405B Instruct and Nous Hermes 3 405B, eating its dust on many standard benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how did Ai2 cook up this powerhouse? They scaled their proven Tülu 3 post-training recipe to the Llama-405B base model, following a five-step program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Delicacy:&lt;/strong&gt; Carefully curating and synthesizing data targeting core skills.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervised Finetuning (SFT):&lt;/strong&gt; Applying a finely selected mix of prompts and their completions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct Preference Optimization (DPO):&lt;/strong&gt; Tweaking the model based on both off- and on-policy preference data.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR):&lt;/strong&gt; A fresh, RL-based method to boost specific skills with rewards you can take to the bank.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation Extravaganza:&lt;/strong&gt; Implementing a standardized suite for development, decontamination, and final evaluation stages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the training arena, Ai2 employed their novel RLVR approach, focusing on tasks with clear-cut answers like math problems and precise instructions. To handle the 405B scale, they deployed the model using vLLM with 16-way tensor parallelism, utilizing 240 GPUs for training. Each RLVR iteration involved approximately 550 seconds for inference, 25 seconds for weight transfer, and 1500 seconds for training. Interestingly, they discovered that feeding the model exclusively MATH data, rather than a mix, yielded better results at this scale—a testament to the model's appetite for complex, specialized tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/64837/1738199366-rlvr-diagram.png?dpr=2&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;fm=webp&amp;amp;h=810&amp;amp;w=1550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tülu 3 405B isn't just big; it's a top performer. It achieves competitive or superior results compared to both DeepSeek V3 and GPT-4o, while also surpassing prior open-weight post-trained models of the same size on many standard benchmarks. Notably, the Reinforcement Learning from Verifiable Rewards (RLVR) framework improved MATH performance more significantly at this larger scale, echoing findings in the DeepSeek-R1 report. Overall, Tülu 3 405B shows a consistent edge over DeepSeek V3, especially when safety benchmarks are in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/64837/1738199543-405b_rl.png?dpr=2&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;fm=webp&amp;amp;h=810&amp;amp;w=1550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Tülu 3 405B, Ai2 has not only scaled up their model parameters but also the impact of open-source AI. This release underscores the scalability and effectiveness of their post-training recipe at an unprecedented scale, setting a new standard in the AI community. As Tülu 3 405B continues to flex its capabilities, it's clear that the future of AI is not just about bigger models, but smarter, more open ones too. To get started and find out more detailes about the afforementioned updates you can visit official &lt;a href=&quot;https://allenai.org/blog/tulu-3-405B&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kavour</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Hold onto your hats, all of you people! The Allen Institute for AI has just unleashed Tülu 3 405B, a colossal 405-billion-parameter model that's not just flexing its muscles but also outpacing the competition. This update is setting new benchmarks, leaving rivals like DeepSeek V3 and GPT-4o in the dust, all while being as open-source as a community cookbook.</summary></entry></feed>